<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aao21f00</tid>
<ti>Duolite</ti>
<dt>Memo</dt>
<dt>Correspondence</dt>
<dd>19790926</dd>
<au>Reynolds-M;BW</au>
<rc>Johnson-R;BW</rc>
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":H82 -->
<pg>4</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:0-->
<!-- Note:dl:19981123-->
<bt>621063816/3819</bt>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>TO MR	x	r	tOHNCON	
.
DEPT				
.
,C. C. TO MR.				
0
				0
				0
				0
				0
fROM MR.	M	L.	REYNOLDS/ie/263	
DATE	SEPTFMEER 26. 1973	
SUBAECT	DUOLITE	
or]teLI9.T1
BROWN 6 WILLIAMSON TOBACCO CORPORATION
LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY 40201
1NTERNALCORRESPONDENCE
In an effoct to answer some recurring questions from your advertising
agencies and the Law Department, we have prepared some notes chiefly
concerned with aldehydes in cigarette smoke and their removal by
Duolite. These, presented in question and answer form, are attached.
Of course we still need to check technical accuracy on copy.
Some miscellaneous information about Duolite which nay be of help to
you in developing marketing approaches is as	follows:
1.	Doolite costs more than four times as much as'most other
	filter materials.	Cellulose acetate, .55/1b., charcoal
	(as used by Philip Nnrris) .58/lb., paper .30/lb.,
	Duolite	$3.00/lb.	
2.	There is only sufficient Dvolite for one smoker in three
	hundred. This is based on Diamond Shamrock producing
	17,000 lbs, per month.	(Stockpiling does allow B&amp;W to
	provide
limited	cigarettes at the rate of one share point for a
time.)
3.	We have screened 255 materials as new cigarette filters.
	The Duolite filter remains unique in its action.
M. L. R.
Attachments
M 13
Uti1Q64C:/1y
pgNbr=1
What is Cigarette Smoke?
Cigarette smoke is a very complicated mixture of liquid droplets and
gases. The liquid droplets constitute the particulate phase. The remainder
is called vapor phase or gas phase.
What is Tar?
The liquid droplets contain about 8,000 different chemical compounds
including nicotine and water. Tar is defined as the weight of these droplets
after subtraction of the weights of nicotine and water contained in them.
What is the Difference Between Gas Phase and Vapor Phase?
None as the tobacco industry uses the terms. Gas phase is the
description we will use here.
What Substances are in the Gas Phase?
Many of the compounds are present in both the gas phase and particulate
phase. Very volatile substances, acetaldehyde for example, are mostly in the
gas phase. Substances which are not very volatile, menthol for example, are
mostly in the particulate phase. About half the hydrogen cyanide is in the
gas phase, half in the particulate phase.
What are Aldehydes? . -
Aldehydes are a family of chemicals which all contain a characteristic
H
C\ Some common aldehydes
grouping of carbon, hydrogen and oxygen atoms:
0
are:
Formaldehyde: HCHO
Acetaldehyde: CH3CH0
Acrolein: CH2CHCH0
Benseldehyde: C6H5CH0
There are at least 27 aldehydes in smoke. Most of them contribute to overall
flavor. Certain aldehydes, particularly formaldehyde, acrolein and crotonaldehyde
621063817
pgNbr=2
are thought to contribute to harsh taste. Vapors from these three substances
(in much higher concentrations than found in cigarette smoke) are very painful
to inhale or smell. eenzaldehyde, on the other hand, smells like almond essence.
Many aldehydes are GRAS (generally recognized as safe) and used as flavorants
for foods. Some examples are: vanillin, cinnamic aldehyde (cinnamon), heliotropin
(sweet and floral), S-propyl acrolein (green leafy). Even acetaldehyde is GRAS.
If Acetaldehyde is GFAS why are you filtering it?
There are two reasons. First, although the odor of acetaldehyde is pleasant
in small concentrations, at high concentrations, acetaldehyde can be an irritant.
Second, acetaldehyde is relatively easy to measure. Filters which reduce
acetaldehyde also reduce acrolein, formaldehyde and crotonaldehyde which are
difficult to measure. We, therefore, use acetaldehyde filtration as a marku
for reduction of harsh aldehydes. .
Which Aldehydes are in the Gas Phase?
This question cannot be answered directly. As mentioned above, many
compounds are present in both the gas phase and particulate phase. No one
has a good method of determining the relative amounts of substances in each
phase. As a broad generalization, aldehydes which probably lead to harsh
taste are mostly in the gas phase, flavorful aldehydes are mostly in the
particulate phase. There are exceutions. Which Aldehydes does Duolite Reduce?
Duolite reduces formaldehyde, acetaldehyde, acrolein, propionaldehyde, .
methacrolein, crotonaldehyde and iso-valeraldehyde by 10 to 30%. We do not
know how much other aldehydes are reduced. Many are present in very small
quantities.
sLl06u818
pgNbr=3
Dow does Duolite Reduce Certain Aldehydes?
Duolite reacts chemically with aldehydes which are in the gas phase.
Duolite contains chemical "hooksJ' amino groups~NH, which react with the
characteristic aldehyde groups-CNO.This is in contrast to charcoal which
merely acts as a sponge. The amino groups in Duolite thus provide a selective
means of reducing aldehydes and certain other closely related chemicals. Duolite does not remove many flavorful compounds such as esters and pyrazines
which are soaked up by activated charcoal.
One further point which we keep coming back to. Hany chemicals are present
both in the gas phase and the particulate phase. Duolite, or charcoal,
reduce materials from the gas phase. When the concentration of a substance
in the gas phase is reduced by such a filter, the gas phase concentration
can be replenished from the particulate phase. In this way, even if only
30% of a chemical is in the gas phase at any one time, and even though the
filter is only removing material from the gas phase, filtration efficiencies
much greater than the 307. can be realized. One good example of this is the
removal of phenol by cellulose acetate filters. There is probably less than
57% of phenol present in the gas phase at any one time yet cellulose acetate
filters can remove as much as 80% of the phenol from cigarette smoke.
621063819
pgNbr=4
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
