<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aaq06c00</tid>
<bt>2071722508/2522</bt>
<dd>19990114</dd>
<dt>MEMO, MEMORANDUM</dt>
<dt>REPT, REPORT, OTHER</dt>
<au>ROLLI,NM</au>
<rc>BOWLIN,J; BRING,M; CAMILLERI,L; DEGYSSER,S; ECKERT,R; HENDRYS,P; HOLSENBECK,P; MACDONOUGH,J; PARRISH,S; SOMPOLSKI,T; SZYMANCZYK,M; WEBB,W</rc>
<pc>ANZISKA,D; BARRINGTON,M; BERAN,D; BRADISH,B; BROSIUS,K; BROWN,B; BURRELL,W; CARNEY,A; CARNOVALE,M; CAUTERO,R; CHATKEWITZ,A; COLLAMORE,T; COLLIER,C; COLLINS,R; DANGOOR,D; DARAGAN,K; DELISI,N; DOLLIVE,J; DONNER,J; FICEK,C; FLANNERY,D; FRAZIER,D; FRENCH,S; GALLAGHER,M; GENTILINI,L; GOMEZ,F; GOODALE,J; GREENBERG,D; GREENE,J; HAN,V; HARRISON,S; HERRICK,S; HERST,B; HODNETT,A; JACOBS,M; KAPLAN,R; KEANE,D; KELSEY,K; KENNY,M; KINNEY,M; KIRCHER,C; KNOX,G; LEVY,C; LEWINTER,D; LEWIS,G; LIEBENGOOD,H; LIU,K; MCADAMS,D; MCKEITHAN,P; MERLO,E; MINKOFF,R; MOWRER,J; MOY,N; MUDD,M; MULVIHILL,K; MURPHY,V; NAPIERALSKI,P; ODOCHARTAIGH,A; ODONNELL,L; PFEIL,M; ROLLI,N; SMITH,C; SMITH,O; SPECTOR,J; SPERA,J; STEELE,H; TAVANO,S; TIESI,J; TOSCANO,F; WAALKES,J; WALL,C; WHITSON,J</pc>
<np>RAUSCHENBERG,R; TIESI,J; XX GEOFF</np>
<ca>PMMC, PHILIP MORRIS MANAGEMENT CORP</ca>
<cr>PMMC, PHILIP MORRIS MANAGEMENT CORP</cr>
<pc>ANNUAL REPORT TEAM; KFI; KRAFT NORTH AMERICA; MILLER; PHILIP MORRIS; PMI, PHILIP MORRIS INTERNATIONAL; PMMC, PHILIP MORRIS MANAGEMENT CORP; PMUSA, PHILIP MORRIS USA</pc>
<no>1ST NATION DEVELOPMENT INST; AMERICAN INDIAN COLLEGE FUNDS; ANNUAL REPORT TEAM; CENTER FOR THE STUDY OF YOUTH POLICY; CHICAGO PUBLIC SCHOOL; CLAUSSEN; COMMUNITY KITCHENS; FTC, FEDERAL TRADE COMMISSION; KRAFT EMPLOYEE FUND; KRAFT NORTH AMERICA; KRAFTS FOODS EQUITY; MAXWELL HOUSE; MILLER BREWING; MILWAUKEE TEACHER EDUCATION CENTER; MISSION VIEJO; NATL AIDS FUND; NATL MEALS ON WHEELS FOUNDATION; NETWORK TO END DOMESTIC VIOLENCE FUND; OSCAR MAYER; PABST; PHILIP MORRIS; PHILIP MORRIS CAPITAL CORP; PHILIP MORRIS EMPLOYEE FUND; PMI, PHILIP MORRIS INTERNATIONAL; PMUSA, PHILIP MORRIS USA; S+P COMPANY; SHAREHOLDER PUBLICATIONS; STARBUCKS; UNIV OF PA</no>
<!-- Note:co:CONF, CONFIDENTIAL; DRFT, DRAFT; MARG, MARGINALIA-->
<fn>2071722507/2071722523/ANNUAL REPORT</fn>
<!-- Note:si:N905-->
<!-- Note:s:PFEIL,MICHAEL/STORED FILES-->
<ti>980000 ANNUAL REPORT TO STOCKHOLDERS: BUSINESS REVIEW AND CORPORATE CITIZENSHIP</ti>
<pg>15</pg>
<!-- Note:lu:FEDA/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:20020723-->
<!-- Note:b:ACCORD; APOLLO SOYUZ; BASIC; BENSON &amp; HEDGES; BOND STREET; CARO; CHESTERFIELD; HELIKON; KAZAKSTAN; L&amp;M; LARK; LONG BEACH; MARLBORO; MERIT; PARLIAMENT; PETER JACKSON; PETRA; PHILIP MORRIS; POLYOT; SPARTA; VIRGINIA SLIMS-->
<dl>20021209</dl>
<ot>structure], we believe that they should ultimately offer a greater measure of stability for
our employees, business partners and consumers.
With our clear track record of brand strength, superior marketing, effective cost
controls and excellence in implementation, we are planning for continued share gains in
one of the most dynamic consumer businesses in the United States.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 2

pgNbr=1
Since we announced our program to realign our international food business
in 1997, we have divested or closed TK non-strategic businesses and announced the
closure of TK manufacturing facilities to improve our business portfolio, and we have
continued to consolidate our sales forces in a number of markets. In 1998, we centralized
our purchasing, and combined our European Union businesses under a single regional
management, for greater effectiveness and productivity.
Despite significant challenges, including the increasing power of the retail trade
in Europe, continued price-based competition and slow economies in many markets, we
believe that our international food business is now on firmer ground to resume volume
and income growth.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 8

pgNbr=2
I
Financial Services
At Philip Morris Capital Corp., underlying income from operations was up an
impressive xx.x% to $xxx million. These results exclude a 1997 $103 million pre-tax
gain on the sale of Mission Viejo Company, our former real estate subsidiary.
We signiCcantly increased our investments in both our domestic and
international portfolios, as total assets grew 10% to $6.5 billion.
Our credit profile remained strong, due to our conservative selection of
investments across a wide variety of industry segments.
We intend to maintain growth in both our domestic and international portfolios,
and to achieve superior results through prudent, well-balanced investments.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 10

pgNbr=3
also saw double-digit volume increases, and Jell-O dry packaged desserts and shelf-stable
puddings gained share.
In Canada, although volume increased for key products such as coffee, Miracle
Whip dressings and cheese, total volume declined as we realigned our promotional
activities.
We continued our efforts to increase our marketing effectiveness. Our new
[Kraft Foods Equity and other] programs unite our brands and create partnerships with
complementary products, to increase packaged food sales for supermarkets and to
simplify food shopping and meal preparation for consumers.
We reduced overhead spending, both in absolute dollars and as a percent of
revenues, and productivity continued to increase.
We believe that Kraft is the North American packaged food company best
positioned to turn challenging trends such as increasing consolidation of the retail trade,
and increasing consumer demands for convenience, into opportunities for continued
volume gains. Kraffs brand portfolio, marketing and scale provide a firm foundation for
growth through new products, tactical acquisitions and alliances with other companies, as
we strengthen our claim to undisputed leadership of the food industry.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 6

pgNbr=4
Many other markets posted impressive volume and share gains, led by
Turkey, the Middle East, Mexico and Argentina. In addition, Marlboro achieved record
volume and share gains in Brazil despite a steep industry decline.
We continued to invest in and expand our international manufacturing base. We
acquired the assets of our former licensee in Indonesia; produced L&amp;M and Bond Street
at our new manufacturing facility in Romania; and began building manufacturing plants
in St. Petersburg, Russia, and in Almaty, Kazakhstan.
We expanded our youth smoking prevention efforts to include more than 60
programs in over 35 major markets. In addition, we are making efforts - in every one of
our markets - to support minimum-age laws, to support programs to restrict youth
access, to work with govenunents and competitors to ensure that cigarettes are
responsibly marketed to adult smokers only, and to apply "underage sales prohibited"
messages on every one of our packs where it is legally possible to do so.
The cigarette market outside the United States includes some 4.5 trillion
cigarettes we don't sell - yet. We are planning for still more volume, share and income
gains in this enormous market by further developing our world-class brand portfolio and
by continuing to expand and improve our infrastructure. Although we face many
challenges, particularly in Asia and Eastern Europe, we are the strongest player in the
international industry, well positioned for future growth.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 4

pgNbr=5
PHILIP MORRIS MANAGEMENT CORP. INTER-0FFICE CORRESPONDENCE
		120 PARK AVENUE, NEW YORK, NY 10017
ro:	Distribution	CONFIDENTIAL	DATE: January 14, 1999
			
aM	Nicholas M. Rolli		
ssEcr	1998_Annual_Report to Stockholders: B' ss Review and Co 0 orate Citizenshi 0
	Attached are first drafts of the busin iew and corporate citizenship sections for the
ort. The financial and other figures are not yet final.
As usual, we have a limited amount of space, so please try to balance requested additions
with deletions. So that we can finalize the report text on schedule, please get back to me or
the annual report team with comments no later than Friday, January 22, 1999. Following is
the schedule for further reviews of the report:
Release of year-end results	Wed 1/27
Distribution of typeset version, with photos and captions	Mon 2/1
Responses and final changes due	Fri 2/5
The February 1 typeset version, reflecting your comments, will be the first one that Geoff
sees.
Distribution:		
J. Bowlin	P.	Holsenbeck
M. Bring	J.	MacDonough
L. Camilleri	S.	Parrish
S. de Gysser	T.	Sompolski
R. Eckert	M. Szymanczyk
P. Hendrys	W. Webb

pgNbr=6
Disaster Relief
During 1998, Philip Morris contributed more than $1.8 million to assist 32
disaster relief efforts in 16 countries around the globe, providing funds, food, water and
volunteer services.
In the United States, we responded to floods, hurricanes and other disasters in a
dozen states from California to New York. Internationally, we contributed to relief
efforts in areas from Central America, Argentina and Brazil to Central Europe, China and
the Philippines.
Employee Volunteerism
Philip Morris employees continued to give back to their communities through a
variety of volunteer activities, including serving food in soup kitchens, tutoring children,
building homes for the needy and teaching adults to read.
Through the Philip Morris Employee Fund and Kraft Employee Fund-managed
by committees of employees representing a cross-section of the Philip Morris family - -
employees pledged $2.8 million in 1998, to which the companies will add more than
$1.35 million in 1999, for distribution to more than 100 charities and civic programs.
Commitment to Diversity
In 1998, we continued working at every level to strengthen and promote cultural
diversity throughout the Philip Morris workplace and among the vendors who serve us.
The percentages of women and of people of color among our U.S. employees, and
among our cadre of senior executives, have grown steadily since TK. In addition, we
spent approximately $940 million in 1998 to purchase goods and services from
businesses owned by women and by people of color, and approximately one of every five
corporate contributions dollars supported diversity-related organizations and projects.
For more information, please contact the Shareholder Publications office
identified on the inside back cover of this report.
1/14/99 draft: Corp. Cit. 3

pgNbr=7
cc:
Other PM Corporate
A. Carney
K. Brosius
B. Brown
R. Cautero
A. Chatkewitz
T. Collamore
J. Donner
N. De Lisi
S. French
M. Gallagher	L.
F.
J.
D.
V.
S.
D.
M.
G.
D.	Gentilini
Gomez
Goodale
Greenberg
Han
Harrison
Keane
Kenny
Knox
Lewinter	H. Liebengood
D. McAdams
K. Mulvihill
L. O'Donnell
J. Spector
J. Tiesi
F. Toscano
C. Wall
J. Whitson (H &amp; W)
PM USA	PMI		Kraft North America
M. Barrington
D. Beran	D.
W.	Anziska
Burrell	C. Collier
J. Dollive
M. Carnovale
K. Daragan
D. Frazier
C. Levy
E. Merlo
M. Pfeil	D.
J.
R.
K.
V.
0.	Dangoor
Greene
Kaplan
Kelsey
Murphy
Smith	C. Ficek
S. Herrick
B. Herst
J. Mowrer
M. Mudd
H. Steele			
Miller	PMCC	KFI
A.
P.	Hodnett
McKeithan	G.
J.	Lewis
Spera	B. Bradish
R. Collins
P.	Napieralski	S.	Tavano	M. Kinney
J.	Waalkes			K. Liu
N. Moy
A. O'Dochartaigh
C. Smith
Annual report team
Nick Rolli
Bob Minkoff
Chris Kircher
Michelle Jacobs
Debbie Flannery
Fax for annual report team:
(917) 663-5502.
Note: Accounting groups should provide supporting detail to Joe Tiesi (3955; fax 2824) by the close
of business Friday, January 22.

pgNbr=8
Beer
Underlying income at Miller Brewing Company continued to grow, increasing
to $xxx million. However, Miller's overall performance in 1998 proved disappointing.
Domestic shipment volume was down 1.8% and market share declined one
point, driven by continued intense competition and the absence of pricing advantages.
Domestic volume for Miller Lite fell, but remained above 19961evels. Volume
for Miller Genuine Draft was also down. However, shipments of Miller High Life grew
slightly. Toward the end of the year, Miller took steps to improve its advertising
campaigns for both Miller Lite and Miller Genuine Draft.
Both Icehouse and Foster's posted double-digit volume gains, for the second
year in a row. Within the Molson brand family, Miller focused on the Molson Canadian
brand, which also saw double-digit volume growth.
Miller entered into a five-year agreement to contract-brew Pabst and certain
other S&amp;P Company brands. The contract should result in additional income that Miller
can reinvest in its business.
Miller also strengthened its distribution network by introducing a new contract
to improve retail execution and increase distributors' commitment to Miller's product line
International sales of Miller products held steady at 2.6 million barrels, with
licensee and affiliate volume continuing to offset a planned decline in exports.
During the year, Miller took several innovative steps to improve its business.
As a result of increased efficiencies in the way our breweries handle glass bottles, Miller
was able to successfully introduce an 18-pack longneck bottle, a major new package for
Miller Lite, Miller Genuine Draft and Miller Genuine Draft Light. In a beer-industry
first, Miller introduced a special new recyclable plastic bottle for Miller Lite, Miller
Genuine Draft and Icehouse beers in six cities across the country. The new packaging
provides the taste, freshness and shelf life of a glass bottle, with the convenience of cans,
in response to strong interest from beer consumers.
Although Miller had a difficult year, it is addressing the challenges ahead with
creative solutions to stabilize its business and deliver better growth in the future.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 9

pgNbr=9
Domestic Tobacco
1998 was another solid year for our domestic tobacco business, as underlying
income rose x.x% to $x.x billion. Underlying results exclude $3.4 billion in pre-tax
charges for tobacco litigation settlements and early retirement and separation programs.
Including these charges, reported income of $x.x billion was down xx.x%.
Our shipment share rose to a record 49.4%, up 0.7 points. Total industry
shipments fe114.6%, well beyond the historic average 1-2% annual decline. We estimate
that the more rapid rate of decline [, which may worsen during 1999,] largely reflected
the impact of manufacturers' 1997 and 1998 [settlement-driven] price increases and the
decision of wholesalers to lower their year-end 1998 inventories.
Our shipment volume of xxx.x billion cigarettes was down 3.2% - a slower
rate of decline than the total industry's.
The premium segment continued to expand, growing to 73.1% of industry
shipments, and our own product mix improved fin•ther, as premium brands' share of our
shipments rose to 86.4%. Our share of the growing premium segment climbed to 58.4%.
Shipment share for Marlboro, the world's best-selling cigarette brand, rose
1.3 points to a record 35.3%, as shipments declined 0.9% to 162.5 billion cigarettes.
Share gains were aided by the January 19981aunch of Marlboro Ultra Lights, which
quickly became the country's leading ultra light brand and the tenth-largest cigarette
brand overall [chk]. In addition, Marlboro Menthol became the fastest growing major
menthol brand in the industry.
At retail, our share rose 1.6 points, spurred by Marlboro's gain of 2.3 points.
These results are directionally consistent with shipment performance, but do not include
data from certain growing trade classes.
Our other premium brands - Merit, Benson &amp; Hedges, Parliament and Virginia
Slims - accounted for 7.4% of industry shipments, down 0.4 points from 1997. However,
both Parliament and Virginia Slims held share.
Our leading discount brand, Basic, increased its share of the declining discount
segment, and its industry share rose to 5.1%.
In November, we agreed to purchase the U.S. rights to three cigarette brands
- L&amp;M, Lark and Chesterfield - which we already market overseas. The agreement is
subject to approval by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.
We began selling the Accord cigarette smoking system through a limited
number of outlets in Richmond, Virginia, in a retail sales test designed to provide
feedback on this new product from adult smokers.
We substantially reduced our manufacturing and administrative costs by
consolidating business functions and simplifying the organization.
Above and beyond the actions required by our litigation settlements, we
introduced our own $100 million Youth Smoking Prevention initiative to help reduce
under-age smoking. The program takes a four-pronged approach involving
communication, education, community involvement and controlling access to tobacco
products.
Although our litigation settlements impose new restrictions on our marketing
and other business practices [and could lead to further actions to realign our cost
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL I

pgNbr=10
We also sponsored the first corporate conference on domestic violence in the
United States, and funded a series of public service advertisements aimed at increasing
public awareness of the domestic violence issue.
Positive Youth Development
With the hope that we can positively influence youth development and discourage
under-age use of tobacco products, Philip Morris U.S.A. provided funding to help
establish a "Children, Youth and Families at Risk" program within the Center for the
Study of Youth Policy at the University of Pennsylvania. Research focuses on
determining the components that make youth programs effective in reducing risky
behavior, including under-age smoking.
This program is in addition to the many efforts being made by Philip Morris
International and Miller Brewing Company to discourage use of their products by under-
age consumers, and is part of Philip Morris U.S.A.'s commitment to spend $100 million
in 1999 to discourage under-age smoking.
Culture
In honor of our 40' anniversary of support for culture and the arts, we launched
the worldwide "Arts Against Hunger" food drive in partnership with leading arts
organizations and food banks. The initiative offers discounts to audience members who
contribute canned food. In 1998, our support enabled arts organizations to reduce ticket
costs, while the audience's food donations helped local agencies provide millions of
meals each month to the hungry.
Other highlights included the exhibition "Robert Rauschenberg: A Retrospective"
in Cologne, Germany and Bilbao, Spain; the 1998 "Photobiennale" in Russia; "Head,
Heart and Hands: Native American Craft Traditions" in Louisville, Kentucky, and
Columbus, Ohio; and "Mexico Now" in Chicago and Houston.
Kraft's Arts-In-Education initiative continued to increase access to the arts for
disadvantaged children. In 1998, the program brought together TK students, teachers and
family members to share in cultural events. In addition, Philip Morris and Kraft have
contributed more than $1 million to "Art Discovery," a collaboration between 12 of
Chicago's premier cultural institutions and the Chicago Public School system.
Education
We support education through a focus on teachers, parents and mentors. Since
TK, our educational grants totaling $TK million have benefited more than TK programs
and organizations.
In 1998, in partnership with Miller Brewing Company, our contribution to the
Milwaukee Teacher Education Center helped prepare and support TK new and veteran
teachers. We also continued our support of the American Indian College Fund's teacher
training initiative, which has helped to recruit and train more than 500 native Americans

for teaching careers, and our adult literacy program expanded to reach more than 73	



N


O
4
	~
organizations in 25 states.	-4
Internationally, our education programs included scholarships in Malaysia,

as well as literacy programs in Brazil and Morocco
Indonesia and the Ukraine	N
N
~
,
.	N
1/14/99 draft: Corp. Cit. 2

pgNbr=11
International Food
1998 marked the beginning of renewed progress in our international food
business.
Although volume declined due to economic conditions in Russia and Brazil as
well as soft coffee markets in Europe in the first half of the year, we saw good gains in
the established markets of the United Kingdom, Italy, Spain, the Benelux countries,
Norway, Denmark and Australia. Importantly, most of our major European coffee,
confectionery and grocery brands showed share growth in the second half of the year.
Underlying income of $x.x billion was slightly below 19971evels, due primarily
to increased brand-building marketing investments in Europe, lower coffee volume and
the Russian economic crisis. The comparison of underlying results excludes, most
significantly, the impact of two 1997 items: charges to realign the business and the gain
from our sale of ice cream businesses in Brazil.
Coffee volume was down due to the impact of high commodity-driven retail
prices in the beginning of the year. However, declines in retail prices encouraged
recoveries in most of our major markets in the second half of the year, and full-year
volume was up in the established markets of Italy and Austria and in the developing
markets of Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia and Hungary.
We gained share in the roast and ground coffee category in Germany, our largest
market, benefiting in part from marketing initiatives for Meisterrostung, our value brand.
In addition, we saw share gains for premium Carte Noire and.7acques Vabre roast and
ground coffees in France, Gevalia roast and ground coffee in Sweden and soluble Kenco
and Maxwell House coffees in the United Kingdom.
Although confectionery volume was lower, principally as a result of market
conditions in Russia and pricing in Germany, share for our key chocolate brand Milka
grew in France, Italy and Spain, aided in part by successful promotions and new products.
In Germany, a 25`' anniversary celebration of the Mflka brand symbol, the "Milka Cow,"
strengthened consumer and trade awareness, and we launched several new Milka line
extensions. In our Central European markets, we introduced line extensions for Prince
Polo in Poland and Korona in the Ukraine, and we launched Sugus in Romania. We also
expanded Forte and 3-Bit confectioneries throughout the region. In Brazil, our Lacta
products gained share despite a sharp market decline.
Volume grew in our cheese and grocery business on gains in many markets,
including Italy, Spain, the United Kingdom, the Middle East, Africa, Australia and China.
Especially strong volume growth in the United Kingdom was fueled by successful
promotions for Dairylea Dunkers and the introduction of Dairylea Lunchables. We also
launched Kraft Lunchables in Germany and expanded Tang powdered soft drinks in
Romania and Turkey. Philadelphia Brand cream cheese continued to grow strongly, with
volume and share gains in several markets including Italy, Spain and Australia. In
addition, Estrella and Maarud snacks gained volume in Scandinavia. However,
powdered soft drink volume declined in Latin America, due primarily to the impact on
our beverage business of a price war between carbonated soft drink manufacturers in
Argentina.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 7

pgNbr=12
Corporate Citizenship
We define ourselves at the Philip Morris family of companies by our deep
involvement in the communities where we live and work, and by our strong support
for programs that serve undeniable human needs. We have had a prominent
corporate citizenship program for more than 40 years, because it's the right thing to
do. Following are highlights of our 1998 corporate citizenship activities.
Hunger
Combating hunger is our primary grant-making priority. Philip Morris remains
one of the largest corporate funders of hunger-relief programs throughout the United
States, and we have given more than $170 million in cash grants and food product
donations to hunger programs around the world since 1990.
In 1998, we launched a national awareness campaign in the United States to
encourage others to help fight hunger. We also supported overseas hunger programs in a
wide range of countries, including the United Kingdom, Hungary, Bulgaria, Lithuania,
Australia and the Philippines.
Our national "Helping the Helpers" U.S. program supports organizations that
provide direct services to people in need. The program includes Senior Helpings, our
partnership with the National Meals on Wheels Foundation to improve meals for the
homebound elderly across America and overseas... Fighting Hunger, a pioneering Miller
program that forms public-private partnerships to address critical hunger relief needs. ..
Community Kitchens, Foodchain's unique program to train unemployed and homeless
people for the foodservice industry while providing meals for the hungry... Native
American Hunger Program, in partnership with First Nations Development Institute, to
address hunger on rural Native American reservations; and Kraft's Fresh Produce
Initiative, through which Kraft and Philip Morris are providing $7.5 million to help food
banks provide some 500 million servings of fresh fruit and vegetables a year to people
who need them most.
As one of the largest corporate contributors to HIV/AIDS programs, we have
focused many of our efforts on the importance of nutrition. In 1998, our Positive
Helpings Program, developed in partnership with the National AIDS Fund, helped fill the
nutritional needs of more than TK people with HIV/AIDS.
Domestic Violence
Philip Morris is a leading corporate supporter of national programs to help victims
of domestic violence and to raise public awareness of the impact domestic violence can
have in the workplace.
In 1998, our $2 million commitment to the fight against domestic violence
included "Doors of Hope," a $1 million program developed in partnership with the
national Network to End Domestic Violence Fund. Through this program, we provided
grants to 132 organizations in a1150 states, focusing on direct services such as food,
shelter, clothing, counseling and job training, as well as outreach, training and awareness
programs.
1/14/99 draft: Corp. Cit. 1

pgNbr=13
International Tobacco
Our international tobacco business again set volume and income records,
despite difficult economic conditions in parts of Asia and Eastern Europe.
International shipments of xsx billion cigarettes were up by x.x billion
cigarettes, and our share grew in virtually all major markets. Volume grew a collective
5% in the established markets of Western Europe and Japan, which account for nearly
60% of our international tobacco income.
Our income [did something quantitative] for the first time, up xx.x%, as
continued strong volume gains in higher-margin markets more than offset the $336
million impact of unfavorable currency.
We estimate that volume for the huge, 5.2-trillion-cigarette international
industry held steady for the year, despite the impact of regional economic crises.
However, the 1.7-trillion-cigarette international-blend segment, in which most of our
cigarettes compete, continued to grow.
The premium-priced Marlboro family sustained its international momentum,
posting a volume gain of almost 4%, with strong performance in a number of important
markets including Italy, France, the Benelux countries, Spain, Portugal, Greece, Austria,
Switzerland, Poland, Hungary, the Middle East, Turkey, Japan, Mexico, Argentina and
Brazil. Marlboro Lights, Marlboro Menthol and Marlboro Medium continued to enjoy
double-digit growth rates, and we successfully launched Marlboro Ultra Lights in
Germany and Switzerland. V
The impact of adverse economic contitions in Russia and other Eastern European
markets lowered overall volume for L&amp;M, but the brand held its position as the world's
third most popular international-blend cigarette and continued to gain share in many
important markets, notably Spain, France and Poland.
We estimate that we now account for four of the top 10 leading international
cigarette brands: Marlboro, L&amp;M, Bond Street and Philip Morris. In addition, our wide
range of local brands showed continued strength during the year, with aggregate volume
up almost 5%.
Our volume grew well in the established markets of Western Europe, paced by
strong performances in Italy, France, Spain and the Benelux countries. Our overall share
hit a record 36%, strengthening our leadership position in the region.
Volume in Central and Eastern Europe was down as economic turbulence
lowered shipments in the second half of the year, especially in Russia and other Eastern
European markets. However, local brands such as Apollo Soyuz, Polyot, Kazakstan,
Caro, Petra, Sparta and Helikon performed well, and we gained volume and share in
Poland and Hungary.
In the AsialPacific region, excellent performances of Marlboro and Lark drove
significant volume gains in Japan, where we gained a full share point. Our shares also
grew strongly in Singapore and Hong Kong, and Longbeach and Peter Jackson fueled
volume and share growth in Australia. However, the regional economic downturn
lowered volume in the Philippines, Indonesia and Korea.
Business Review 1/8 draft CONFIDENTIAL 3

pgNbr=14
North American Food
Kraft's North American food business turned in another good year, as new
product successes and effective marketing drove strong volume growth.
Underlying income rose a solid x.x% to $x.x billion, fueled by higher volume
and aggressive cost management, partially offset by slower growth for some of our most
profitable products. Income margins rose 0.6 points to a record 17.6%.
Kraft's beverage business served up higher volume. Gains for ready-to-drink
Capri Sun and Kood Aid Bursts beverages, as well as new Country Time Lemonade Ice
Teas and Koo! Aid Splash products, more than offset declines for Kool-Aid powdered soft
drinks.
Our pizza business again fired up exceptional results. In our third consecutive
year of double-digit volume gains, our share rose to a record 37.5%, boosted by new Di
Giorno Rising Crust and Tombstone Stuffed Crust offerings. We further expanded the
business through our licensing agreement to manufacture, market and sell California
Pizza Kitchen frozen pizzas to grocery customers.
Our meals business generated strong volume gains, powered by the
momentum of the Taco Bell Home Originals line and new product successes such as
Stove Top Oven Classics dinner kits, Krafi "DC" Super Heroes Macaroni &amp; Cheese and
Easy Mac dinners, and Minute Rice and Cheese side dishes.
Post cereals scored good volume gains and share climbed to 17.2%, driven by
the success of Honey Nut Shredded Wheat, introduced in the second half of 1997, and
Oreo O's, launched in 1998. Volume also grew for established cereals such as Honey
Bunches of Oats, Great Grains and Honeycomb.
Volume grew in our cheese business despite record high dairy costs, with good
gains for most product lines, including Kraft Slices, Velveeta Loaves and Breakstone's
sour cream and cottage cheese. New products such as Kraft Natural Cheese Cubes and
Cheddar Classic Melts cheese also fueled volume growth.
Our processed meats business registered its sixth consecutive year of volume
gains. Oscar Mayer Lunchables lunch combinations strengthened its category leadership
through the continued growth of Taco Bell Lunchables and the successful introductions
of Lunchables Pizza Dunks and Swirls as well as All Star Burgers and All Star Hot Dogs.
Volume gains were also driven by Oscar Mayer bacon, new Louis Rich Carving Board
Strips and Seasoned Meats, and Claussen pickles.
Maxwell House coffee volume was up, and we gained share in the premium
segment. We laid the groundwork for an expanded presence in the gourmet coffee
segment by signing a licensing agreement to market, sell and distribute Starbucks coffee
to grocery customers across the United States.
Our enhancers business made progress against stiff competition, with volume
up in both pourable and spoonable dressings. Kraft pourable salad dressings gained
share, benefiting from the launch of Special Collections and Light Done Right! offerings.
In spoonable dressings, we began shipping new flavors of Kraft mayonnaise and Miracle
Whip dressings toward the end of the year.
In desserts and snacks, our confectionery products racked up strong volume
gains, led by Altoids mints' double-digit growth. Handi-Snacks ready-to-eat puddings
Business Review 118 draft CONFIDENTIAL 5

pgNbr=15
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
