<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae04d00</tid>
<bt>508228221/8226</bt>
<rc>CHRISTOPHER FH JR</rc>
<au>RJR;DIMARCO GR;I RWS</au>
<bx>RJRC1712</bx>
<!-- Note:b:VANTAGE 100;MERIT;SALEM ULTRA LIGHTS MENTHOL 85-->
<pc>LONG GH;ANGUOLI R;DAHNE WD;EMKEN RA;HILDEBOLT WM;FITZGERALD CW;MYERS GM;JUCHATZ WW;WINEBRENNER JT;R&amp;D DIRECTORS;BASS LL III;RHOADS AC;BARROW LB;SIMMONS RW;WHEELER JJ;DIMARCO GR</pc>
<!-- Note:rn t="p":1RFP4;1RFP39;1RFP47;4RFP8;4RFP9-->
<dd>19871211</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<!-- Note:co:Y-->
<np>AVOCA;MUELLER EXTRACT;COBER ELECTRONICS;EPA;MONTREAL PROTOCOL;UNEP;RJR;CORESTA;JENKINS R;PHILIP MORRIS</np>
<!-- Note:dl:19980227-->
<pg>6</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":MINNESOTA 1RFP61;TEXAS COURT ORDER 19970811-->
<!-- Note:sh:19960628-->
<!-- Note:s:R&amp;D;R&amp;D ADMIN;GOFORTH PG;EXECUTIVE ASST-->
<ti>R&amp;D WEEKLY HIGHLIGHTS.</ti>
<!-- Note:tp:IN-HOUSE RESEARCH ON SMOKING &amp; HEALTH; SMOKING BY-PRODUCTS; TRADE ASSOCIATIONS OTHER THAN CTR/TI-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>R.J.Reynolds Tobacca Com; =riy
°nRon
December 11, 1987
T0: Mr. F. H. Christopher, Jr.
SUBJECT: R&amp;D Weekly Highlights
BRAND R&amp;D
FFLT DEVELOPMENT
VANTAGE 100
COMPETITIVE TEST RESULTS: VANTAGE 100 ACHIEVES PARITY POSITION VERSUS MERIT
100
Current competitive wave scores indicate VANTAGE 100 is rated at parity to
Merit 100 among the competitive target smokers and maintains its superiority
to Merit 100 among franchise smokers. Merit 100 has experienced a decline in
overall acceptance due to attribute performance.
ULT MENTHOL DEVELOPMENT
SALEM Ultra Lights 85
PRODUCTION OF SALEM ULTRA LIGHTS 85 WITH WHOLE LEAF CG3 (30'/ INCLUSION LEVEL)
HAS BEGUN
SED diagnostic results have been received on the incorporation of whole leaf
CG3 in SALEM Ultra Lights 85 at 30, 60, and 100% levels. Results indicated no
perceptual differences were noted on all three tested levels for tobacco
aroma, menthol aroma, lit resistance, menthol flavor, tobacco flavor, overall
impact, cooling sensation, mouth sensation, burn rate, throat dryness, cooling
sensation, aftertaste, and biting aftertaste. Production began 12/7 on SALEM
Ultra Lights 85 with whole leaf CG3 at the 30% inclusion level. After Phase
III data and primary data is reviewed and PT&amp;D determines whole leaf
production capabilities, 100% whole leaf CG3 will be implemented.
pgNbr=1
APPLIED R&amp;D
Total Dilution Study
ADDITIONAL TESTS PLANNED TO DETERMINE IF DILUTION CONTROL BY TOTAL DILUTION
CAN REDUCE 'TAR' VARIABILITY
The results of analyses of the total dilution sample data and total dilution
simulation were discussed with representatives of Product and Process Control
and Tobaccoville. The.results indicate no detrimental effects of dilution
control using total dilution. Additional testing has been requested to
determine if dilution control by total dilution can reduce 'tar' variability.
These tests are being planned.
Manufacturing Standards System (MSS)
FILTER SHELF-LIFE LIMITS ADDED
Filter shelf-life limits have been added to all current filter specifications.
Flue-Cured Stabilization Buyout Usage Plan
TOBACCO STANDARDS TO RE-RUN SIX-YEAR USAGE MODEL TO REVIEW IMPLICATIONS FOR
BLENDING AND INVENTORY LEVELS
Numerous meetings have been held between Finance and Tobacco Standards to
review the six-year usage plan for flue-cured stabilization buyout tobacco.
Finance informed Tobacco Standards that the 1988 purchase program for
stabilization buyout tobacco had been reduced from 40 MM to 20 MM pounds green
weight. In addition, over half of that purchase would be lower tier grades
(Category B, C, and D). The anticipated impact of these decisions on Tier 1
blends has been discussed. Tobacco Standards will re-run the six-year usage
model to review the implications for blending and inventory levels.
ADMINISTRATION AND AGRICULTURAL SCIENCE
AVOCA
Miscellaneous
The preparation of 10 lbs. of ethyl vanillin glycoside has been completed and
the material transferred to Brand R&amp;D. The assembly of a system necessary to
2
pgNbr=2
produce pilot scale developmental batches (25 lbs.) for future testing and the
gathering of design data for possible scale-up in 1988 is underway.
The expansion of the supercritical extraction screening unit to 4-liter
capacity is complete, except for furnaces which are to be delivered later this
month.
Discussions were held at Avoca with PT&amp;D personnel on the high pressure pilot
plant and on the design, purchase, and installation of the variable volume
vessel needed for the extract enriched expansion project. Topics discussed
relative to the high pressure pilot plant include safety features, hazard
analysis, bulk bag handling of tobacco - before and after high pressure
treatment, and process control equipment. A consensus was reached that the
variable volume vessel -for extract enriched expansion work will be installed
as part of the new bench scale supercritical extraction unit.
PROCESS TECHNOLOGY &amp; DEVELOPMENT
Separation Methods - Supercritical Extraction
SUPERCRITICAL EXTRACT RECEIVED
The first of the supercritical extracts to be received from Mueller Extract
Co. has arrived. K22 extract was received last week and is currently being
refined in our laboratory for testing as a burley flavor enhancer. It is ex-
pected that the remaining extracts; as well as, portions of the extracted
tobaccos, will be shipped shortly.
Alternate Tobacco Forms: Screw Extrusion
EXTRUDER USED FOR RECONSTITUTION
Reconstituted sheet, containing spray dried 1983 burley and inorganic filler
material, was produced using the leased extruder in support of exploratory
Brand Technology projects.
: Alternate Expansion Processes: High Rate Drying/Puffing
MICROWAVE FEASIBILITY TESTS PLANNED
Cober Electronics facilities have been visited, after preliminary discussions
indicated that they have appropriate expertise and technology. A feasibility
test plan has been outlined. Resultant materials will be evaluated for fill-
ing capacity and sensory attributes, if appropriate.
y
3
pgNbr=3
EPA Restrictions on Chlorofluorocarbons
PLANS FOR TOBACCO EXPANSION PROGRAM CONSISTENT WITH EPA'S PROPOSED
RESTRICTIONS
-Tfi e Environmental Protection Agency issued notice 12/1 of proposed restric-
tions for the production and consumption of chlorofluorocarbons. Regulations
will be full implementation of the Montreal Protocol adopted by UNEP and will-
be controlled through production quota. This action is consistent and com-
patible with the Tobacco Expansion Program plans.
G7 Process Improvements
COST ESTIMATES TO BE OBTAINED FOR IMPROVEMENTS AND MODIFICATIONS TO INCREASE
PRODUCTION YIELD
Efforts have commenced to obtain a cost estimate from improvements and
modifications at G7 Plant No. 603 to increase production yield. Engineering,
Tobacco Processing Division, and PT&amp;D are participating in this study.
Specific improvements include two Fourdriniers and new extractor white water
system changes. A budget estimate will be available during January.
Wrinkled Cigarettes Investigation
INITIAL EVALUATION INDICATES INCREASE IN CIGARETTE PAPER WEIGHT DECREASES NUM-
BER OF WRINKLED CIGARETTES
Samples have been collected to evaluate wrinkled cigarettes during Brand R&amp;D's
testing of several basis weight cigarette papers. Initial evaluation of the
raw data shows clearly that the number of wrinkled cigarettes, both at the
maker and from the packer, decrease quite rapidly as the weight of the paper
increases. A full report will be issued by PT&amp;D Statisticians, as soon as
analysis is completed. PT&amp;D will continue to work with Brands in collecting
wrinkle data in the Pilot Plant and eventually, Manufacturing.
On-Line Nicotine Measurement
FLUE-CURED SAMPLES BEING GATHERED TO CALIBRATE NICOTINE GAUGE FOR FLUE-CURED
GROUP BLENDED STRIPS
A sample set of 200 pre-selected flue-cured samples is presently being
gathered by Leaf Processing for the calibration of the IR 512 nicotine gauge
for flue-cured group blended strips (GBS). This gauge has already been cali-
brated and demonstrated to predict nicotine on-line for burley strips.
s
4
pgNbr=4
R&amp;D TECHNICAL SERVICES
NOVEMBER SUMMARY REPORT
1.	Analytical Support:	Tobacco Analyses	3,773
		Smoke Analyses	26,677
		Other Analyses	1 303
		Total	31,753
2.	Sensory Evaluation:	Products Evaluated - R&amp;D	85
		- NPT	22
		- Total	107
3.	R&amp;D Library:		
Document Acquisition Services:	Articles Ordered	493
	Books Ordered	100
	Interlibrary Loans	52
Reference Services:	Reference Calls	577
	On-line Searches	77
Information Acquisition:	Journal Citations	333
BIOCHEMICAL/BIOBEHAVIORAL R&amp;D
Pesticides
THIODAN RESIDUE RESULTS OBTAINED FROM 1987 CROP FROM TURKEY: AKHISAR DISTRICT
HAS HIGHEST THIODAN RESIDUES
Thiodan residue results were obtained for 90 tobacco samples of 1987 crop from
Turkey. Thiodan residues ranged from below the detection limit to 85 ppm.
The Akhisar district had the highest thiodan residues. The Kirkagae, Bergama,
and Gordes districts had consistently low thiodan residues. Akhisar is the
wealthiest district and growers apparently have greater access to chemicals.
Samples submitted for analysis were identified by village and farmer. An
effort will be made to segregate tobacco purchases by RJR from farmers showing
5
pgNbr=5
excessive thiodan residues. Residue data were obtained for 13 samples of 1987
crop burley tobacco from China. No detectable residues were seen for these
.samples.
TORESTA Task Force
JANUARY MEETING BEING PLANNED
Current RJR methods for collection and assessment of sidestream nicotine,
WTPM, CO, and C02 will be presented at the January meeting of the CORESTA
group. A meeting was held with Dr. R. Jenkins (Philip Morris) to discuss
other methods submitted and the organization of the upcoming meeting.
g (~) 04 ~a-tzo/
G. R. Di Marco 42V--~&gt;
/1c:m33
Distribution
Mr. G. H. Long
Mr. R. Anguoli
Mr. W. D. Dahne
Mr. R. A. Emken
Mr. C. W. Fitzgerald
Dr. W. M. Hildebolt
Mr. G. M. Myers
Mr. W. W. Juchatz
Mr. J. T. Winebrenner
xc: R&amp;D Directors
Mr. L. L. Bass, III
Mr. A. C. Rhoads
Ms. L. B. Barrow
Mr. R. W. Simrans
Mr. J. J. Wheeler
5
6
pgNbr=6
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
