<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aad43d00</tid>
<bt>512175274/5301</bt>
<au>CLAPP WL;MCGEE CD;MUNOZ JA;OCONNOR LH;RIDINGS AV;YOUNG HJ;PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT;SOHN EJ;PERFETTI TA;HODGE BT;BURGER FT</au>
<bx>RJRC3553</bx>
<!-- Note:b:NON-RJR BRANDS-->
<pc>I ELW;EHMANN CW;BURGER GT;BORSCHKE AJ;HARDIN RV;TINSLEY CE III;BLIXT CA;WILLARD RL;PHILLIPS JD;DEBETHIZY JD;WHEELER JP;SELLERS FO;SUBER RL;CURTIS LE;DAHNE WD;LIBRARY;CLAPP WL;MUNOZ JA;OCONNOR LH;RIDINGS AV;SOHN EJ;YOUNG HJ;MCGEE CD;PERFETTI TA;HODGE BT;WALKER VC;FOY BT;DUFOUR WM;CULP GD;COOK WR;JACOB SW;LUFFMAN WC;PORTER TJ;ARMSTRONG ST;SMITH SL;BROWN TW;HICKMAN TL;ANDRESEN NP;WILHELM DE;MARTIN TG;LAMONDS DI;MITCHELL JS;GUESS HE;BEESON DH;WILLIAMS EL</pc>
<!-- Note:rn t="p":1RFP129-->
<dd>19940211</dd>
<dt>FORMAL R&amp;D REPORT</dt>
<!-- Note:co:Y-->
<np>RJR;PHILIP MORRIS;YOUNG HJ;BURGER GT;HAUNI;MORGAN W;CALLESON ;CLAPP WL;MORGAN WT</np>
<!-- Note:dl:19990615-->
<pg>28</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":MINNESOTA 1RFP129-->
<!-- Note:sh:19970217-->
<!-- Note:s:MANUFACTURING;TOBACCO PROCESSING;WILLIAMS L-->
<ti>PD 94-042. THE EFFECT OF CIGARETTE MAKING ON TOBACCO BLENDS CONTAINING PROCESSED TOBACCOS.</ti>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>reduced as the inclusion level was increased. In fact, reductions of 10-15% in weight, while
achieving comparable firinnesses were the norm in this t.est. For G7 and CRES, however, the
Figure 7.
Before Makii!9 Filling Values
600
/~ 650
.~
600
400
-_-~~-_ 10 20
Inclusion Level
r--0 07 -a-- O 19 -a-- CRES --SPS
t-- -----_.---------
30
Figure 8.
After Making Filli&gt;&lt;g yalues
400
660
450
600
0
10
'----~_.
20
t
30
40
40
Inclusion Level
--0Ci7 -o-019 --CRES -«-SP
~ -- - ------~
13

pgNbr=1
SUMMARY OU'I'PUT	G7 Longs				
Regression Statistics __				
Multiple R
R Square
Adjusted R Square
Standard Error
Observations	0.352677512
0.124381428
-0.16749143
0.036790236
5				
ANOVA					
	df __~SS ~ ,	A1S	F	Significance F	
Regression
Residual
Total	1 0.000576802
3 0.004060564
4 0.004637367	0.000577
0.001354	0.426149	0.560447706	
					
	Coecients_Standard Error	t Stat	P-value	Lower 95%	Upper 95%
Intercept	0.71791874 0.028497594	25.19226	0.000137	0.627226592	0.808610888
% Inclusion	0.000759475 0.001163409	0.652801	0.560448	-0.002943016	0.004461966
SUMMARY OUTPUT
Rg ression Statistics __
Multiple R 0.804942389
R Square 0.647932249
Adjusted It Square 0.530576333
Standard Error 0.024961153
Observations 5

ANOVA
Regression
Residual
Total
Intercept	0.65778068	0.019334826	34.02051
% Inclusion	0.001854714	0.000789341	2.349699
G19 Longs
3
4
SS _ A1S F Significance F
0.003439964 0.00344 5.521087 0.100333186
0.001869178 0.000623
0.005309142
_ ~ Coe rcients Standard Error t Stat P-value Lower 95% Upper 95%
5.58E-05 0.596248576 0.719312784
0.100333 -0.000657324 0.004366752
25

pgNbr=2
and the highest level of fines. However, CRES material which will be produced on the new line at
Tobaccoville is eaq)ected to be a much improved product over this which was produced on the
temporary line at Shed 113. This new CRES could certainly be tested under the same test protocol
to verify that the improvements are realized through the maker.
Although limited data were obtained on finished cigarette characteristics other than particle
size, G19 and SPS were found to contribute in a positive manner to filling values and weight
reductions in the finished cigarettes, whereas, the G7 and CRES materials used in this study
contributed little in either a positive or a negative manner.
It is recommended from this work and earlier studies cited in this report, that careful
attention be given to the integrity of our processed tobaccos and the extent to which they may be
degraded by the making process. An increase in longs and a decrease in fines in the finished products
should result in a blend with increased filling values and may generate cost savings through the
resulting changes in the quantities of the strip tobaccos in the blend. In any event, a more detailed
study should be conducted on the high speed makers in Manufacturing to determine the validity of
these findings.
STATUS: This phase ofthe work is complete. Additional work is planned to quantify the
individual and interactive effects of each of the processed tobaccos used in Company blends from
initial processing through making on a Protos unit, and on opportunities to improve G7 sheet
strength and cutting.
KEYWORDS: G7-1, G19-1, CRES, DIET, puffed stems; particle size distribution, sieve analyses,
burn rate, cylinder filling value, tobacco analyses, smoke analyses, cigarette analyses, strand•length.
2

pgNbr=3
Overall, increasing the level of G7 had no detrimental effect on finished cigarette properties observed
here relative to the control blend. Increasing levels of G19, CRES, and SPS resulted in worsening
particle size distribution than the control blend, while G19 and SPS resulted in improved filling
capacity, reduced weight and increased draft. G19, CRES, and SPS also resulted in increased burn
rate and reduced pufl'count.
Walter T. Morgan
22

pgNbr=4
SUMMARY OUTPUT
Re ression Statistics
~--- -		
Multiple R	0.726319536		
R Square	0.527540069		
Adjusted R Square	0.370053425		
Standard Error	0.23815964		
Observations	5		
ANOVA			
	df __	SS	MS
Regression	1	_
0.189997574	0.189998
Residual	3	0.170160043	0.05672
Total	4	0.360157616	

_ -	Coe rcients Standard Error	t Stat
Intercept	2.075131294	0.184477664	11.24869
% Inclusion	-0.01378396	0.007531269	-1.83023
SUMMARY OUTPUT
Re~;ression Statistics __
Multiple R 0.709340707
R Square 0.503164239
Adjusted R Square 0.337552319
Standard Error 0.204485054
Observations 5
ANOVA
CRES Fines
F Signifrcance F
3.349745 0.164631899
P-value Lower 95% Upper 95%
0.001506 1.488040483 2.662222105
0.164632 -0.037751843 0.010183921
SPS Fines
SS
__ _
df
MS F Significance F
Regression
Residual
Total	1
3
4	0.127040243
0.125442412
0.252482654	0.127040243
0.041814137	3.038212697	0.179682057
					
_ -_~-	Coe reient.c ,S'tandard Error	t Stal		P-value	Lower 95%
Intercept	1.854169507	0.158393442	11.70610025	0.001339494	1.350090411
% Inclusion	-0.011271213	0.006466385		- 0.179682057	-0.031850156
1.743046958
Upper 95%
2.358248602
0.00930773
28

pgNbr=5
l)ish ibution:
Cover Page Only:
I)r. C. W. Ehmann
Dr. G. T. Burger
Mr. A. J. Borschke
Mr. R. V. Hardin
Mr. C. E. Tinsley, III
Mr. C. A. Blixt
Mr. R. L. Willard
Mr. J. D. Phillips
Dr. J. D. deBethizy
Ms. J. P. Wheeler
Mr. F. O. Sellers
Dr. R. L. Suber
Ms. L. (_. Curtis
Mr. W. D. Dahne
17
Complete Copy:
Library (original)
W. L. Clapp
J. A. Munoz
L. H. O'Connor
A. V. Ridings
E. J. Sohn
H. J. Young
C. D. McGee
T. A. Perfetti
B. T. Hodge
V. C. Walker
B. T. Foy
W. M. Dufour
G. D. Culp
W. R. Cook
S. W. Jacob
W. C. Luffinan
T. J. Porter
S. T. Armstrong
S. L. Smith
T. W. Brown
T. L. Hickman
N. P. Andresen
D. E. Wilhelm
T. G. Martin
D. I. Lamonds
J. S. Mitchell
H. E. Guess
D. H. Beeson
E. L. Williams

pgNbr=6
retained on 6 mesh and 10 mesh screens), "middlings" (% retained on 14 mesh and 20 mesh screens)
and "fines" (% passed through a 20 mesh screen). A second portion of each of these tobacco
samples was collected and used for moisture and cylinder filling volume determinations.
DISCIISSION:
Strand Length Distribution
Table III shows the results from determinations of longs, middlings and fines (by sieve
analyses) for each of the processed tobaccos as well as blends of each of the different processed
tobaccos with the control cut filler. Each of the values in Table III are the result of at least two
determinations, and in the case of the control cut filler blend are the result of five determinations.
~ .		
Lon s %	
M'ttitlli s %	
7ri ~ics %
Test Leg	%	
I3et'ore~	
After-	

13eforc-	

Aftcr-	:~efore-	Aftcr- '
_	L~cli~siAxr	
Maki~
_	
JYit~ki~l	
lY,I '	
N1[a.ldn	~altiu	1Vl&lt; _ '
C_ontrol_
+	0%	63	42	32	47	5.3	10
	10%	63	48	31	44	5.7	8.1
	20%	69	52	28	40	3.1	7.4
G7-1	30%	65	48	31	44	4.2	8.2
	40%	73	53	26	40	1.2	6.6
_
Y	100%	65	-	32		2.9	
	10%	69	46	27	44	4.1	9.7
	20%	57	38	35	48	7.7	14
G19-1	30%	56	39	35	46	9.4	15
	40%	49	37	38	47	12	15
_
~ ~	100%	26 _		52		23	
	10%	60	39	34	50	5.9	13
	20%	56	35	36	50	8.5	15
CRES*	30%	42	25	43	53	15 ..	21
	40%	40	20	44	54	16	27
- -	100%	23
--
-		52		24	
	10%	60	_
40	33	48	6.8	12
	20%	55	39	37	48	8.0	13
SPS**	30%	57	46	36	45	7.7	9.7
	40%	55	37	37	49	8.2	13
.
	100%	44		47		9.9	
Table III
Cut Filler Sieve Anal ses



*Cut rolled expanded stems
* *Shredded cut puffed (DIET) stems
Analyses of the data in Table III by Walt Morgan have lead to the following observations
regarding statistical significance of the data in this table:
5

pgNbr=7
A. simple way to examine these blends then is to divide the value for after-making longs by
the value for the before-making longs at each inclusion level and to plot these values against the
inclusion level. If the impact of the maker on the longs in the two types of tobacco, control and
processed tobacco, is identical, then a constant value should result, i.e., a plot of zero slope. A
positive slope for this plot would indicate the longs in the control blend are preferentially degraded (a
positive survival rate for the processed tobacco component), and a negative slope would indicate the
longs in the processed tobacco component are preferentially degraded (a negative survival rate for
the processed tobacco component.). Such plots have been carried out for the four types of processed
tobaccos and their blends with the control and are shown in Figure 3-6. For all but the CRES
Figure 3.
G7 Longs Survival Rate
1
0.8
0
Ratio
......... ....................... ...... ........... ......................
- .. ............. _ .... ........................... ---- x --- ---K------
0.6
0.4
0.2
0 10 20 30 40 50
% Inclusion
-x-After-Making to Before-Making Ratio
Figure 4.
G19 Loqgs Survival Rate
1
Ratio
0.8
x
0.6
0.4
0.2
x
............. ............. _......... ............. .......... .............. ...... ..................................
.. ...... .......... ......... ... .....__ ._.._............ ..._..._....... ......... _.......................__......_....._............. ..........
.............._............ _.._................................................ ..................... ............................... ....... ...
0L
0
10
20 30 40 50
% Inclusion
+=After-Making to Before-Making Longs Ratio
9

pgNbr=8
processed tobaccos used in this study were G7 prepared with the G7-1 formulation on the
Fourdrinier line at shed 181 and cut at a width of 16 cuts per inch and a length of 1.0 inch, G19-1
and CRES (conditioned, rolled, cut at 160 cpi. and expanded stems). In addition, cut puffed stems
(prepared by conditioning, cutting at 93 cuts per inch, drying to 20-25% moisture, and DIET-
ea7)anding at Tobaccoville), that were shredded through a Winsmith 920 shredder were also tested;
this stein sample will be referred to as SPS in this report. Appropriate mixtures of finished tobacco
blends were then carefully prepared by combining mixed and weighed portions of the control cut
filler blend with mixed and weighed portions of the four types of processed tobaccos to obtain final
blends containing between 10 and 40% of the processed tobaccos. Cigarettes were made from each
of the blends, including the control blend, on the Hauni pilot maker in the Cigarette Fabrication
Laboratory. All were made to a 69-mm rod length, unfiltered, with Standard Grade 454 (item ID
004-4890) cigarette paper. Weights, firYmiesses, circumferences and drafts were measured on the
finished products. Table 11 contains the summary information from these measurements.
Blend	
_
% inclusion	
Weight, gms	
Cjtrcuniiere~aee,	I~rimess	Draft, mnl
		((orrected
for	
~
wl	(Corrected for	
		drcundorence &amp;		dreuntferol-co	
~_--~		
~ tirntness &gt;'	~	moisturb	
Control	
N/A	
1.032	24.67	10.34	45.3
	10	1.014	24.81	8.91	69.2
G7•-l	20	1.044	24.68	11.86	52.5
	30	1.072	24.66	9.55	65.6
	40	1.077	24.73	10.89	57.0
	10	0.962	24.74	9.25	76.0
G 19-1	20	0.889	24.70	9.42	96.2
	30	0.913	24.67	8.64	120.4
	40	0.829	24.75	9.34	103.0
	10	0.945	24.81	7.57	34.8
CRES*	20	0.991	24.77	9.74	36.7
	30	0.942	24.69	9.24	38.7
	40	0.949	24.76	9.29	39.1
	10	1.024	24.75	11.80	36.2
SPS**	20	0.862	24.73	9.65	35.9
	30	0.937	24.78	11.64	97.2
	40	0.839	24.72	9.37	107.1
*Cut rolled expanded stems (] 60 cpi)
**Shredded cut puffed (DIET) stems (93 cpi)
Samples were collected ofthe "before making" and "after making" cut filler for each of the
test parls shown in Table 11. In the latter case, cigarettes were slit and the tobacco removed. Each
of these samples were then sieved on a Tyler Model B Ro-Tap (Combustion Engineering, Inc.) using
a set of 5 screens ranging from Tyler 6 mesh to Tyler 28 mesh. The fractions collected on each sieve
screen were weighed and these weights were used to determine the percentages of "longs" (%
Table II
Finished Ci~arette Characteristics




4

pgNbr=9
making were significant. The +6 mesh fraction of longs was the most severely reduced, in the worst
case being reduced by about. 90%. He also found that fines were increased, in the worst case about
100%. And although the changes in fines and longs were not as great as that found in our work, it is
important to note that he tested filler cut at 25 cpi (rather than 28 cpi) and used a water tongue for
Figure 1.
Before and After Makin Longs with G7
80.00
70.00
Moo
20.00
10.00
0.00
............ ..__...~:.-..
_........
_- ~
---+------+-
......~ .._...~ _ ~.-:-.- .._..._ .. ........... .......................__
0% G7 10% G7 20% G7 30% G7 40% G7 .100% G7
--"-- Before Making --~- After Making
T.....
12.00
Figure 2.
Before and After Making Fines with G7
10.00 ..... _............. ---- . ... ., . ......................... ... ......... _ ......
s.oo ................_..........,.. -

A.
M 6.00 1.....__._...._ ............._......_........._...__...
0
2.00 -1
0.00t
0% G7 10% G7 20% G7 30% G7
LiIIIIIIIiI'IIIII
After Maki
ng
40% G7
A
100% G7
7

pgNbr=10
temporary line at Shed 113. This new CRES could certainly be tested under the same test protocol
to verify that the improvements are realized through the maker.
Although limited data were obtained on fmished cigarette characteristics other than particle
size, Gl9 and SPS were found to contribute in a positive manner to filling values and weight
reductions in the finished cigarettes, whereas, G7 (Fourdrinier-produced) and CRES contributed
little in either a positive or a negative manner.
It is recommended from this work and earlier studies cited in this report, that careful
attention be given to the integrity of our processed tobaccos and the extent to which they may be
degraded by the making process. An increase in longs and a decrease in fines in the finished products
should result in a blend with increased filling values and may generate cost savings through the .
resulting changes in the quantities of the strip tobaccos in the blend. In any event, a more detailed
study should be conducted on the high speed makers in Manufacturing to determine the validity of
these findings.


William L. Cla


Edward J. (Steve) Solm
-~-V 4'~~Y nl -
Curti~s!_`GD. McGee
Accepted:
Approved:
Approved:
0
Julio
AM
r
/
~ gela V. Ridings
Ha ey . o-l/
Date: ~ ' 1  ~" - '77
Dat.e: '4 - ;2 &amp;-- /1114
Date: 3-' -~
16

pgNbr=11
l. Before-making longs decreased significantly with inclusion rate for G19, CRES and SPS,
while the increase observed for G7 was not significant. Differences between the product sets
depended upon whether the 100% value was included (the complete data set) or not (the
"restricted" data set). With the complete set, the declines with CRES and G19 were both
significantly greater than SPS; but with the restricted data set, CRES showed significantly
greater declines than either 619 or SPS, which were not different.
2. Before-making fines increased significantly with inclusion rate for G19, CRES and SPS,
while 67 was not significant. As with longs, when the complete data set was used, the
increases in fines were greater for CRES and G19 than for SPS; but with the restricted data
set, CRES increased significantly more than either G19 or SPS.
3. After-making longs decreased significantly with increasing inclusion rate for G19 and CRES
and increased significantly for G7, while changes for SPS were not significant. The longs
decrease was greater for CRES than for any of the other products, and G19 was not
significantly different from SPS.
4. Afler-mAking fines increased significantly with increasing inclusion rate for G19, CRES and
SPS, while the changes for G7 were not significant. The increase for CRES was significantly
higher than for G19 and SPS, and the increase for G7 was significantly less than the other
three products.
5. Changes ui longs (i, e., the difference in before and after-making longs) were not significant
for any of the materials, and none were different from each other.
6. Changes in fines increased significantly for CRES but were not significant for the other
inaterials. (It was noted that the change in fines found at the 40% inclusion level (a 11%
increase) are driving this finding and that at levels below 30%, this may not be correct.)
Strand Survival Through the Maker
Figures 1 and 2 show graphically the impact of cigarette making on longs and fines in blends
containing G7 from the data in Table III. (It is important to note here that the type of G7 used in
this study was stronger than G7 currently manufactured at 603. Additionally, it should be
understood that the width and length were previously optimized at 1/16" by 1".) Since the G7 used
in this case was of similar longs and fines distribution as the control cut filler blend, the effects on
longs and fines from blending alone are minimal. The survival of the G7 strands through the maker
shows a similar trend to that observed with the control cut filler blend, and in fact, of the slopes of
the lines in Figures 1&amp; 2, only the slope of the after-making longs line is statistically different from
zero. As such, it is difficult to visualize exactly the impact of the making operation on either the
longs or the fines in these particular blends.
In a study carried out in early 1990, Calleson (PD91-004) examined the effect of the maker N
on strand length distribution and found that particle size reductions from before making to after w
~
cn
N
J
6 ~

pgNbr=12
cooling the Protos unit. Either of these changes would be expected to reduce the degradation at the
maker. Irurthei7nore, there may be some fundamental differences in the way filler is acted upon by
the Hauni pilot maker and the Protos unit.
To understand the effects of any cigarette maker on the tobacco strand lengths in cigarettes
made with variable levels of the processed tobaccos, it is necessary to look at the tobacco strands in
the tobacco samples, both before and after making, as a function of the starting blend. If the
cigarette maker were to act equally on all components of the blend, then the longs in the tobacco
after making should be affected/reduced in proportion to the longs contributions of the individual
components. As a consequence, the composition of the longs in the blend after making should be
exactly the same as the composition of the longs in the blend before making. The same would also
apply to the middlings and the fines.
Plots then of the before-making longs and after-making longs versus the blend composition
would follow equations (l) and (2), respectively, where Lsb equals the longs content of the tobacco
sample at a particular processed tobacco inclusion level before making; Lsa equals the longs content
of the tobacco sample at a particular processed tobacco after making; I is the inclusion level of the
processed tobacco in the blend; and L,b and L, are the longs contents of the control cut filler
portion of the blend before and after making, respectively.
(1) I-sb = mbI + Lcb
(2) I-sa '= nial + Loa
Such plots would yield straight lines with slopes, ma and mb, dependent upon whether the
processed tobacco had more longs than the control cut filler blend (a positive slope) or less longs
than the control cut filler blend (a negative slope). The ratio of values at any inclusion point on these
two lines (after-makuig longs to before-making longs) would be equal to 1.0 only if the maker had
no effect on the longs content of the blend, i.e., the after-making longs were equal-to the before-
making longs. Therefore, the amount the ratio drops below 1.0 is indicative of how much the longs
are reduced through the maker.
Ifthe impact of the maker on both the control cut filler portion of the blend and the
processed tobacco portion of the blend is the same, then the slopes for both equations (1) and (2)
will be identical. Or put another way, if the slopes for equations (1) and (2) are found to be different,
then this difference is an indication that the maker acts differently on the two components (cut filler
and processed tobacco) of the blend. A more positive slope for equation (1) than for equation (2) is
an indication that the longs in the control blend survive the maker better than the longs in the
processed tobacco. Conversely, a more positive slope for equation (2) than equation (1) indicates
the longs in the processed tobacco survive the maker better than the longs in the control blend.
8

pgNbr=13
..
RJR Confidential
PD REPORT
AUTHORS: William L. Clapp DATE: February 11, 1994
Curtis D. McGee
Julio A. Munoz
Lila H. O'Connor
Angela V. Ridings
Steve Sohn
Harvey J. Young
DEPARTMENT: Product Development NOTEBOOK PAGES: None
DIVISION: Blends &amp; Process Tobacco Technology NO. OF PAGES: 28
PROGRAM NC).: 0332 REPORT NO.: PD 94-042
PREVIOUS REPORTS: PD 93-292
PD 93-348
The Effect of Cigarette Making on Tobacco Blends Containing Processed Tobaccos
.
OBJECTIVE: To measure the effects of the cigarette making operation on the strand length' distribution, burn rate and filling value of the tobacco in the finished cigarettes, and to assess the
relative importance of processed tobaccos used in the blends on these characteristics:
SUMMARY: A study has been completed which evaluates the impact of the cigarette maker on a
number of finished cigarette characteristics for a standard blend which contained variable levels of
four different types of processed tobaccos: G7 (prepared with the G7-1 formulation on the
Fourdrinier line at Shed 181), G19-1, CRES (cut rolled expanded flue-cured stems produced at
Shed 113), and SPS (stems which were conditioned, cut, sent through the DIET expansion process
and shredded). Finished cigarette characteristics were measured as the level of inclusion of each of
these processed tobaccos was varied from 0-40% of the cigarette blend. The impact of the maker
on the longs, middlings and fnes in the tobacco blends and filling values of the blends was assessed
by measuring them before and after the maker.
G7, G19 and SPS were found to survive the maker without a significant adverse effect (a
lowering) on longs when compared to the standard cut filler blend. CRES was found to have a
negative impact on longs, resulting in a disproportionate reduction in the finished cigarette longs

pgNbr=14
INTRODUCTION:
A comparison of the cigarettes made by Philip Morris, Inc., with those made by RJR has been
made ("Analysis of PM's Generic Products Relative to Similar RJR Products", Interoffice
Memorandum, H. J. Young to G. T. Burger, July 22, 1993). One conclusion from this study was
that, if the ratio of "longs" to °middlings" or "fines" in the finished products could be maintained at a
higher level than currently found, it might be possible to make cigarettes without using expanded
tobacco at weights comparable to those found in cigarettes incorporating expanded tobacco (PD
Report 93-348). The importance of this finding is that there are significant costs associated with all
tobacco expansion processes which might be avoided if acceptable cigarettes can be made at the low
weights normally found in cigarettes with high expanded tobacco inclusion levels, but without the
use of expanded tobacco. To understand how increasing the longs-to-fines ratio could be
accomplished, it was first necessary to develop an understanding of the impact of the making
operation on strand lengths for each of the blend.components found in cigarettes, i.e., a "survival
rate" through the maker for each of these components.
Work completed earlier this year was directed towards understanding and quantifying the
survival rates (the ability to go through the maker without excessive degradation) for Fourdrinier-
produced G7 of varying lengths and widths through the cigarette making operation. From this work,
optimal cut widths of between 16 and 32 cuts per inch and lengths of approximately 0.50 to 1.0 inch
were found and reported (PD 93-348). For strands in these length and width ranges, G7 produced
on the Fourdrinier line at Shed 181 was found to survive the making operation without a significant
increase in the amount of fines produced. The purpose of the current study was to assess in a similar
manner the survival rates versus inclusion levels for optimally cut G7 and other types of processed
tobaccos, specif cally G19 and several types of cut puffed stems, through the cigarette maker and to
compare their survival rates with a standard strip blend.
EXPERIIM ENTAL:
Finished blended strip (1000 lbs.) of the composition shown in Table I below was prepared and cut at 28 cuts per inch; this will be referred to as the control cut filler blend. The
Table I.
Strip Filler Blend
Co»oone .n..t Iil -
~..~	1)1 y V4'..cigltt, %
.. +.,...,~. _
KG1	5.9
KG2	16.5
_ KG-0	7.1
CGI	16.2
CCJ 1-0	12.7
CG3	41.6

pgNbr=15
Table I
Slohes and__ Tests for Slopes=0
		Slopes G7	G19	CRES SPS	G7	G19	CRES SPS
Measure		piffer Slone Slohe Slope Slope p	k	k	P
					
Before	Longs	.0001	.043	-.365	-.457	-.216	.36	.0001	.0001	.0002
Making	Mids	.0001	-.008	.199	.243	.168	.78	.0001	.0001	.0001
	Fines	.0001	-.035	.171	.206	.057	.08	.0001	.0001	.0070
	Fill Value	.0001	.483	.11	.50	1.97	.26	.0001	.0223	.0003
Before	Longs	.0001	.133	-.337	-.634	-.291	.17	.0032	.0001	.0082
Making	Mids	.0001	-.075	.159	.349	.189	.21	.0148	.0001	.0055
(x 100%)	Fines	.0001	-.056	.165	.286	.108	.14	.0006	.0001	.0104
After	Longs	.0001	.212	-.192	-.602	-.135	.0161	.0260	.0001	.10
Making	Mids	.0001	-.156	.011	.208	.041	.0049	.81	.0006	.38
	Fines	.0001	-. 067	.162	.400	.084	.10	.0011	.0001	.0478
	Fill Value	.0001	.383	.56	.37	1.94	.13	.0001	.13	.0001
Change	Longs	.38	.079	.145	.032	.155	.32	.08	.68	.06
During	Mids	.44	-.081	-.148	-.141	-.148	.10	.0071	.0093	.0071
Making	Fines	.0162	-.011	-.003	.114	-.025	.79	.95	.0127	.54
	Fill Value	.77	.002	.559	.159	.082	.99	.34	.78	.89
Weight		.0001	.0019	-.0043	-.0017	-.0039	.07	.0006	.08	.0012
Circum.		.70	-.0011	-.0009	.0002	.0001	.40	.52	.90	.96
Firmness		.33	.023	-.022	-.020	.018	.46	.47	.50	.55
Draft		.0018	.53	2.01	-.20	1.30	.24	.0006	.66	.0109
Ruturate		.0003	.19	-.01	.28	.19	.0012	.75	.0001	.0011
Puffs		.0109	-.016	-.051	-.048 '	-.076	.27	.0033	.0047	.0002
23

pgNbr=16
tobaccos are an important factors to consider when adding these components to tobacco blends at
higb levels.
Parf.s	Burn Rntc	Puffs	TPM nig/cig.	Nicotine	TarfPufl'
_	ni /ni.u..a	~i0.		/Cl •	
Control	51.22	9.8__	29.5	2.49	2.51
10ONO G7	50.45	9.6	26.3	2.04	2.26
20°io G7	58.38	8.4	28.1	1.99	2.75
30°io G7	54.67	9.5	23.3	1.5	2.06
400/o07	59.62	8.6	24.5	1.7	2.40
10% G 19	51.00	__
8.9	27.3	2.05	2.52
20%G19	51.94	8.0	23.3	1.66	2.41
30% G19	50.32	8.4	21.7	1.48	2.14
40% G19	50.64	7.2	22.2	1.45	2.48
10% CRES	51.93	9.7	29.1	2.32	2.50
20% CRES	56.64	8.5	23.8	1.76	2.32
30% CRES	60.18	7.8	21.3.	1.37	2.29.
40% CRES	62.51	7.4	20.1	1.20	2.26
1 0%, SPS	55.32	8.0	25.3	2.05	2.56
20% SPS	56.58	7.2	21.8	1.51	.2.51
30%. SPS	56.96	6.9	18.1	1.14	2.16
400/0 SPS	57.76	7.1	16.8	1.04	1.95
CONCLUSIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS
A study has been completed which evaluates the impact of the cigarette maker on a number
of finished cigarette characteristics for a standard blend which contained variable levels of 4 different
types of processed tobaccos: 67 (prepared with the G7-1 formulation on the Fourdrinier line at shed
181), G19-1, CRES (cut rolled expanded flue-cured steins), and SPS (stems which were
conditioned, cut, sent through the DIET expansion processand shredded). Finished cigarette
cliaracteristics were measured as the level of inclusion of each of these processed tobaccos was
varied from 0-40% of the cigarette blend. The impact of the maker on the longs, middlings and fines
in the tobacco blends and filling values of the blends was assessed by measuring them before and
after the maker.
67, G19 and SPS were found to survive the maker without a significant adverse effect (a
lowering) on longs when compared to the standard cut fillet blend. CRES was found to have a
negative inypact on longs, resulting in a disproportionate reduction in the finished cigarette longs and
the highest level of fines. However, CRES material. which will be produced on the new line at
Tobaccoville is expected to be a much improved product over this which was produced on the
Table VII.
Smoke Analyses
15

pgNbr=17
Figure 5.
CRF,S LIongs Survival Rate
0.6
0
Ratio
1 r----- -----
0.8
--.... _
~ _. . .... ....__....._ ___.......X
x
0.4
0.2
0 10 ~ 20 '- 30
% Inclusion
-X-After-Making to Before-Making Ratio
Figure 6.
SPS Longs Survival Rate
1
0.8
0.6
Ratio
40 50
........... ............. .... ........ ...............X.............. ......._.... .. ...... _.__.......,....._.._................ .........
--~:-._.-
x
............... ..... ..... ......... ......................... ......... ._.............. ............................... ....................
0.4
0.2
0 10 20 30 40 50
% Inclusion
4E-After-Making to Before-Making Ratio
0
samples the slopes of these lines show a positive trend. This indicates a survival rate similar to the .
cut filler portion of the blend. And although the longs decreased significantly for G19 and SPS, the
decrease is no more than would be expected from the level of inclusion in the blend.
Table IV gives the slopes for each of the lines in Figures 3-6 along with the intercept values,
correlation coefficients and P-values at the 95% confidence level. (Appendix II contains the
complete statistical analyses for survival rate determinations.) While the slope is an indicator of
10

pgNbr=18
weights had to be maintained at a somewhat constant level, and in the case of CRES, a slightly more
firm cigarette was produced at a fairly uniform weight and draft. These data then confirm the
conclusions reached from longs and filling values and suggest that G19 and SPS offer opportunities
for weight reductions at fixed firninesses, while G7 and CItES are comparable in their impact on final
cigarette weights and filling values, contributing little in a positive manner.
Table VI contains the results of analyses of the various tobacco blends tested. The percent
nicotine decreased with the incremental addition of processed tobaccos to the control blend. The
total sugars are not affected by the incremental increase of processed tobaccos but they are effected
by the specific processed t;obacco added, i.e., % total sugars for CRES &gt;SPS&gt;G7= G19. The
moistures for all blends were in the 11.5 to 12.7% range, with the lowest moisture equilibration
values being found for samples containing the two highly expanded tobacco types (G19 and SPS).
Parts	% M.oistuure	% Nicotioc	°fo' Rc.c.i, Sxt gars	% To.t._,Su ars '
C.ontrol	12.00	_ 2.76	7.9	8.6
10% G7	12.76	2.50	6.7	7.5
20% G7	12.58	2.43	6.7	7.9
30% G7	12.51	2.20	6.4	7.3
40%_G7	12.42
-	2.06	7.1	7.7
10% G 19	12.72	-- 2.62	7.4	8.2
20% G19	12.27	2.46	5.9	7.0
30% G19	11.79	2.45	6.7	8.0
40% G19_	11.49 _	2.30
i	5.9	6.7
10°,/o CRES	11.60	2.66	9.6	9.9
20°,/o CRES	11.92	2.43	8.8	9.6
30% CRES	11.62	2.13	8.3	9.8
40% CRES	12.45	_
1.89	8.4	9.9
10% SPS	11.56	_
2.56	_
8.0	9.0
20% SPS	11.50	2.37	8.4	9.7
30% SPS	11.66	2.13	7.7	8.8
40% SPS	11.79	1.94	8.3	9.2
Table VII give the results of the smoke analyses on cigarettes prepared from each of the -
tobacco blends used in the test. The burn rate increased with each incremental addition of G7 and
CRES but remained constant with the increased addition of G19 and SPS. The puff count, smoke
nicotine and total particulate material (TPM) analyses showed a decreasing trend with an increase in
the processed tobaccos. Although it was not the purpose of this test to address specifically the issues
of burn rate and puff count, in general the trend of decreased puff count with increased burn rate was
noted. Reductions in puff count or increases in burn rate with increased inclusion levels of processed
Table VI.
Tobacco Anal ~s~ es on Test Blends
14

pgNbr=19
slope afler making than before making, therefore less sensitivity), but increased generation of fines
with CRES. This raises questions about using this material at anything but low levels.
Filling-Value
• Significant increases in before mak i~ filli~~ value were observed for G19, CRES, and SPS.
(Note that 100% measure is available only for CRES, providing much greater sensitivity than for
the other components). The slope for G19 was greater than any of the others, and the slope for
SPS was greater than that of CRES and G7, which were not different.
• Significant increases in after makin fiIling vAlue were observed for G19 and SPS. The slope for
Gl9 was greater than any of the others, and the slope for SPS was greater than that of CRES and
G7, which were not different.
• No significant effects of inclusion levels on change in fiWng value were found for any of the
materials. This is saying that the before and after making slopes are not significantly different. .
However, note (from Figure 12) the result at 40% G19, which shows very little change in filling
value (due to the low value before making). The other points suggest a reduction in change (i.e.,
greater sensitivity to inclusion level before making than after making) for G19.
Overall, while after making values were less than before making values, the relationship between
filling value and inclusion level did not change significantly through the making process.
Other Measures
• Weia;ht: decreased with increasing inclusion levels of G19.and SPS but was not significant for G7
or Cl~'sS. This was related to the increased filling values observed for these materials. The
slopes for G19 and SPS were not different from each other, but were both different from those of
G7 and CRES. The slope for G7 was positive (increasing weight with increasing level) and was
significantly greater than that of CRES, which was negative (decreasing weight with increasing
level).
Slopes for circumference and firmness were not significant for any of the materials.
• Draft increased significantly with inclusion level for G19 and SPS but was not significant for G7
or CRFS. The slope for 619 was greater than those of G7 and CRES, and the slope for SPS
was greater than that of CRES.
• Burn rate increased significantly with inclusion level for G7, CRES, and SPS. The slope for G19
was less than those of the other three materials, which were not different from each other.
• Puffs decreased significantly with inclusion level for G19, CRES, and SPS. The slope for G7
was less than those of the other three materials, which were not different from each other.
1) l

pgNbr=20
SUMMARY OUTPUT
_ ftression Statistics __
Multiple R 0.944002419
R Square 0.891140566
Adjusted R Square 0.854854088
Standard Error 0.026529084
Observations 5

ANOVA
CRES Longs
SS MS F SiQnif cance F
Regression 1 0.017284066 0.017284 24.55848 0.015772693
Residual 3 0.002111377 0.000704
Total 4 0.019395443
	Coe rcients	Standard Error	t Stat P-value Lower 95%	Upper 95%
Intercept	0.6906226	0.02054934	33.60802 5.79E-05 0.625225366	0.756019834
% Inclusion	-0.00415741	0.000838923	-4.95565 0.015773 -0.006827242	-0.00148758
SUMMARY OUTPUT		SPS Longs		
Re ression Statistics				

Multiple R	_
0.369802166				
R Square	0.136753642				
Adjusted R Square	-0.150995144				
Standard Error	0.062875799				
Observations	5				
ANOVA					
		SS _	MS	F	Significance F
Regression	1	0.001878851	0.001878851	0.475253585	0.540116593
Residual	3	0.011860098	0.003953366		
Total	4	0.01373895			
_ _	Coe ficients	Standard Error	t Stat	P-value	Lower 95%	Upper 95%
Intercept	0.68199698	0.048703384	14.00307169	0.00078865	0.52700093	0.83699303
% Inclusion	0.001370712	0.001988307	0.689386383	0.540116593.	-0.004956975	0.007698399
V1
N
26 W
W

pgNbr=21
survival rate, the intercept gives the survival rate with no processed tobacco for each test part. From
this table, the relatively high negative correlation coefficient for CRES, combined with the negative
slope oft.he line in Figure 6, is a strong indicator that the maker is causing an inordinate amount of
breakdown in the longs in the tobacco. No such trends occur with the other three types of processed
tobaccos.
Pi occssed Touacco	Sw vbval Rate	Intercept	Corrbaation	p-Value


----	3)
~10
~~)C x 10-		

Coefficient	

95% Contldence

G7	
0.760	0.718	0.353	0.560

G19	
1.85	0.655	0.805	0.100

CRF S	
-4.l 6	0.691	-0.944	0.016

SPS
- -	
1.37
_~	0.682	0.370	0.540
The values for the slopes in Table IV indicate that the blends containing G7, G19 and SPS
might be expected to contain somewhat more longs after.making than would be anticipated from the
blend alone, although statistically these slopes, with P-valuesin excess of 0.05 are not significant at
the 95% confidence level. That the survival rate decrease for CRES has a P-value of less than 0.05
indicates tliat. the drop in after-making longs relative to the before-making longs is significant and
further that the negative slope of this line is also significant.
Finally, since fines are produced during the making operation, it would be meaningless to .
calculate a "survivalrate" for fines. Instead the data were examined for significance in the increase
of fines for both the before-making and after-making samples. Statistically there were significant
increases in before-making fines for GI 9, CRES and SPS. This was to be expected from the blending
step since all of these processed tobaccos had high initial levels of fines. Both CRES and G19 had
significantly greater fines in the before-making samples than SPS, but both also had significantly
greater fines in the 100% processed tobacco samples (-24% vs. 10%). However, after making, the
fines increase for CRES was signilicantly greater than for G19 or SPS, and all three were
significantly greater than for the Fourdrinier-produced G7. Moreover, the change in the fines from
before-making to after-making increased significantly for CRES but not for any of the other
materials, indicating that the maker may actually be producing fines from CRES. .
Filling Values
Filling value determinations for each of the test parts both before and after making are shown
in Table 0/ below. The last two columns show the filling values as corrected to 12.5% moisture.
The average value found for the control blend before making was 473 cc/100g and after making was
408 cc/100g. This constitutes a drop of approximately 14% in filling value through the maker.
Statistically significant increases in before-making filling values were found for .G19, CRES and SPS.
The slope for G19 was greatest and was significantly higher than any of the others. SPS was greater
Table IV
I°ngsSurvival Rates for Processed Tobaccos



11

pgNbr=22
Appendix I
Statistical Treatment of Data
RJR INTEROFFICE MEMORAND UM
To: Dr. W. L. C:lapp ])ate: January 20, 1994
From: Mr. W. T. Morgan
Effects of Cigarette Making on Tobacco Blends Containing Processed Tobaccos
Summary:
Vaiying levels of processed tobacco products (G7, G19, CRES, and SPS) were added to a base
blend. Particle size and filling value measurements were taken before and after making, and some
additional cigarette parameters were measured. Results showed
• Particle size distribution after making improved with increasing levels of G7 (more longs, fewer
mids), but woisened with increasing levels of the other three materials before and after making .
(fewer longs and more mids and fines), especially for CRES.
• Change in longs during making was not significant (the reduction in longs did not depend on
inclusion level) for any of the materials. Change in mids during the making process decreased
with inclusion level for G19, CRI:S, and SPS, since the slope before making was greater than
that after making, so that the maker is acting as an "equalizer" in this sense. Change of fines
during the making process increased for CRES, indicating increased generation of fines with
inclusion level. Overall, high levels of CRES appear undesirable from a particle size perspective.
• Before making filling value increased with inclusion level for G19, CRES, and SPS, while after
making filling capacity increased witb inclusion level only for G19 and SPS. Change in filling
capacity during making did not change significantly with inclusion level.
• Cigarette weight decreased and draft increased significautly with increasing inclusion level for
Gl9 and SPS but did not change significantly for G7 or CRES. Circumference and firmness
linear effects were not significant for any of the materials.
• Bum rate increased and number of puffs decreased with increasing inclusion level for G19, CRES
and SPS.
Overall, increasing the level of G7 had no detrimental eflect on finished cigarette properties observed
here relative to the control blend. Increasing levels of G19, CRES, and SPS resulted in worsening
particle size distribution than the control blend, while Gl9 and SPS resulted in improved filling
capacity, reduced weight and increased draft. G19, CRES, and SPS also resulted in increased bum
rate and reduced puff count.
18

pgNbr=23
• Overall, increasina levels of G19, CRES and SPS resulted in before makina particle size
degradation _relAtive to the control blend witli decreased longs and increased mids and fines
(Wova for CRES , while tlie Particle size distribution~ not chanae significantly with G7
inclusion rate.
• Afler rriaking longs decreased significantly with increasing inclusion rate for Gl 9 and CRES and
increased significantly for G7, while the slope for SPS was not significant. T'he slope for G7 was
different from those of the other 3 materials, while the slope for CRES was greater (in
magnitude) than for GI 9 or SPS, which were not different.
• After rriaking mids increased significantly with increasing inclusion rate for CRES, and decreased
significantly with inclusion rate for G7, while slopes for G19 and SPS were not significant. The
G7 slope was significantly different from those of the other three materials, and the CRES slope
was greater than those of G19 and SPS.
• After making fines increased significantly with increasing inclusion rate for G19, CRES, and SPS,
while the slope for G7 was not significant. The G7 slope was significantly different from those of
the ot:her three materials, and the CRES slope was greater than those of G19 and SPS, which
were not different.
• Overall, increasing levels of G19, CRES and SPS resulted in after makingparticle size
de~radation relative to the control blend with decreased longs and increased mids and fines
worst for CRES while the Particle size distribution actually imnroved with increasing G7
inclusioi&gt; (greater longs and fewer mids).
• Change_in_lorags was not significant for any of the materials, and none were different from each
other. The graph shows an upward trend for some materials, but it is not significant based on the
data here.
• Chanae_in mids decreased significantly for G19, CRES, and SPS. This is saying that the slope
before making was greater than the slope after making for these materials (i.e., the maker acts as
an "equalizer" to some extent). While the slope for G7 was not significant, it was in the same
direction as the others so that none of these slopes are different from each other.
• Chanae in fines increased significantly for CRES and was not significant for the other materials.
This was because the slope before making is less than the slope after making for CRES (i.e., the
maker increases the fines for this material). It should be noted from Figure 9 that the l 1%
increase in fines before and after making observed at the 40% inclusion rate were driving this
result, which may not be correct at levels below 30%. Accordingly the slope for CRES was
different from those of the other three materials, which were not different from each other.
Overall, these particle size data showed some improvement in longs with increasing G7 levels after
making, while particle size distribution suffered with increased levels of the other materials (reduced
longs and. increased.mids and fines). CRES showed the greatest degradation with increased level.
The making process seemed to reduce the effect of varying inclusion levels on mids increase (smaller
20

pgNbr=24
SUMMARY OUTPUT		G7 Fines				
Regression Statistics				
Multiple R	0.745385688					
R Square	0.555599824					
Adjusted R Square	0.407466432					
Standard Error	1.213626035					
Observations	5					
ANOVA						
	df	SS	11IS	F	Significance F	
Regression	1	5.524320941	5.524321	3.750672	0.14819494	
Residual	3	4.418664461	1.472888			
Total	4	9.942985402				
						
	Coef icients	Standard Error	t Stat	P-value	Lower 95%	Upper 95%
Intercept	1.132908948	0.940070685	1.205132	0.314545	-1.858818336	4.124636232
% Inclusion	0.074325776	0.038378225	1.936665	0.148195	-0.047810979	0.196462531
SUMMARY OUTPUT
Regression Statistics
Multiple R	0.815381634
R Square	0.66484721
Adjusted R Square	0.553129613
Standard Error	0.278511489
Observations	5
ANOVA	
	df
Regression	l
Residual	3
Total	4
	
	Coefflcients
Intercept	2.21478792
% Inclusion	-0.02148539
G19 Fines
SS MS F Significance F
0.461621998 0.461622 5.951141 0.092541834
0.232705949 0.077569
0.694327947
Standard Error t Stat P-value Lower 95% Upper 95%
0.215734072 10.26629 0.001971 1.528225176 2.901350664
0.008807307 -2.4395 0.092542 -0.049514197 0.006543416
27

pgNbr=25
Introduction
I have reviewed the data you provided concerning tobacco blend and cigarette particle size, filling
value, and some additional cigarette parameters, for blends using various inclusion rates of G7, G19,
CRES, and SPS. Before and after making results were used to characterize the effect of the making
process on blend particle size and filling value.
Statistical Analysis
Since the blends evaluated were mixes of.a.base blend Mth varying levels (10%, 20%, 30%, 40%,
and sometimes 100%) of each of the four processed tobacco products (G7, GI 9, CRES, and SPS),
analysis consisted of testing for significant linear effect of inclusion level of each material. Slopes for
each material were estimated (including the 0% level control product for each line) and tested for
significance (i.e., different from 0), and then compared to each other on a pairwise basis. Tables I
and II present slope estimates and p-values for significance tests. P-values of.05 were considered
significantl,y.different, so that p-values in this table of 0.05 or less were judged significant. Figures 1-
l 8 display the results graphically.
Particle Size
Particle size was evaluated by looking at results before making, after making, and the increase
observed during making for each processed tobacco product. Before making particle size was
analyzed based on all the data (including the 100% blends), and then repeated for only the 0-40%
blends, since it may not be reasonable to assume that a straight line describes the behavior of the
system over the entire 0-100% range. Results showed that
• I3efore makinglo_ W decreased significantly with increasing inclusion rate for G19, CRES, and
SPS, while G7 showed increasing behavior, which was not significant. Accordingly, the slope for
G7 differed significantly from those of the other three materials, for which CRES showed the
s1iarIrest decline, followed by G19 and SPS. Differences between these three products varied
depending on whether the 100% values were included, with CRES and G19 both significantly
larger (in magnitude) than SPS but not different from each other when all data were included,
while CRES was larger in magnitude than G19 and SPS, which were not different from each
other, for the restricted data set.
Before making_mids increased significantly with inclusion rate for G19, CRES, and SPS while the
G7 slope was not significant. The G7 slope was sigiufioantly different from the other three, with
the greatest slope for CRES, significantly greater than that of SPS when all data were included,
and greater than both GI 9 and SPS for the restricted data set.
• Before makiugfines increased significantly with inclusion rate for G19, CRES, and SPS, while
the G7 slope was not significant. Again, the G7 slope was different from the other three, with
the greatest slope for CRES and G19, both greater than that of SPS for the complete data set,
while the CRES slope was greater than those of both G19 and SPS for the restricted data set.
19

pgNbr=26
than CRES, which was not significantly different from G7. Significant increases in after-making
filling values were found for both G19 and SPS; CRES and G7 were not different.

Part	~~ % Moisture	klitli~~ VolrIn)c'~~ ~	
Corrected pShia Volunne ''
_	
~'rc-h7Akcr	
Po.st Mztkcr _	~^
Prc-lllstkGr	Post-Maker	Prc-Maker	Post-Maker '
Control	
12.97	
l 1.95	
459	425	473	408
10% GI	
13.17	
12.36	
460	427	482	423
20% G7	
14.02	
12.10	
451	434	499	422
30% G'/	
13.68	
12.32	
454	431	492	426
40% G'I	13.53	11.71	459	433	492	409
10% Gl9	13.78	12.43	_
478	443	_
521	441
20% G19	13.57	12.24	513	476	551	467
30% G19	14.36	12.21	540	521	610	510
40% G19	_ 12.18	12.07	578	575	565	558
10% CRES	12.79	12.01	466	431	475	416
20% CRES	12.66	11.31	474	447	479	410
30% CRES	12.84	10.92	489	459	501	408
40% CRtiS	11.97	11.72	504	455	485	430
100% CRES	_ 14.63	_	
464		533	

10% SPS	
12.70	
11.66	481	
447	
488	
421

20% SPS	
12.97	
11.59	498	
469	
514	
439

30% SPS	
12.78	
11.62	529	
491	
539	
461
40% SPS	12.42	11.'/9		518	559	492
* cc/100g
The impact of the maker on filling values is graphically shown in Figures 7 and 8. These data
clearly sliow that G19 and SPS contributed in a positive manner to the filling values both before and
after the maker, whereas. G7 and CRES contributed very little, if any, to either filling value; statistical
analysis supports this observation. The data also show that there is a consistent drop in filling values
going through the maker of between 12% and 14%, but statistically, this drop through the maker is
not affected by the inclusion level. However, the fact that both the longs and filling values decreased
as a result of the making operation suggests that a positive relationship may exist between strand
length and filling values. Finally, of the two types of puffed. stems tested, only the shredded DIET-
puffed stems (SPS) contributed to increases in filling values. The impact of CRES on filling value
was at best negligible.
From the cigarette data shown in Table II earlier in this report, the finished cigarette
characteristics are entirely consistent with the findings on longs, fines and filling values. As each
series were made on the cigarette maker, the instructions to the operator were to make as "good" a
cigarette as possible, allowing weight and firmness to float as necessary. The final results showed
that the best cigarettes which were made with Gl9 and SPS were done so if the weights were

Table V.
Fillin Value Determinations


12

pgNbr=27
			tIz				
80'	IF 98'	£I00'	Lt~tiO'	61£0'	6010'		spnd
60'	8000' 1000'	96'	80'	8000'	£000'		als.uung
17900'	£[' £000'	I['	Zi'	8500'	8100'		Ue.r(I
£Z'	IZ' 96'	68'	81'	91'	££'		ssauur.il~
b6'	617' Sb'	8£'	S£'	V8'	OL'		umo.il~
££V0'	89' 8610	1000'	bZ00'	1000'	1000'		3ll~~aM
06'	Z17' OS'	68'	6L'	S£'	LL'	an[gA Il?3	
9b00'	65' LZiO'	£L'	8800'	68'	Z910'	sau[3	!911131sw
68'	66' 68'	81'	ZZ'	81'	tiP'	sptW	Var.in(I
b['	06' LI'	b£'	9S'	[b'	8£'	sifacrl	aVuuit:)
1000'	1000' 1000'	1000'	66'	1000'	1000'	an[gA 11N	
1000'	L0' 1000'	ZZ00'	1000'	1000'	1000'	saai3	
L£00'	£S' 1100'	1100'	1000'	L£00'	1000'	spiW	VinKew
1000'	817' Z000'	8000'	1000'	Z000'	i 000'	siluo-I	.cajjy
V000'	S i' V900'	L000'	1000'	1000'	1000,	sanc3	(%00 [ X)
0910'	19' 1900'	9000'	1000'	5100'	1000,	spiW	!3urIM
££00'	£9' E800	L000'	1000	£000	1000'	s9uo-I	aJolag
8100'	6ZZ0' 1000'	V900'	L6'	1000'	I 000'	anlgA IllA	
1000'	1000' £1 '	8000'	1000'	1000'	1000'	sauca	
L9b0'	8£' £Z'	1000'	1000'	1000'	I 000'	spiW	vulAeN
5000'	9910' Z1 '	£000'	1000'	1000'	1000'	s&amp;uoZ	aJo1aH
SdS SdS S3Wa 	SdS S:RIO	610 Ja13KI		a.cnssaw
^ Sa2ID A 619 ^ 610	^ LJ ^ LJ	A LO sadoIS		
sacCols Io uosff9-cluz6-5
11 aiQs.L

pgNbr=28
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
