<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae31f00</tid>
<ti>Trip Report - BAT (Suisse) Switzerland Date Visited: 841210.</ti>
<dt>Trip Report</dt>
<dt>Report</dt>
<dd>19841219</dd>
<au>Harper-P;BW</au>
<rc>Hamerton-M;BW</rc>
<pc>Kohnhorst-E;Whitehair-T;Mason-W;Raphael-G;Macdonald-I;De Wolf-C;BW</pc>
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":H79 -->
<pg>4</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:0-->
<!-- Note:dl:19981123-->
<bt>620404723/4726</bt>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>NtERfVAL COWZDDONDENCE
December 19, 1984
TO:	Mr. M. 8amerton	
COPIES:	Mr.
Mr.
Mr.
Mr.
Mr.	E.
T.
W.
G.
I.	E.
E.
S.
D.
D.	Kohnhorst
Whitehair,
Mason
Raphael
Macdonald	
Jr.
Mr.	C.	De Wolf /Brussels
PROM: P. B. Harper
		TRIP REPORT-n BiT (SUISSE)	
		~ SWITZERLANU ,		
		Date Visitedd v Decembei 10,	198&lt;	-'
Discussions with:
Mr.
Mr.
Mr.
Mr.
Ms.	
W.
A.
J.
R.
H.	
Bizon
Cha[alambous
C. Chappuis
Bumair
Ibeg		
LOUISVILLE
1) BARCLAY - PRODUCT CHANGES
Prior to our visit, new blends for BARCLAY Ring Size and Deluxe, with
Corby DIET substituted for G-13, had been approved for implementation
early in 1985.
Subsequent to the decision to use these new blends, a court ruling in
Switzerland will now require B4T (Suisse) to print tar and nicotine
deliveries on BARCLAY packs as measured with the filter vents open (the
usual procedure) and blocked.
Blocked delivery figures, for products with the new blends containing
DIET are:
Tar NiC
Ring Size 11.0 1.0
Deluxe 13.0 1.1
EAT (Suisse) was of the opinion, and we agreed, that printed delivery
figures should be the same for both versions.
4253M/Pg.l
6ti11404'723
pgNbr=1
TRIP REPORT - SWITZERLAND
December 19, 1984
The following proposals were discussed during our meeting. Mr. Bizon
confirmed, in a subsequent phone conversation with me, that these
proposals were approved by Mr. Pritchard during meetings at BST
(Suisse) on December 14, 1984.
a) New delivery figures to be printed on both the Ning Size and
Deluxe versions will be:
Open Blocked
Tar 1.0 11.0
Nicotine 0.2 1.1
The packaging with these printed figures will be implemented in
production, approximately January 21, 1985 and will be on the
Swiss market in early February, 1985.
b) Deliveries of the King Size product using both the current
blend (with G-13) and the proposed new blend (with DIET) are in
line with the above figures.
It is felt that the blend and packaging for the King Size
product should not be changed at the same time. Therefore, BAT
(Suisse) will continue using the current blend, containing
G-13, until at least March, 1985.
c) The blocked tar delivery of the Deluxe version with both the
current blend and the proposed blend (with DIET) is 13 mg.
Thus, it will be necessary to change the blend to reduce the
blocked tar delivery to 11 mg. BAT (Suisse) had produced a
sample (NO.420) using a new blend which gave the desired
deliveries.
A comparison of this new blend to the current blend is shown
below:
		Current Blend	Sample 420
t Flue cured	38		24	
%	Burley	17		19	
\	Maryland	8		15	
Y	oriental	7		7	
\	ET	30	(G-13)	30	(DIET)
t Stem	0		5	
	100		100	
4253M/Pg.2
620404'724
pgNbr=2
TRIP REPORT - SWITZERLAND
December 19, 1984
We agreed with the BAT (Suisse) Leaf Department, that sample
420 has a slightly more satisfying taste than the current
product. The BAT (Suisse) Taste and Flavor Panel found no
difference between Sample 420 and the current product.
Thus, it was agreed that the blend used for sample 420 will be
adopted concurrent with the packaging change.
2) BARCLAY - SALES IN SWITZERLAND IN NOVEMBER, 1984
		S.O.M.
(U
King	size Box	4.1
King	size Soft Cup	0.6
Deluxe Box	0.6
		5.3
VOLUME
(Millions)
55.4
8.1
8.1
71.6
BARCLAY - MALAUCENE TIPPING WITS BURN RETARDANT
BAT (Suisse) had received samples of BARCLAY tipping (60 gm/m2) from
Malaucene with a Diammonium Phosphate additive. This tipping appeared
to significantly reduce coal fall-out when the cigarette is burned to
the tipping. BAT (Suisse) agreed to send me 10 200's cartons of
BARCLAY with this tipping. These samples will be submitted to RD&amp;E for
special coal retention testing.
4) USE OF DIET IN ALL BRANDS
SAT (Suisse) plans to incorporate Corby DIET in all their blends early
1. 1985. This is in accordance with their Company Plan for 1985.
The only brands they currently use ET in are BARCLAY, KENT special and
MARYLONG.
BAT (Suisse) has begun product trials using ET in the KENT Parent, PALL
MALL, and ROOL BLENDS.
Once they have acceptable products, they will send us samples for
evaluation by RD6E.
5) PRODUCT MONITORING IN 1985
The following program was agreed:
• BAT (Suisse) will send me their laboratory data on all B6W
brands once each month.
4753M/Pg.3
6.:0464"I25
pgNbr=3
TRIP REPORT - SWITZERLAND
December 19, 1984
• They will send 4 200's cartons each of BARCLAY King Size and
BARCLAY Deluxe to Dr. P. L. Aulbach once each month.
. They will send 4 200's cartons of each of the following brands
to Dr. P. L. Aulbach two times in 1985 (January and July):
Kent Bing Size
Eent Special
LUCKY STRIKE Plain
LUCKY STRIKE Ring Size Filter
PALL lRLL superlongs
ROOL
P. H. Harper
/enm
4253N/Pg.4
62m4002G
pgNbr=4
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
