<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aac76e00</tid>
<bt>2051124323</bt>
<dd>19930601</dd>
<dt>MEMO, MEMORANDUM</dt>
<au>MURPHY,V</au>
<rc>CUMMINGS,LM</rc>
<np>CUMMINGS,LM</np>
<ca>PM, PHILIP MORRIS</ca>
<cr>PM, PHILIP MORRIS</cr>
<!-- Note:pa1:2051124321/2051124324&lt;/pa1-->
<!-- Note:si:M170-->
<!-- Note:s:CUMMINGS,LEWIS/FILE ROOM-->
<ti>RECORDS MANAGEMENT</ti>
<pg>1</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":STMN/R1-023-->
<!-- Note:lu:STMN/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:19980605-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>PHILIP MORRIS MANAGEMENT CORP. INTER-OFFICE CORRESPONDENCE
120 PARK AVENUE, NE'yv YORK, NY 10017-5592
TO: Lewis Cummings / , DATE: June 1, 1993
FROM: Virginia Murphy
SUBJECT: Records Management
As a result of research and analysis conducted by the PM USA Legal and Records
Management Departments, and in order to achieve company-wide consistency within
record categories, the following record categories must be revised.
• "Calendars/Daytimers/Diaries" will have a total,retention of C+1. This
record category should appear on all retention schedules.
If the following record categories currently appear on retention schedules, they
should be revised as follows:
• "Contracts &amp; Agreements - Official Copies" will have a total retention period
of ACT+6. If the contracts and agreements are labor, insurance or benefits contracts, etc.,
they will have a retention period specific to the type of contract and should be labelled as
such.
ACT.
• "Contracts &amp; Agreements - Unofficial Copies" will have a retention period of
• '7ob Safety Procedures" will have a total retention of SUP+5.
• "Safety Issues" will have a total retention of C+5. Existing safety categories
should be deleted and combined into a single category. These changes do not apply to the
Environmental Health and Safety retention schedule.
• "Safety Procedures Manual" (PM USA) will have a total retention of SUP and
the office of record will be ER/EHS with a total retention of P.
• "First Aid Team Records" will have a retention period of Act and the office of
record will be Medical with total retention of P.	
~	"Government Agencies, Laws and Regulations" will have a total retention of	
SUP.

•	

"Workers Compensation Claims"
should be deleted from th
nmental
Envir	
?V
.
e
o
Health and Safety retention schedule and placed on the Medical Retention Schedule. All	Cn
~
records will be relocated pursuant to this change.	
~
	
Appropriate maintenance forms should be prepared to reflect these changes.	~
	~
Thank you for your anticipated assistance, Lewis.	C,5
pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
