<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae13f00</tid>
<ti>Subj: Incorporation of RT Into Deer Material.</ti>
<dt>Memo</dt>
<dt>Correspondence</dt>
<dd>19930820</dd>
<au>Caruso-L;Souza Cruz</au>
<rc>Riehl-T;B&amp;W;Read-G;BATCO</rc>
<pc>Gordon-D;B&amp;W;Baker-R;BATCO;Pangritz-D;BATCF;L Saboia e Silva;de Siqueira-C;Souza Cruz</pc>
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":A5-->
<pg>6</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:967688-->
<fn>BAT Program</fn>
<!-- Note:dl:19990524-->
<bt>586100379/0384</bt>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>AUG 20 '93 08:52 FROM R AND D 3RD FLOOR TO 8225
rHVt. 005
'!3 •t,28 09+28 a e21 201 7393 50U2R CRUZ CPO e2
*•-
/N
SOUZA CRUZ
I; t'CJrpcg
CP&amp;cTr2t;7
TO: T.F. Rieh! - S&amp;w
C. Read - RA'I'(:O.
eROM: I..T. f:aruso
DATE: August 20, i993
SURJF.C'1': INCORPORA'i'IOlV Olt RT INTO DEER MATERIAL
C/C: D. Gordon / H, Honoycuu -}3&amp;W
R. J;akcr - t3A'I'CO.
i). Pangritz -13nTC'h'
L.1. Salwlb c SitVa ' SOIJLA CRU/.
t'.J. P. de Siqucira - SOUZA CK tJ'/.
Nttasc find ettac}ted for your eommcnts the G^•rwtArnent Nrngram for thr, nhavr.
mentioned subject.
Should it bc suitxhlc for you t would recommend thc date of October 4, 1993 to start
the program.
Please let me know, as soon as possiblc, the s:etondCCs'namcs and your opinion on
the su~,tgested program.
I witl be tooking forward 10 YOUT trply.
Kind regards.
L.T-Caruao
Resatrch &amp; Develupmsat Center
1~ncI
Sousa Crus SA
Aw. Suaurlwm. poss
21059 900 • Rio do JaHpitO RJ B.npii
lelex (21) 31187 $CIC HH
TA{. 281-6122
fsx 201 •7395
I
iYlG 20 '93 08: 36 021 201 'T-3,95 PFlGE.002
5~8-61100379
pgNbr=1
AIJG 20 ' 93 08:52 FROM R AND D 3RD FLOOR TU 8225 rnuG . ~-+
'93 88%28 89!29 j 82! 201 7399 SCUZR CRU2 CPO 93
Souza Cruz
Soamdwrat Prvgraat
Incorporatiod of R'1' Ento DEER Mgterial
Objnctivc:
To share Souza Cruz expertise in inccuporation ol` Root '1'echnology into exlruded
rcoon co contiuuousty llnju-uvG Its sensoty quality.
Timing:
45 - 60 days.
Progratn
1. Souza Cruz R&amp;D Orientation
2. Presentation and Discussion of Works Developed in Souza Cruz
Presentation of works carried out to incorporate K'1' into extrudcd rccon which will
cover the following topics:
- tests on different agglutinattts;
- tests on differem ammonia sources;
- tests nnder differmt processing conditions:
- tests on burn control agents;
- tests on residue addition;
-f6srs on lnc4i}}dradai of ItII ane! athtv flav,ars: and
- rvtitm wInmisun lrsultx.
3. rormulatiob Devdopmcnt
tinlinuring An Mrim'voT ditrnrrirm, NT.irrrnqn»f" ftrtrntit~tirmg higrd rot
EXPERT development cxpcricricc witl be developed considering the followittg
parametCrs.
I
aUG 2e 's3 0e: 3s
V('&gt;,'JM,-MCIM
58GI-0U380
pgNbr=2
AUG 20 '93 08:51 FROM R AND D 3RD FLOOR
TO 8225 PAGE. 0OJ
'93 66i26 69r1A a 621 261 7395 SOU2A CRUZ Cv0 04
.2.
3.1 Furnishieg
A number of furnishing compositions can be tested to evaluate extruded recon
Production at diffemro ste.m materials addition rates.
Also studied can be the influence of furnishing particle sir,e on quality characteris-
tics of the extruded materiat.
Use of the furnishing normally used for other B&amp;W and HA'I'Co recon processes, is
ttrMicipated. These furnishings can have their formulation reproduced u,4ittg materials
from OLT plants and Souza Cruz factories.
3.2 Agghttin:ant and Humettast Additives and E=pansion Ag.nts
Action of modified starches as expansion and agglutinant agents and their sensory
properties can be studied.
Different formulation HPC Icvtls can be tested to rneasure product feasibifity and
resistance at the soverat process steps.
Humectaztt action of gtycerol, sorb2tol, and propylene glycol can be compared.
3.3 Ammonia Sources
Diffcrtnt ammonia sources can be used in R&amp;W and BAI'Co furnishings based on
EXPERT devolopmont experience.
Action of burn control agents in formulation developments under way can be
invesdgaood.
Effect of ammmiium sait crystat sizc and of eventually incrca.SCo mechanical shear
on sheet formation mechanism, can be studied.
3.4 Retction Flavor
f)ifferrnt RF (ANSIRO, CESPAU. DAISSA etc.) at different addition levels can be
cvalue4ed to improve product sensory eharactcriaties.
I
AJG 20 '93 06:37 021 201 ?396 PPGE.0e4
58GI00381.
pgNbr=3
AUG 20 '93 08:51 FROM R AND D 3RD FLOOR TO 8225 PAGE.002
'93 88i2® 89131 ! 621 291 7393 SOUZi7 CRUZ CPD
-3-
3.5 Tobacco Duat ExtrsCt3
Tobacco dust extracts can bc used to enhance tobacco typical notes of tl+c final
product.
3.6 Other Flavors
Possibility of incotporatinl; such flavors normally used in thc cigarette industry as
cocor,, licoricc etc., can be evaluated.
3.7 Processing Conditions
On the basis of the experience gained in F.XPERT development the following
processing conditions may he cheaged as a result of quality characicristics of thc
formulation dovdopments in progress:
- cxtrudcr scrcw configuration;
- extruder cylinder temperature profik;
- screw speed and residence time; and
- atarting moisture.
3.8 Product Characterization
Thc following analyses can be effectcd to characterize and comparc formulation
developments under way:
- moisture;
- fiiting density;
- balance moi$ture;
- sheet width and thickness;
- sheet density;
- ultimate stress and pcrcent elongation;
- particle size;
- total auloids;
- total sugars and reducers;
- total N;
- ammoniacal N;
- 2,5- and 2,6-deoxyfiuatosazits.s;
- pyrazancs; and
- expert and Delta panal sensory evaluation.
AJG 20 ' 93 08 :39
821 201 7396 PAGE.005
85
SSGI_00382
pgNbr=4
AUG 20 '93 08:52 FROM R AND D 3RD FLOOR TO 8225
'93 08--2e 89233
Z 62: 201 7395 SDU2R cRUZ CPD
.,.
4, Study of Extruded Product Aging
RT-incorporating products arc known to require a bulking time for all the expected
cfiemicaf reactions to take place. This aging could be obtained either with thc
cxtraded product alone or afler its incorporation into a blend.
At this point, the former process can be evaluated at 0, S, 10, and 15 days with the
periods being chemically atonitored_
5. Manufacture of Cigarettes for Kormutation Comparison
Cig,aretxes (blend to be defined following a discussion with secondees) can be
manufactured with different addition levels of the best formulation developments.
Cigarettr manufacture can take into account the influence of addition levels of the
extruded prodiict on its physical propcrties.
Cigarette aging period required for completion of arninonia and nicotinc migration,
can be Gvaluated.
Thcse formulations can be compared with a nosE-R'3' standard forrnuiation and other
recons available within the Group (CPCl., l:I3R etc.).
6. Experimental Design
To be followed up by the socondees and based on the needs of each development
ste(1.
7. Other Activities
Other extrusion proccss related activities may be eruried out during the secondmetu
dependent upon each secondee's available time. Suggcstions among other activities
are:
- Evaluation of the effcct of dbw amrnoniation of tobacco dust cxtracts for
add;tyon to fsmishings as tobacco natural reaction flavor.
- Fvaluation of the influence of ammonium salts &lt;m product balnnce tnoisturc.
- Development of extruded tobacco with addition of non-lt7' flavors. i
At.I3 20 ' 93 08= 40 021 201 7395 PFlGE. ee6
FHGE.bbb
e 6
5861.00383
pgNbr=5
AUG 20 '93 08'52 FROM R AND D 3RD FLOOR TO 8225 PAGE.007
'93 68,20 09934
T 021 2e1 7395 SOUZA CRUZ CPn E7
.5-
- f.:valuation of the effeet of furnishing contents of silica on mechanicat wear of
extruder set rws and beds.
Naw.
$toondccs' proposal of any additive for test shall bc infonncd in advance so
that its procurement can be arranl,rod.
Secondees shall bring information on composition of blends and furnishings
scheduled for testing. Brazilian tobacco grades shall be used in the rnakinb of
such blends.
Seaondcxs are encouragcd to bring recon ciganettcx either uscd or being acsted
in their respective companies for comparison with (lie deveioprnCnts under way
in Braz.il.
f
AUG 20 ' 93 0F3 :42 021 201 7'.396 PAC£. 007
** TOTAL PAGE.007 **
58f100384
pgNbr=6
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
