<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aax02a00</tid>
<bt>2001116408/6409</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="m":2001116364/6438-->
<!-- Note:br t="o":PRO1904-->
<dd>19851003</dd>
<dt>SCRT, REPORT, SCIENTIFIC</dt>
<au>UYDESS,IL</au>
<np>BOKELMAN,G; BRADFORD; DAVIES,B</np>
<!-- Note:co:CONF, CONFIDENTIAL; EXTR, EXTRA-->
<!-- Note:si:R6-->
<!-- Note:s:CHARLES,JIM/OFFICE-->
<ti>TOBACCO PHYSIOLOGY AND BIOCHEMISTRY 850901 - 850930</ti>
<pg>2</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":STMN/R1-137-->
<!-- Note:lu:STMN/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:19990524-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>I
I
I
I
I
I
i
I
L
I
I
i
L
CHARGE NUMBER: Project 1904
PROJECT TITLE: Tobacco Physiology and Biochemistry
PERIOD COVERED: September 1i-30, 1985
PROJECT LEADER: I.L. Uydess
DATE OF REPORT: October 3, 1985,
Objective: To establish the time course and bilochemical changes
characteristic of tobacco leaves at varilous stages during senescence.
Status: Two different extractions of greenhouse-grown, Coker 31:9 green leaf
were prepared for use in three biochemical enzyme assays. One set of
extractions was made in Pipes buffer, containing KC1, sodium ascorbate, and
thiourea, with and without one of two protease inhibitors (Phenyl-Methyl-
Sulfonyl-Fluoride, and leupeptin)1. The second set of extractions was made
in Bis-Tris buffer, containing thiourea and KC1, with and without casein
and/or leupeptin (a serine and thiol-type protease inhibitor).
Leucine aminopeptidase (LAP), endopeptidase (EP), and~carboxypeptidase-
A(CP-A) assays were conducted on the aforementiomed green leaf extracts.
All positilve controls using commerci'ially available preparations of each
enzyme worked well. LAP was the only enzyme which showed activity iin any of
these extracts, as well as in previous extracts.
Protein determinations according to the Bradford method were also made
on these extracts. It is not clea at this time whether or not the
inclusion of PMSF, casein, and/or leupeptin is necessary.
A method!for the determi,nation of chlorophyll in tobacco leaves was
transferred from Project 11720 to Project 1904. Frozen greenileaf, freeze-
dried green leaf, and senesced (yellow) leaf were ground wilth Liquidid
nitrogen and the chlorophyll extracted with 80% acetone. The absorbancy
values were measured at 663 nm and 645 nm and corrected against a background
absorbancy at 720 nm. As expected, the amount of chlorophyll was found to
be greater in the greenileaves, than inithe yellow, senesced leaves.
Plans: To:continue testing for enzyme activitiies initobacco extracts
prepared from material grown in the greenhouse or in the field under various
conditions.
Other Studies: 2Q01:1i7 64Q8
Greenhouse grown, Coker 319 leaf material frozen at -70°C in July, 1985
was powdered and~ lyophilized to determine the dry weight yield~ from, fresh-
frozen leaf at different stages of senescence. This material was
subsequently submitted to the Analytical Research Division for the purpose
of conducting trial determinatilons of Ca++, starch, nitrogen, and other
targeted tobacco components.

pgNbr=1
-2-
Samples supplied by B. Davies were electrophoresed on a 3-27% SDS
polyacrylamine gel. This work was done in conjunction~with G. Bokelman to
characterize proteins present in extractions of'an Acetobacter used to~study
the synthesis of cellulose.
I
I
I
I
I
I
I
I
I
pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
