<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aae31c00</tid>
<bt>2085614390/4401</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="m":2085614380/4470-->
<dd>19900101</dd>
<dt>LETT, LETTER</dt>
<dt>CONT, CONTRACT, AGREEMENT RESOLUTION</dt>
<au>BAUM,DM</au>
<ca>LEO, LEO BURNETT AGENCY</ca>
<cr>DONREY OUTDOOR ADV</cr>
<no>DONREY OUTDOOR ADV; LEO, LEO BURNETT AGENCY</no>
<!-- Note:co:ATCH, ATTACHMENTS MISSING; ILLE, ILLEGIBLE-->
<fn>2085614356/2085614581/ADVICE SUBJECT FILE 40.220</fn>
<!-- Note:si:N1019-->
<!-- Note:s:MSA/STORED FILES-->
<pg>12</pg>
<!-- Note:lu:FEDA/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:20030102-->
<dl>20030215</dl>
<ot>r
`
II
LEO BllRNETT U.S.A.
January 1, 1990
Donrey Outdoor Adv. Co.
P.O. Box 18636
Oklahoma Citv, OR 73118
This letter, when signed by Donrey Outdoor Adv. Co.
("Company") and Leo Burnett Company, Inc. ("Agency") as agency for
its clients ("Advertisers") shall constitute an agreement that all
dealings between them regarding Outdoor Advertising shall be
governed by the terms and conditions set forth in this letter
agreement. For each advertising display ordered by Agency from
Company, Agency and Company shall enter into separate agreements
("Individual Contracts"). Any Individual Contract for services to
be performed by Company on behalf of Agency and its client(s)
shall be governed by the terms specifically set forth therein and
by the terms and conditions specifically set forth herein. In the
event of a conflict between terms in an Individual Contract and
the terms and conditions contained herein, the terms of the
Individual Contract shall prevail. In addition, any instructions
contained in painting or posting instructions shall prevail over
the terms and conditions contained herein.
1.0
RATES:
1.1 All rates quoted in each Individual Contract are
subject to an Agency commission of 16-2/3% of those
rates, unless otherwise indicated in an Individual
Contract.
1.2 All rates and adjustments shall be computed on a
basis of thirty (30) days to a month.
1.3 Company represents that all its rates are published
(except in the cases of permanent bulletins) and that
the rates specified in each Individual Contract
(including discounts under any plan of continuity,
frequency or quantity) are the lowest rates at which
any party may contract for like services at the time
of that contract.
1.4 For the purpose of computing the applicable discount
for each Advertiser, the service ordered under any
Individual Contract, for the same market(s) and the
same Advertiser, shall be combined with the service
ordered under any other Individual Contract for any
other products or services of Advertiser and its
affiliates. Affiliates include, but are not limited
to, Advertiser's subsidiaries, parent company and
subsidiaries of the parent company.
2085614390
35 WEST WACRER DRIVE. CHICAGO, ILLINOIS 60601 1312) 220-5959 TELEX-25409B
pgNbr=1
.
-2-
1
2.0	INDEPENDENT CONTRACTOR; COMPLIANCE WITH APPLICABLE LAWS:
	2.1	The	Company's relationship to the Agency is that of
		an
all	independent contractor and Company will do any and
things necessary to comply with laws and
		regulations pertaining to its independent business.
3.0	CANCELLATION OF INDIVIDUAL CONTRACTS:
3.1 Except in the case of permanent or rotary bulletins,
any Individual Contract may be cancelled by Agency by
giving written notice thereof to the Company no later
than sixty (60) days, including Sunday and holidays,
in advance of the scheduled posting date under an
Individual Contract. In the case of permanent or
rotary bulletins, cancellation shall be governed by
the terms set forth in Individual Contracts.
Cancellation of any Individual Contract shall not
affect the application of these terms and conditions
to any other Individual Contract between Company and
Agency.
3.2 In the case of permanent or rotary bulletins, upon
cancellation or non-renewal, the final month's
payment shall not be due and owing to Company until
Agency has received an affidavit from the Company
confirming that any Display posted on behalf of
Agency has been covered over or removed.
3.3 In the event of cancellation by Agency, Agency shall
pay Company a short rate charge equal to the
difference between the rate earned under the contract
and the rate applicable to the service used,
determined by reference to the rate card on which the
contract rate is based, where applicable.
3.4 In the event that the Company delays in or fails to
perform under an Individual Contract as the result of
force majeure, labor dispute, legislation, court
order or decision, regulation, administrative
decision or rulemaking, federal, state, or local
governmental action or order, any other law, or other
cause beyond Company's reasonable control, including,
but not limited to, the length of approach diversion,
redirection of traffic, or obstruction of line of
sight, such delay, failure, or cause shall not
constitute breach of contract. However, in case of
those events, Agency shall be notified immediately of
such delay, failure, or cause in the manner set forth
in Paragraph 7.2 and shall be entitled, at its
election, to (1) cash, and/or (2) an extension of
service, and/or (3) advertising service on new
substituted location approved by Agency to be
executed and maintained under the terms and
2085614391
pgNbr=2
I
conditions hereof, and/or (4) credit, all on a pro
rata basis. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the
event of a failure to provide illumination as
required under Paragraph 6.0 herein, Agency shall be
compensated by a cash credit equal to 25% of the
monthly cost of the display.
3.5 Notwithstanding the foregoing, should any delay,
failure or cause described in Paragraph 3.4 above,
continue for a period of sixty (60) days or longer,
in addition to credit as provided for in that
Paragraph, Agency shall have the right to terminate
the contract forthwith.
3.6 In the event there is any federal, state or local
government law, ordinance or ruling that is enacted
during any Individual Contract between Agency and
Company, which makes advertising of any product or
service specified in any Individual Contract between
Company and Agency unlawful or which requires a
modification to the advertising copy which, in the
opinion of the Agency, reduces the value thereof to
the Advertiser, Agency then reserves the right to
terminate any Individual Contract so affected,
without penalty and with no further payment, as of
the date such law, ordinance, or ruling becomes
effective.
3.7 It is further understood and agreed that Agency may
cancel any Individual Contract without penalty at any
time without notice by Agency in the event of adverse
publicity of any nature resulting frc:n the presence
of any Display placed pursuant to this Agreement.
3.8 In the event Agency cancels any Individual
Contract(s), Agency's obligations shall cease, except
that Agency shall make payment for unamortized costs
of embellishments, if any.
4.0 CIGARETTE ADVERTISING:
Outdoor Displays used to display cigarette advertising must
be located a minimum of five hundred (500) feet away from
the building, playground, or property adjacent to the
following establishments:
a.	educational institutions (schools);	
b.	churches;	
c.	hospitals;	N
d.	public playgrounds; or	O
		Co
e.	cemeteries.	Cn
		IM
		_a
		~
		w
		co
		N
pgNbr=3
- 4 - ~
outdoor Bulletin Displays displaying cigarette advertising
that are located more than five hundred (500) feet, in
either direction, from the above-referenced establishments
may not be facing the property or the buildings of said
establishments. If there is any question as to whether a
Display is within five hundred (500) feet of any of the
above-referenced establishments, Company shall get approval
of the Display from Agency's Field Representative.
5.0 RENEWAL:
5.1 At any time during the term of any Individual
Contract, Agency has the first right to renew any
such contract with the company, terms and conditions
to be negotiated.
5.2 If Agency and Company do not reach an agreement on
the rates proposed to renew the terms of any
Individual Contract within sixty (60) days prior to
the end of the term, then Company shall be free to
negotiate with another Advertiser for the Outdoor
Bulletin Display. The Company, however, cannot
contract with another advertiser at rates lower than
these offered to Advertiser for use of that Outdoor
Bulletin Display without first offering the lower
rates to Advertiser.
6.0 Ii.IdRIINATION:
6.1 All illuminated Displays shall be illuminated by up-
to-date outdoor lighting, and shall be equipped
properly with a sufficient number of reflectors and
lamps of adequate size to evenly illuminate the
entire Display. In the case of permanent and/or
rotary bulletins, all new illuminated Displays shall
be illuminated by Holophane Sign-Vue II fixtures
equipped with 400 watt Sylvania Metralarc Lamps
(clear); the equivalent may be used on existing
illuminated Displays. All posted bulletins shall be
illuminated by the aforementioned Sign-Vue II
fixtures or fluorescent lights, unless variation is
similarly approved by Agency. Notwithstanding the
foregoing, other illumination may be used if (1)
Agency is notified of the proposed variation in
writing upon receipt of any Individual Contract from
Agency by Company, and (2) Agency approves such
variation, in writing.
6.2 Illuminated Displays shall be illuminated each night
from one half hour prior to sunset to midnight.
6.3 Failure to conform performance to the terms set forth
in this Paragraph 6.0 shall constitute failure to
provide illumination.
2085614393
pgNbr=4
7.0 NOTICE:
7.1 All notices hereunder 4all be in writing, unless
otherwise provided herein, shall be given only by
prepaid telegram or mail to the addresses set forth
below, and shall be dee',:ed given on the date of
dispatch.
7.2 All notice(s) to Agency shall be sent to:
LEO BURNETT COMPANY, IN?%.
35 West Wacker
Chicago, Illinois 60601
Attn: Out-Of-Home Media Director
referencing the particular Advertiser involved.
All invoices shall be sent to the attention of
Agency's Accounting Department, Section B.
All notice(s) to Company shall be sent to the address
set forth at the end of this Agreement.
Each party shall notify the other of any changes in
address.
8.0	TERMS OF PAYMENT:
8.1 Company will, within five (5) working days after
completion of:
a.	initial copy, and each month thereafter (if

b.	Outdoor Bulletin Display) or;
posting for each date ordered (if poster display)

c.	or;
Displays for each date ordered (for other out of
home media not specified in this Agreement)
bill Agency at the address set forth in Paragraph 7.2
of this Agreement. Agency shall pay Company, at the
address set forth at the foot of this Agreement or
the address set forth in any Individual Contract,
within 30 days after date of billing.
8.2 Company agrees to hold Agency solely liable for
payment to the sums due under any Individual
Contract(s).
8.3 Additionally, billing procedures shall follow the
instructions set forth in the following documents,
and any amendments to those documents, as applicable
to each category:
2085614394
pgNbr=5
r
- 6 -
a. "Important Notice to All Outdoor Plants Regarding
Billing Procedures for All Poster Contracts,"
b. "Important Notice to All Plants Regarding Billing
Procedures for All Painted Bulletin Contracts,"
c. "Important Notice to All Plants Regarding Billing
Procedures for all Miscellaneous and Transit
Contracts."
Copies of these documents are attached hereto and thereby
incorporated into all contracts between Company and Agency,
as applicable to each category.
9.0 INSURANCE:
9.1 At any time it provides services to Agency, Company
agrees to maintain in full force and effect public
liability insurance in the amounts of at least
$500,000 for personal injury and $500,000 for
property damage relating to the structures on which
the Displays and/or posters will be exhibited, and
Company agrees to provide Agency with a Certificate
of Insurance evidencing such coverage.
10.0 WARRANTY AND INDEMNIFICATION:
10.1 To Company
10.11 Agency agrees to hold Company harmless against
all liability arising out of the content of
advertising materials furnished by Agency.
10.2 To Agency
10.21 Company warrants that it will construct and/or
maintain all of the structures related to any
Individual Contract in a safe and lawful manner
and obtain all necessary leases, licenses and
permits pertaining thereto, and Company agrees
to hold Agency and Advertisers harmless from
any and all claims (including reasonable
attorney's fees) relating to the structures and
their installation, maintenance, removal and
any and all aspects of their operation,
including but not limited to, all such
liability arising out of Company's failure to
remove posters within thirty (30) working days
after the expiration of any Individual
Contract, provided such failure is not due to
force majeure.
J
2085614395
pgNbr=6
- 7 -
11.0 ASSIGNMENT:
11.1 Neither party may assign this Agreement or any rights
or obligations arising from this Agreement without
the prior express written consent of the otherl
provided, however, that nothing in this Agreement
shall impair the right of any Advertiser to assign
this Agreement, any Individual Contract, or its
beneficial interest therein. In the event assignment
does occur, such assignment shall not relieve the
assigning party from its liability or obligations
hereunder, and this Agreement as well as Individual
Contracts shall also be binding on the successors and
assigns of the assigning party.
11.2 Company agrees not to sell, lease, or otherwise
convey any interest in an Outdoor Bulletin Display
that is the subject of this Agreement or any
Individual Contract to a third party except subject
to the terms of this Agreement and any Individual
Contract; Company shall take all necessary steps to
ensure that the obligations of this Agreement and any
Individual Contract run with any Outdoor Bulletin
Display or other property to which they are subject.
12.0 COMPETITIVE ADVERTISING:
12.1 There will be no competitive products or services
displayed by Company in the same facing for a minimum
of:
a. 300 feet preceding and/or following a poster
panel;
b. 1,000 feet preceding and/or following a
bulletin.
13.0 ALTERATION OF MATERIAI6:
13.1 Company shall not make any alteration in advertising
materials without written consent of Agency.
13.2 Unused material, including posters, may be disposed
of by the Company upon completion of the schedule
called for in any Individual Contract, or if no
schedule is specified, fifteen (15) days after the
last day of display schedule as defined in Agency's
posting instructions, unless written instructions to
do otherwise are received by Company.
13.3 Company shall not scrape Boards/Displays over the
weekend. Scraping may only be done Monday through
Thursday and Board/Display may not be out of service
for more than twenty-four (24) hours.
2085614396
pgNbr=7
S
- 8 -
13.4 Any changes not approved by Agency under Paragraphs
17.41 or 18.41 and any failure to give Agency notice
required under those Paragraphs are subject to
automatic credit to Agency for the displaced poster
or advertising material.
14.0 TAXES:
Company shall pay all taxes, except sales and use taxes,
which may be applicable to the ownership or control of
Display(s) or the display of materials thereon.
15.0 REJECTION OF MATERIALS:
Company and any third party which controls the poster
locations shall have the right to reject any advertising
material submitted by Agency. In the event of such
rejection, Agency shall have no obligation to pay for the
service for which the rejected material was submitted and
shall have the right to fully or partially terminate the
Individual Contract dealing with rejected material.
16.0 OUTDOOR BULLETIN DISPLAYS
IN ADDITION to the foregoing, the following terms and
conditions shall govern all contracts for Outdoor Bulletin
Displays:
16.1 Copy Changes
16.11 The following copy change options are available
to Agency:
(a) If any bulletin is to be completely
painted, there will be three (3) complete
paintings each year, including the
initial; or
(b) If any bulletin is to be partially
posted, there will be six (6) postings of
posted portion and three (3) paintings of
painted portion each year, including the
initial; or
(c) If any bulletin is to be completely
posted, there will be six (6) postings
each year, including the initial.
16.12 Agency, as provided below, will deliver
Acceptable Artwork to the Company in sufficient
quantity for proper execution of display(s),
all as provided herein below and in Individual
Contracts.
2085614397
pgNbr=8
7
l
- 9 -
16.13 In the case of a new contract, Agency will
deliver Acceptable Artwork to the Company
within thirty (30) days of receipt of Company's
acceptance of the new contract. For subsequent
copy changes, Agency will furnish Acceptable
Artwork and instructions sixty (60) days prior
to desired copy change date if this is a
painted display, or forty five (45) days prior
for a fully or partially posted display.
16.14 If, for any reason, Company cannot complete any
copy change on the date specified, Company will
notify Agency immediately.
16.15 "Acceptable Artwork" shall be defined as a
scaled or properly proportioned mechanical,
original illustration, dye transfer or other
color reproduction of comparable quality.
Color transparencies shall not be deemed to be
Acceptable Artwork.
16.16 All copy changes agreed to as indicated on an
Individual Contract may be carried over from
one year to the next during the life of that
Individual Contract. However, there will be no
credits issued to Agency by Company for copy
changes not used.
16.17 Any copy changes requiring a change in cut-outs
must take place simultaneously. Both cut out
and copy must be transferred at the same time
in order to minimize down time. Any copy
and/or cut out changes must be completed within
a twenty-four (24) hour period and prior to the
weekend.
16.2 OBZ.IGATIONS OF COMPANY:
16.21 All designs are to be faithfully reproduced, and all
displays are to be maintained in accordance with
standards of the industry, in the sole opinion of
Agency.
16.22 Within five (5) days of completion of copy changes,
Company will send completion notices to Agency,
giving date of completion.
16.23 Upon completion of copy changes, Company will submit
to Agency the following photo requirements on the
date specified in painting instructions:
1 - 35mm color slide (close-up)
2 - 3 1/2" x 5" color prints (close-up)
16.24 Failure to supply the materials set forth in
Paragraphs 16.22 and 16.23 in a timely fashion may
result in Agency withholding payment of your
invoice.
2085614398
pgNbr=9
C
16.25 company will be responsible for and agrees to
maintain special treatment, if used, in a
satisfactory condition through any Individual
Contract term and will indemnify the Agency against
loss or damage including, but not limited to, acts of
God.
17.0 POSTER DISPLAYS:
IN ADDITION to the foregoing general terms and conditions
set forth in Paragraphs 1 - 15, the following terms and
conditions shall govern all contracts for Poster Displays:
17.1 Location List
17.11 Company shall submit a location list in duplicate to
Agency along with its invoice(s). The list shall
conform to the requirements set forth in the document
entitled "Important Notice to All Outdoor Plants
Regarding Billing Procedures for all Poster
contracts." Failure to submit such location list
may, at sole option of Agency, result in Agency
withholding payment of your invoice.
17.2 Delivery of Posters By Agency
17.21 Agency will deliver posters in quantity sufficient to
meet the needs under any Individual Contract(s) (plus
10% for renewal purposes) at places designated by
Company, shipping charges prepaid, at least fifteen
(15) calendar days prior to the scheduled posting
date(s).
17.3 Posting Obligations of Company
17.31 Except as hereinafter provided, the posters furnished
by the Agency shall be posted by Company in the
markets and on the dates scheduled in any Individual
Contract.
17.32 Posters will be freshly blanked at the time of each
posting on panels which are maintained in accordance
with standards of the industry, and will be
distributed on locations approved by Agency
representative.
17.33 Posters and panels will be kept in good condition
throughout the term of any Individual Contract.
Posters will be promptly reposted, provided
sufficient additional posters are supplied by Agency.
Company will notify Agency immediately if posters are
needed for reposting.
2085614399
pgNbr=10
Y
17.34 If posters are timely delivered, Company shall
complete posting no sooner than five (5) working days
before and no later than five (5) working days after
the scheduled posting date. Advertisers shall have
the benefit of a full thirty (30) days display from
the average date of posting. Company will
immediately notify Agency by telephone and in writing
if posters are not received on time.
17.35 If posters are timely delivered but cannot be posted
in accordance with Paragraph 17.31, Agency will be
informed immediately and any available substitute
dates and locations will be submitted for Agency's
approval. Such inability to post shall be governed
by the terms of Paragraphs 3.4 and 3.5 herein.
17.4 Poster Placement
17.41 Company retains exclusive control and supervision
over the posting, maintenance and removal of the
posters and over the location on which they are
displayed. Any proposed change made in location of
posters, for any reason, must be reported to Agency
in writing ten (10) days prior to such change, along
with a statement of reason for the change, a
statement of comparable location, and information
regarding daily effective circulation and type of
panel. All proposed changes must be approved by
Agency.
18.0 MISCELS-ANEOUS:
IN ADDITION to the foregoing general terms and conditions
set forth in Paragraphs 1- 15, the following terms and
conditions shall govern all contracts for Out-Of-Home Media
not specifically addressed elsewhere in this Agreement:
18_1 Advertising Service
18.11 Company shall install the advertising display
materials furnished by Agency on the locations and
dates scheduled on the face of Individual Contracts.
Company agrees to maintain the Displays in good
condition and promptly replace soiled or defaced
Displays with extra material furnished for that
purpose. Advertisers should have full display thirty
(30) days from average date of installation.
18.2 Installation
18.21 Installation should be completed no sooner than five
(5) working days before and no later than five (5)
working days following scheduled carding or posting
dates.
208561 4400
pgNbr=11
~
18.3 Advertising Display Materials '
18.31 Agency will provide advertising display materials at
places designated by Company (shipping charges
prepaid) at least fifteen (15) calendar days prior to
display date. Company will notify Agency immediately
if materials are not redeived by that time.
18.32 Agency is entitled to a&gt;~hange of display material
once every thirty (30) days without charge, on
scheduled dates.
18.4
Placement !
18.41 company retains exclusive control and supervision
over placement, maintenance and removal of the
advertising materials and over the locations on which
they are displayed. Any proposed change made in
location of advertising materials for any reason,
must be reported in writing to Agency ten (10) days
prior to such change, along with a statement of
reason for the change, a statement of comparable
location, and information regarding daily effective
circulation. All proposed changes are subject to
Agency approval.
Failure of either party to enforce any of the
provisions hereof shall not be construed as a general
relinquishment or waiver of that or any other
provision.
If Company agrees to the foregoing, please execute
both copies of this Agreement and return one original
copy to Agency, retaining the other copy for your
files.
Very truly yours,
ACCEPTED AND AGREED TO: LEO BURNETT COMPANY, INC.

(Company)	
'	35 West Wacker
Chicago, Illinois	
60601	
		~		
By:		By:			
Title:	f. I	Title:	7~t  =~	J,	
	'	-	i		
Address:	&lt;&lt; ~				N
	f~	• t			
CD
00
	%				CA

Date:					a)
					A
O
l
pgNbr=12
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
