<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aab00d00</tid>
<bt>50308951/8951</bt>
<ti>CTR PROGRESS REPORT  PCP-A NEW PROBE OF PLATELET FUNCTION</ti>
<dd>19920630</dd>
<dt>SCIENTIFIC REPORT</dt>
<au>JAMIESON GA; CTR</au>
<!-- Note:d:SPECIFIC AIMS ARE: 1) STUDY OF THE EFFECTS OF PCP WITH REGARD TO MEMBRANE POTENTIAL AND ION FLUXES AND THE EXPRESSION OF FIBRINOGEN, 2) THE PCP BINDING PROTEIN WILL BE CHARACTERIZED BY THE MAPPING OF INTERACITVE DOMAINS WITH CARIOUS AGONIST AND ANTAGONIST AND STRUCTURAL ANALOGS OF PCP, AND 3) A PCP RECEPTOR WILL BE IDENTIFIED BY AFFINITY LABELLING AND ITS PRIMARY STRUCTURE DETERMINED BY CLONING ITS CDNA AND AN APPROPRIATE EXPRESSION-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>•
CTR PROGRESS REPORT MAY 2 61992
GRANT NUMBER 3177 ._ Period Covered: from 07/01/91 L to 06/30/92
Name of Investigator: Graham A. Jamieson, Ph.D., D.Sc ~-.
Title of Original Grant: PCP--A New Probe of Platelet Function
Abstract of the specific aims as stated in the original application:
Preliminary studies have shown that the psychotomimetic drug phencyclidine (PCP)
specifically inhibits platelet activation by epinephrine and by low concentrations of thrombin
corresponding to the thrombin high affinity receptor pathway. This inhibition appears to
correspond to the binding of PCP to a high affinity binding site in platelets that has similarities
to the NMDA receptor of neuronal cells but lacks its stereoselectivity towards specific
antagonists. The purpose of the proposed study is to understand the mechanism by which these
selective inhibitory effects of PCP are modulated. This will be achieved under three specific
aims: i) the effects of PCP will be studied with regard to membrane potential and ion fluxes and
the expression of fibrinogen receptors; ii) the PCP binding protein will be characterized by the
mapping of interactive domains with various agonist and antagonists and structural analogs of
PCP; and iii) a PCP receptor will be identified by affinity labelling and its primary structure
determined by cloning its cDNA and an appropriate expression vector. These studies may be
important in designing selective inhibitors of platelet function.
List any publications (author, title and journal) resulting from the current CTR award that
contain a printed acknowledgement of CTR suppor1. For manuscripts, the designation "in
press" means you have a preprint; otherwise use "accepted for publication by...",
"submitted for publication" or "in preparation." Do not include publications that do not
acknowledge CTR.
None
0 Report of Progress (no more than 4 pages, please):

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
