<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aaz90d00</tid>
<bt>522760216/0217</bt>
<rc>ITTERMANN PF; RJR</rc>
<au>LONG HAYMES; KENDALL SL</au>
<bx>RJR4844</bx>
<!-- Note:b:CAMEL-->
<pc>RJR; WILLIARD J; LONG HAYMES; STERLING C; ESELIUS L; TUCKER T; SHELTON M</pc>
<dd>19970528</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<!-- Note:co:Y-->
<np>ITTERMANN PF; RJR; LONG HAYMES; LIST OF PRINT MEDIA ADVERTISERS; KLEIN O; OGILVY MATHER</np>
<!-- Note:dl:20010827-->
<pg>2</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":US PRIORITY REQUEST 3-->
<!-- Note:sh:20010221-->
<!-- Note:s:MARKETING; MKTG OPS-MEDIA PLANNING; WILLIARD JM; MGR;-->
<ti>CAMEL: ICON THOUGHTSTYLE.</ti>
<!-- Note:tp:YOUNG ADULT SMOKING-->
<dl>20021018</dl>
<ot>were tested include Upside Magazine (a financial publication); Forbes; Spin, Time, Inc.,
Worth, and Red Herring (financial publication).
• Prototype Research: According to Oglivy &amp; Mather prototype research (based against
GQ and Esquire, 80% male readership, 3.5 readers per copy, 350M total readers), the
following readership has been assigned to the various age breaks:
•Under 18: OM readers, 0% of total readers
•18-24: 115.5M readers, 33% of total readers
•21+: 304.5M readers, 87% of total readers
Please note that a reader survey card will be distributed through the July/August issue
and will include age, gender, lifestyle, and smoking questions.
As this is a special opportunity, we need your approval to run in ICON today. If you need
further information, please call. (For your convenience, we've attached a previous
evaluation of ICON and sample copies.)
g:/media/rjr/cameVicono528
cc: RJRT Agency
Joan Williard Carol Sterling
Liz Eselius
Tonya Tucker
Monica Shelton

pgNbr=1
LRNGHAYMESCARR?CtiEd'SIVG 14RCHANLOISBIVR. P0.60X5621 WINSTNNSALEM.NC 21113 - TEL:9101653630 FAX:910659-0126
MEMORANDUM
~p~'''~~~ I 3~ 197
)
To:	Patti Ittermann v„"
R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. ~ ~
From:
Date:	Sue Kendall
May 28,-19g7 - -	
Y
.Rer CAMEL: ICON Thoughtsfvle~
As discussed, Camel has been offered a gratis 3rd cover page 4c bleed (opposite "Motive"
department) in the July/August (cover August) issue of ICON Thoughtstyle. Although it is
not currently on the RJRT approved list of publications, LHC believes that this publication is
suitable for use by Camel. The reasons are as follows:
1. Editorial Environment.
ICON's subject matter is of interest to males 21+, particularly males 21-44. What's
more, the length of the articles and in-depth nature of the material make this a
publication for someone who wants to be informed and educated, not merely amused.
2. Advertising Environment.
Advertising in the first issues of ICON is geared towards a male 21-44. The list of
advertisers includes Baccardi Rum, Beefeater Gin, Don Tomas Cigars, Jack Daniels,
Tanqueray, Thompson Cigar Co. (direct response), Macanudo Cigars, Brown &amp;
Williamson (Kool, Lucky Strike), IBM Thinkpad (laptop), Halekulani Hotel (Hawaii), Skyy
Vodka, Calvin Klein, Donna Karan Men, Gucci, Ford Explorer, Chrysler Sebring, and
Cadillac Catera.
3. Demograohics/Mailing_Lists and Research.
As ICON is a start-up publication, there is no demographic information available on the
readers. However,/CON states that it is targeted against a 21-44 year old male, with a
core audience of males 25-34. The editorial and advertising environment supports this.
In addition, evidence regarding mailing lists used and research from other sources
indicates that this publication is suitable for males 21-44.
• Mailing List: Per Orien Klein, Account Manager, the only age groups tested were 21-
25, 26-30, 30-35, and 35-40. Under 21 year old names of the various mailing lists
tested were not solicited. Publications/publication companies from which mailing lists

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
