<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aaz98d00</tid>
<bt>50419734/9734</bt>
<ti>JUN HAYASHI, PH.D.  NO. 2081</ti>
<dd>19870310</dd>
<dt>SCIENTIFIC REVIEW</dt>
<au>FELDMAN JD</au>
<rc>HAYASHI J</rc>
<pc>JACOBSON; SCIENTIFIC STAFF; SOMMERS</pc>
<!-- Note:d:APPROVAL, LOW PRIORITY-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>3/10/87 CC: DRS. .TACOBSON,SOMMERS,SCIENTIPIC STAFF
Jun Hayashi, Ph.D.
No. 2081
DESCRIPTION: Hayashi proposes to study the renin-angiotensin system
and kallikrein-kinin system in lymphoid cells and their effect on the
immune system of rats. He has detected renin on the surface of thymocytes
and cites a number of publications that implicate renin-angiotension
systems and kallikrein activators in the development of hypertension and
in the development and differentiation of lymphoid tissue. His protocols:
1. Characterization of thymic and lymph node renin, is it the same as
or similar to renins found in kidney, plasma, and elsewhere?
2. Production of MAbs to detect and isolate active and inactive renin.
3. Six in vitro assays that represent different T cell functions will
be manipulated by use of renin-angiotensin and KKKK reagents to
learn if the latter affect the former.
4. Effect of R-A, KKKK, and their inhibitors, their analogs on the
Tdt+ progenitor lymphoid cells.
Hayashi is a 36-year-old Ph.D., 1981, University of Connecticut in
Developmental Biology. His mentor was Irv Goldschneider who has been
interested in the biology of progenitor lymphoid cells. Since 1983,
Hayashi has been at Alton Jones Cell Science Center as Senior Scientist.
His publications are sparse and total one in JEM with two more submitted.
With the PI is J. W. Crabb, another Senior Scientist at Alton Jones
Center, who will perform some of the,chemical studies and assays.
The budget shows $95,000, $79,000, and $84,000 for first, second, and
third years. Over $20,000 is requested in the first year for permanent
equipment.
CRITIQUE: The study of renin-angiotension and kallikrein-kinin is not
in the mainstream of current immunologic research, and; in fact, it is
a minor eddy in immunopharmacologic research. Hayashi appears to be
continuing in the direction he learned at the University of Connecticut,
and the significance of the proposed experiments for hypertension and
immune system development is derived from fragile data. Hayashi's
productivity in terms of publications is below average. I see very little
in his training to indicate an imaginative scientist at work. The budget
might be reduced by $10,000 (for the visiting Chinese trainee) and by
$20,000 the first year for permanent equipment.
RECOMMENDATION: Approval, low priority.
Joseph D. Feldman, M.D.

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
