<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae15d00</tid>
<bt>505622752/2755</bt>
<rc>DIMARCO GR;RJR</rc>
<au>PUGH DR;RJR</au>
<bx>RJRC1809</bx>
<!-- Note:b:CAMEL NON FILTER 70-->
<pc>DAHNE WD;DUFOUR WM;ESKEW TH;RODGMAN A;STOWE ME;TEAGUE CE;WILLARD RL;RJR;HILDEBOLT WM;HARDIN BV;THREATT HC JR;HAYES AW;PT&amp;D MANAGERS;LC;GCE;I LJI;I JWL;I DLP;I GWW</pc>
<!-- Note:rn t="p":1RFP4-->
<dd>19860403</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<!-- Note:co:Y-->
<np>HAUNI;RJR NABISCO;RJR;STAR WAREHOUSE;ZEISS;BAUSCH &amp; LOMB;NABISCO;DEL MONTE;KFC;VIDEO TEK;SHORE M;STEELMAN H;MACHINE VISION;PRAWTER</np>
<!-- Note:dl:19980227-->
<pg>4</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":MINNESOTA 3RFP2;MOORE 1RFP2;MANGINI COURT ORDER-->
<!-- Note:sh:19960731-->
<!-- Note:s:R&amp;D;BRAND R&amp;D;WALLACE GW;BRAND MGR-->
<ti>WEEKLY HIGHLIGHTS PROCESS TECHNOLOGY &amp; DEVELOPMENT.</ti>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>ReC'd. APR 3 1986 ' LC
. , ' '
t ;,.iO,C%~ -i_ C~.%:fi:, .0
.i
INTER-OFFICE MEMORANDUM
,...., i , ~~ ..,
~ ,
~ nl
April 3, 1986
TO: Dr. G. R. Di Marco
i
SUBJECT: Weekly Highlights
Process Technology &amp; Development
I. ADVANCED PROCESS TECHNOLOGY
• Extraction Investigation
The extraction/spray drying process line in 112 Shed is
operational. Equipment characterization is in progress
and minor modifications are being made as necessary.
Several extended runs, 24 hours or more, are planned in
order to achieve equilibrium operation and develop com-
plete mass balance data. Spray dried extracts are being
evaluated in products. The extracted tobacco is also
being studied to determine its potential uses.
II. PROCESS DEVELOPMENT
• G-7 Pilot Line
Qualification G-7 product has been prepared via the G-7
Pilot Line and will be evaluated against G-7 plant prod-
uct to establish base line parity. Brand R&amp;D and PT&amp;D
have finalized plans for separate extraction G-7 prod-
ucts which will be prepared during April. The plans
consist of 12 products to determine-the influences of
stem, scrap, flue-cured and burley extract.
• Primary Processing Specifications
The strategy for obtaining target and control limits has
been developed. Brand R&amp;D will determine the initial
reject limits for casing, G-13, and top flavor
application.
pgNbr=1
Weekly Hifjhlights - Process Technology &amp; Development
Page 2
~ • Process Development Pilot Line, Star Warehouse
Installation and start-up on the modifications to the
Pilot Line in the Star Warehouse are complete. Testing
runs for Whole Leaf Processing and Air Classification
began on April 1. Besides improvements to the material
handling capability, a major improvement was seen as a
result of the installation of the force feed on the RC-3
cutter. Scrapping and pull outs on the cutter have vir-
tually been eliminated. Minor modifications are planned
to further improve overall operation, e.g. infeed to the
dryer.
III. MECHANICAL &amp; PROCESS CONTROLS DEVELOPMENT
• RJR industries Process Automation Center/
Machine Vision Work
RJR Industries has authorized two headcount for the
Tobacco Company to apply to machine vision development
work which will benefit two or more of the affiliates.
Construction of the PT&amp;D vision/optics lab has begun and
an AR for purchase of a Zeiss image analysis system is
being circulated. It will replace the antiquated Bausch
&amp; Lomb system in R&amp;D.
The second meeting of the Process Automation Center
sponsored by Industries R&amp;D focused on initial project
selection. The first two are vision based and are
generic in nature. The percent stems project for Tobac-
co will address the integration of X-rays, material han-
dling, and machine vision. Opportunities for reapplica-
tion exist at Nabisco, DelMonte, KFC, and Tobacco. A
high speed peanut sorter prototype needs to be in-
dustrialized and evaluated in plant at Nabisco. This
line-scan-based high speed system developed by Video Tek
can also have multiple corporate applications. A longer
term project to establish an intelligent topic-based
electronic mail system was also chosen. The intent is
to facilitate technology transfer between individuals in
all parts of the corporation.
pgNbr=2
Weekly H~yhlights - Process Technology &amp; Development
Page 3
. On-Line Data Monitoring &amp; Display System For Protos
Significant progress is being made in the data monitor-
ing and display system for the Protos 8000 complex. The
objective is to provide color graphic displays of mois-
ture, size, dilution and weight which will help the
operator make machine adjustments to keep product quali-
ty up to specifications. Interfaces between sensors and
computer are now being established. Hauni system sig-
nals are compatible with these interfaces, and elec-
tronic improvements are being made as appropriate. An
I.D.T. color monitor system is being specified which
will provide capability to display data in charts,
graphs, tables, etc. The first system will be demon-
strated in the R&amp;D Pilot Plant by end second quarter. A
long term objective is to close the loop to provide on-
line control of the maker.
VI. SPECIAL PROGRAMS/PROJECTS
. Drying Study
Severe drying of cut filler had been found to reduce its
equilibration moisture level. CAMEL 70 when dried to 4%
moisture reequilibrated to 11.4% moisture while the same
blend when dried to 2% moisture reequilibrated to 10.8%
moisture at 76F, 60% RH. After reordering, the severely
dried product also has a reduced portion of tightly
bound water as measured by NMR and appears to have a
high moisture loss rate.
Discrimination panel evaluation of severely dried CAMEL
70, reequilibrated to 10.8%, a reduced mo,isture product
at the same moisture and a control product at 11.5%
moisture revealed no significant differences.
Based on this and previous panel evaluations, it is con-
cluded that drying produces no direct change in smoking
properties when products are evaluated at comparable
moistures.
All attempts to optimize cut filler drying on the basis
of direct_sensory impact have been discontinued. Future
drying tests will focus on property changes which may
have an.indirect effect on smoking performance such as
filling capacity, moisture retention and uniformity.
pgNbr=3
Weekly H'ghlights - Process Technology &amp; Development
Page 4
PT&amp;D SUPPORT SERVICES
. Pilot Plant •
Assisted project leaders on the following projects:
Cast Sheet, Whole Leaf, FS 2001, G-7 and G-13. Maximum
effort will be spent on G-7 and Whole Leaf the next
eight weeks.
A Prawter grinder has been obtained from Applied R&amp;D for
use on the Cast Sheet project. An input chute and safe-
ty switches will have to be installed before use in our
grinding room.
. Fabrication Shop
Mitch Shore and Harold Steelman have completed training
on the EDM (Electrical Discharge Machining) wire cutting
system.
Personnel training for the control system will be done
in-house this week. The complete system will be opera-
tional during the week of April 14th.
. PT&amp;D Support Lab
Support has been provided for the Turkish conditioning
test through particle size classification. The test was
conducted by Primary Process Engineering at 601 Turkish
and 605,-11.
Dan R. Pugh
DRP: st
xc:	Dr.	W.	M.	Hildebolt
	Mr.	B.	V.	Hardin
	Mr.	H.	C.	Threatt,	Jr.
Dr.	Alan	Rodgman	
Dr.
Dr.	M.
C.	E.
E.	Stowe
Teague,	
Jr.
Dr.
Mr.
Mr.	A.
W.
T.	W.
D.
H.	Hayes
Dahne
Eskew	
PT&amp;D Managers

pgNbr=4
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
