<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aac77e00</tid>
<bt>2062970061/0066</bt>
<dd>19800101/E</dd>
<dt>CONT, CONTRACT, AGREEMENT RESOLUTION</dt>
<dt>FORM, FORM</dt>
<au>DECAMINADO,JP; MACKOWSKI,JJ; MANSFIELD,C; QUINN,GJ</au>
<ca>CENTENNIAL INSURANCE; SCHIFF TERHUNE</ca>
<cr>PM, PHILIP MORRIS</cr>
<!-- Note:si:N530-->
<!-- Note:s:LUTTRELL,JERRY/INSURANCE POLICIES-->
<ti>CERTIFICATE OF EXCESS INSURANCE CERTIFICATE NO: 462 01 99 37</ti>
<pg>6</pg>
<!-- Note:lu:IEYO/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:19990519-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>A
CENTENNIAL INSURANCE COMPANY
45 Wall Street, N.w York, N.Y.
CERTIFICATE OF EXCESS INSURANCE
CERTIFICATE NO: 462 01 99 37
IN CONSIDERATION OF THE PAYMENT OF THE PREMIUM AND SUBJECT TO THE DECLARATIONS,
TERMS AND CONDITIONS HEREOF, THE COMPANY DOES HEREBY INSURE:
DECLARATIONS
ITEM 1. NAMED INSURED:
P.O. ADDRESS:
PHILIP MORRIS, INC.
100 PARK AVE.
NEW YORK, N.Y.
ITEM 2. CERTIFICATE PERIOD:
FROM: 1/1/80 TO: 1/1/81
12:01 A.M. Standard tima at the addrsss of the named insured as stated herein
ITEM 3. PREMIUM•PAYABLE: S 7,000. Total Premium Adjustable at a Rate of
per
Subject to Annual Minimum Premium $
ITEM 4. UNDERLYING INSURANCE:
i
TWENTY FIVE MILLION DOLLARS C$25,000,000.) COMBINED SINGLE LIMIT EACH
OCCURRENCE/ANNUAL AGGREGATE, EXCESS OF PRIMARY.
ITEM 5. DESCRIPTION OF COVERAGE - LIMITS OF LIABILITY HEREUNDER:
FIVE MILLION DOLLARS C$5,000,000.) COMBINED SINGLE LIMIT EACH OCCURRENCE /ANNUAL
AGGREGATE PART OF TWENTY FIVE MILLION DOLLARS ($25,000,000.) COMBINED
SINGLE LIMIT EACH OCCURRENCE/ANNUAL AGGREGATE EXCESS OF TWENTY FIVE MILLION
DOLLARS C$25,000,000.) EXCESS OF PRIMARY.
PREVIOUSCERTIFICATE NO: 462 01 84 85
1/9/80
DATE
PRODUCER: SCHIFF TERHUNE, INC.
COUNTERSIGNED BY
2062970061
Page I of 4
pgNbr=1
TERMS AND CONDITIONS
INSURING AGREEMENTS
1. The Company hereby indemnifres the Insured against ultimate net loss in excess of and arising out of the hazards
covered and as defined and in excess of the underlying insurance as shown in Item 4 of the Declarations (hereinafter referred tc,
as "underlying insurance") but only up to an amount not exceeding the limit(s) shown in Item 5 of the Declarations.
2. Except as may be otherwise stated in this Certificate, the coverage provided by this Certificate shall follow the
insuring agreements, conditions and exclusions of the underlying insurance (whether primary or excess) immediately preceding
the layer of coverage provided by this Certificate, including any change by endorsements. The Company shall be notified of any
change in coverage or premium in such underlying insurance and copies thereof shall be furnished to the Company upon request.
3. The limits of the underlying insurance shall be maintained in full effect during the currency of this Certificate
except for reduction of such limits by exhaustion of aggregate limits (if any) contained therein solely by payment of claims
resulting from accidents or occurrences happening during the period thereof. Failure of the Insured to comply with the foregoing
Shall not invalidate this Certificate, but in the event of such failure the Company shall be liable only to the extent that it would
have been liable had the InsVred complied therewith.
4. Unless aggregate limits are specifically stated in Items 4 and 5 of the Declarations, the coverage provided by this.
Certificate applies only with respect to each accident or occurrence for limits in excess of the amount provided for same in the
underlying insurance and does not apply over any reduced amount of underlying insurance in the event of the exhaustion or
reduction of aggregate limits (if any) in the underlying insurance.
5. If' aggregate limits are specifically stated in Items 4 and 5 of the Declarations, this Certificate will apply in excess of
reduced underlying insurance, provided such reduction in the underlying insurance is solely the result of accidents or occurrences
happening after the inception date of this Certificate. The lnsured shall give the Company written notice as soon as possible of
any reduction or exhaustion of such aggregate limit in the underlying insurance.
6. If more than one insured is named in the Declarations, such additional Insured(s) shall not have the effect of
increasing the Company's limit of liability for each accident or occurrence stated in Item 5 of the Declarations.
PREMIUM
7. Premium due the Company for this excess insurance shall be that amount shown in Item 3 of the Declarations and
is payable upon delivery of this Certificate.
NOTICE OF LOSS
8. The Insured shall immediately advise the Company of any accident or occurrence which appears likely to result ir
liability under thh Certificate and of subsequent developments likely to affect the Company's liability hereunder. At no time
shall the Company be called upon to assume charge of the settlement or defense of any claims made or suits brought or
proceedings instituted against the Insured, but the Company shall have the right and shall be given the opportunity to associate
with the Insured or its underlying insurer or insurers, or both, in the control, defense and/or trial of any claims, suits or
proceedings which, in the opinion of the Company involves or appears reasonably likely to involve the Company. If the
Company avails itself of such right or opportunity, the Insured, any underlying insurer or insurers and the Company shall
cooperate in the control, defense and/or trial of such claims, suits or proceedings, so as to affect a final determination thereof.
Failure on the part of the Insured to cooperate shall relieve the Company, at its option, of liability under this Certificate.
9. The Insured shall be solely responsible for the investigation, settlement, defense and final disposition of any claim
made or suit brought or proceeding instituted against the Insured to which this Certificate would apply and which no underlying
insurer or insurers is obligated to defend. The Insured shall use due diligence and prudence to settle all such claims and suits
which in the exercise of sound judgment should be settled, provided, however, that the Insured shall not make or agree to any
settlement for any sum, in excess of the underlying insurance, without the approval of the Company.
10. The Insured shall (a) cooperate with the underlying insurer or insurers, as required by the terms of the underlying
insurance, (b) comply with all the terms and conditions thereof and (c) enforce any right of contribution or indemnity against
any person or organization who may be liable to the Insured, because of liability with respect to which insurance is afforded
under this Certificate and the underlying insurance.
LOSS PAYABLE
11. The Company's obligation to pay any ultimate net loss and costs with respect to any accident or occurrence failing
within the terms of this Certificate shall not attach until the amount of the applicable underlying limit has been paid by or on
behalf of the Insured on account of such accident or occurrence. The Insured shall make claim for any ultimate net loss and
costs under this Certificate as soon as practical after, (a) the Insured shall have paid ultimate net loss in excess of the underlying
limit, with respect to any accident or occurrence, or (b) the Insured's obligation to pay such amounts shall have been finalhy
determined, either by judgment against the Insured after actual trial or by written agreement of the Insured, the claimant and
the Company.
ULTIMATE NET LOSS AND COSTS
12. "Ultimate net loss", as used herein, shall be understood to mean the sums paid in settlcment of losses for which the
Insured is liable after making deductrons for all recoveries, salvages and other insurances (cithc•r than rerove•nes under the
underlying rnsurance, policies c,f ccrinsurance, or policies specifically in excess hereot), whether recoverable or not• and shall
exclude all "custs",
F'aq,r 2 uf 4
2062970062
pgNbr=2
13. The word "costs", as used herein, shall be understood to mean interest on judgments, investigation, adjustment and
legal expenses including taxes, court costs and premiums on bonds, for which the Insured is not covered by the underlying
insurance excluding, however, (a) all expenses for salaried employees and counsel on general retainer, (b) all office expenses of
the Insured, and (c) regular fees paid to counsel on general retainer.
14. Costs incurred by the insured, with the written consent of the Company, shall be apportioned as follows:
(a) in the event of claim or suit arising which appears likely to exceed the underlying insurance limit or limits, no
costs shall be incurred by the Insured without the written consent of the Company.
(b) should such claim or suit be settled previous to going into court for not more than the underlying insurance
limit or limits, then no costs shall be payable by the Company.
(c) should, however the sum for which the said claim or suit may be settled exceed the underlying insurance limit
or limits, then the Company, if it approves such settlement or consents to the proceedings continuing, shall
contribute to the costs incurred by the Insured in the ratio that its proportion of the ultimate net loss as
finally adjusted bears to the whole amount of such ultimate net loss.
(d) in the event the Insured elects not to appeal a judgment in excess of the underlying insurance limit or limits,
the Company may elect to conduct such appeal at its own cost and expense and shall be liable for the taxable
court costs and interest incidental thereto, but in no event shall the total liability of the Company exceed its
limit or limits of liability as stated above, plus the costs of such appeal.
(e) in the event a judgment is rendered in excess of the underlying insurance limit or limits and the underlying
insurer or insurers elect.to appeal such judgment, the duty of obtaining an appeal bond in regard to liability in
excess of the underlying insurance limit or limits shall rest with the Insured and its underlying insurer or
insu re rs.
SUBROGATION AND SALVAGE
15. All salvages, recoveries or payments recovered or received subsequent to a settlement under this Certificate shall be
applied as if recovered or received prior to such settlement and all necessary adjustments shall then be made between the Insured and
the Company, provided always that nothing in this clause shall be construed to mean that losses under this Certificate are not
recoverable until the Insured's ultimate net loss has been finally ascertained.
16. Inasmuch as this Certificate is Excess Insurance, the Insured's right of recovery against any person cannot be
exclusively subrogated to the Company. It is, therefore, understood and agreed that in case of any Payment hereunder, the
Company will act in concert with all other parties (including the Insured) concerned, in the exercise of such rights of recovery. The
apportioning of any amounts which may be so recovered shall follow the principle that any parties (including the Insured) that shall
have paid an amount over and above any payment hereunder, shall first be reimbursed up to the amount paid by them, the Company
is then to be reimbursed out of any balance then remaining up to the amount paid hereunder; lastly the parties (including the
Insured) of whom this coverage is in excess are entitled to claim the residue, if any. Expenses necessary to the recovery of any such
amounts shall be apportioned between the parties (including the Insured) concerned, in the ratio of their respective recoveries as
finally settled.
17. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to mean that the Insured shall be required to enforce by legal action any
right of subrogation or indemnity before the Company shall pay any loss covered hereunder.
TERM
18. The Certificate applies only to accidents or occurences happening during the certificate period shown in Item 2 of the
-Declarations, unless otherwise cancelled.
NUCLEAR INCIDENT EXCLUSION
19. It is agreed that this Certificate does not apply: 2062970063
I. Under any Liability Coverage, to injury, sickness, disease, death or destruction
(a) with respect to which an insured under this Certificate is also an Insured under a nuclear energy liability policy
issued by Nuclear Energy Liability Insurance Association, Mutual Atomic Energy Liability Underwriters or
Nuclear Insurance Association of Canada, or would be an insured under any such policy but for its termination
upon exhaustion of its limit of liability; or °
(b) resulting from the hazardous properties of nuclear material and with respect to which (1) any person or
organization is required to maintain financial protection pursuant to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, or any law
amendatory thereof, or (2) the insured is, or had this policy not been issued would be, entitled to indemnity from
the United States of America, or any agency thereof, under any agreement entered into by the United States of
America, or any agency thereof, with any person or organization.
II. Under any Liability Coverage, to injury, sickness, disease, death or destruction resulting from the hazardous properties
of nuclear material, if
(a) the nuclear material (1) is at any nuclear facility owned by, or operated by or on behalf of, an insured or (2) has
been discharged or dispersed therefrom;
Page3of4
20 4339B (3/77)
pgNbr=3
t
(h) the nuclear material is contained in spent fuel or waste at any time possessed, handled, used, processed, stored,
transported or disposed of by or on behalf of any insured; or
(c) the injury, sickness, disease, death or destruction arises out of the furnishing by an insured of services, materials,
parts or equipment in connection with the planning, construction, maintenance, operation or use of any nuclear
facility, but if'such facility is located within the United States of America, its territories or possessions or Canada,
this exclusion (c) applies only to injury to or destruction of property at such nuclear facility.
Ill. As used herein:
"itazardous properties" include radioactive, toxic or explosive properties; "nuclear material" means source material,
special nuclear material or byproduct material; "source material", "special nuclear material", and "byproduct material"
have the meanings given them in the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 or in any law amendatory thereof; "spent fuel" means
any fuel element or fuel comp":ent, solid or liquid, which has been used or exposed to radiation in a nuclear reactor;
"waste" means any waste material (1) containing byproduct material and (2) resulting from the operation by any person
or organization of any nuclear facility included within the definition of nuclear facility under paragraph (a) or (b)
thereof; "nuclear facility" means
(a) any nuclear reactor,
(b) any equipment or device designed or used for (I) separating the isotopes of uranium or plutonium, (2) processing
or utilizing spent fuel, or (3) handling, processing or packaging waste,
(c) any equipment or device used for the processing, fabricating or alloying of special nuclear material if at any time
the total amount of such material in the custody of the insured at the premises where such equipment or device is
located consists of or contains more than 25 grams of plutonium or uranium 233 or any combination thereof, or
more than 250 grams of uranium 235,
(d) any structure, basin, excavation, premises or place prepared or used for the storage or disposal of waste,
and includes the site on which any of the foregoing is located, all operations conducted on such site and all premises
used for such operations; "nuclear reactor" means any apparatus designed or used to sustain nuclear fission in a
self•supporting chain reaction or to contain a critical mass of fissionable material;
With respect to injury to or destruction of property, the word "injury" or "destruction" includes all forms of radio-
active contamination of property.
CANCE LLATION
20. This Cef tiftcate may be cancelled at any time at the written notice of the Insured or may be cancelled by or on behalf of
the Company provided thirty (30) days written notice is given to the Insured at the address shown in the Declarations. The mailing
of notice as aforesaid shall be sufficient proof of notice. The effective date of cancellation stated in the notice shall become the end
of the certificate period. However, in the event of cancellation or non-renewal of the underlying insurance immediately preceding
this Certificate, this Certificate terminates as of the same date without notice to the Insured. If the Insured cancels, earned premium
shall be computed on a short rate basis, and if cancelled by the Company, adjustment shall be pro-rata. Notice by the Company to
the first named Insured, if more than one, shall be deemed notice to any other interests included as an Insured.
IN WITNESS WHEREOF The Company has caused this Certificate to be signed by its President and Secretary, but same
shall not be binding upon the Company unless countersigned on the Declarations page by an authorized representative of the Company.
PrAsid.nt
?7_11 PN-&lt;&lt;-._._.,,~.•_
s.cr.t,.y
pgNbr=4
Ejjective -1 /1 /80 this endorsement forms a part of Policy No. 462 01 99 9 7
(At the time stated in the policy)
issued to Phi lip Morris Inc.
by Centennia 1 Insurance Company
(The information provided for above is required to be completed only when this
endorsement is issued for attachment to the policy subsequent to its effective date.)
It is agreed that Item 1 Named Insured is amended to read:
Philip Morris Incorporated and its Affiliated and
Subsidiary Companies and Corporations now existing=
or hereafter created or acquired.
GJQ:sh
4/10/80
All other terms and conditions of this insurance remain unchanged.
G1690B I1/791
~" P~re~sident
ENDORSEMENT
i
2062970065
pgNbr=5
G16900 (V791
Effective , this endorsement forms a part of Policy No.
(At the time stated in the policy)
issued ta
by Insurance Company ENDORSEMENT
(The information provided forabove is required to be completed only when this
endorsement is issued for attachment to the policy subsequent to its effective date.)
EXCLUSION OF HEALTH HAZARD
THIS POLICY DOES NOT APPLY TO BODILY INJURY, SICKNESS, DISEASE OR
DEATH (CAUSED, OR) ALLEGED TO HAVE BEEN CAUSED, IN WHOLE OR IN PART,
BY CONTINUOUS OR REPEATED, USE OF ANY TOBACCO OR TOBACCO PRODUCTS,
MANUFACTURED, SOLD, HANDLED OR DISTRIBUTED BY THE NAMED INSURED,
THE WORDS "TOBACCO" OR TOBACCO PRODUCTS" AS USED HEREIN INCLUDES ANY
SUBSTANCE OR INGREDIENT USED IN OR A PART OF ANY TOBACCO OR TOBACCO
PRODUCT AND, ALSO INCLUDES ANY PRODUCT OF WHICH ANY TOBACCO OR TOBACCO
PRODUCT IS A COMPONENT PART.
c
All other terms and conditions of this insurance remain unchanged.
1"41 r
President
C'
----- ----- --- ---
Author. '°. Representativ,
pgNbr=6
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
