<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aac79d00</tid>
<bt>500555227/5232</bt>
<rc>LARSON KH</rc>
<au>TRAKTMAN D;BBDO</au>
<bx>RJR2018</bx>
<!-- Note:b:WINSTON LIGHTS 100;CAMEL LIGHTS 100;VANTAGE 100;MARLBORO;PARLIAMENT;BENSON &amp; HEDGES;VIRGINIA SLIMS;MERIT ;PALL MALL;TAREYTON;VICEROY;RALEIGH;KENT;L&amp;M;LARK-->
<pc>RJR;COX A;FOUGHT DG;STRAWSBURG S;DAVIS S;BBDO;NEMAN T;PRINGLE L;ROGERS K;SALZBERG R;HAWKINS FH</pc>
<dd>19800227</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<!-- Note:co:N-->
<np>STUART J;F KRIS</np>
<!-- Note:dl:19980227-->
<pg>6</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":MINNESOTA 1RFP93;MANGINI COURT ORDER-->
<!-- Note:sh:19960930-->
<!-- Note:s:MARKETING-->
<ti>LAST FRIDAY, WE DISCUSSED USING QUALITATIVE RESEARCH TO ENHANCE OUR UNDERSTANDING OF THE PRIME PROSPECT FOR S1.</ti>
<!-- Note:tp:YOUNG ADULT SMOKING-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>BBDO
Batten, Barton, Durstine &amp; Osborn, Inc.
383 Madison Avenue, NewYork, N.Y.10017, Te1. 212-355 5800, Cable Address BEBEDEOH, Telex 224320
RESEAIiC H
DFPAfCI7rtFNT
February 27, 1980
Ms. Kristine H. Larson
Marketing Research Department
R. J. Reynolds Tobacco, Inc.
Fourth and Main Streets
Winston-Salem, No. Carolina	



7102
Dear Kris:	
Last Friday, we discussed using qualitative research to en-
hance our understanding of the prime prospect for S1.
Specifically, now that there is general agreement that Sl
must appeal to current smokers of fuller flavor low tar
100mm brands, we concur with Jim Stuart that it is important
to learn more about this smoker group. Whereas most past S1
research focussed on smoking behavior and attitudes, the
emphasis now shifts to the general attitudes, beliefs and
behavior of our prime prospect. Qualitative research should
provide an initial reading on any common attitudinal or be-
havioral traits which characterize these smokers; this in
turn will assist in developing advertising most calculated
to induce trial of S1.
To begin, we recommend that four focus group sessions be con-
ducted among current 100mm FFLT smokers. In the interest of
clear and meaningful discussions, we further recommend that
these initial groups be limited to.female smokers of non-menthol
FFLT 100mm cigarettes, aged 25-54, high school graduates, annual
family income $15,000+. Two of the groups should consist of
working women.
Beginning qualitative work with the focus groups recommended
has several advantages. First, our Boston and Miami experi-
ence indicates that the interplay of a group session is ex-
tremely valuable to creative personnel in getting to know the
prime prospect. In addition, we will be able to refine and
P
pgNbr=1
. BBDO
Bate,artor,W=r* bOsbcm Inc
- 2 - February 27, 1980
revise our initial hypotheses and questioning areas from group
to group. Once these groups are completed and analyzed,
further groups (for example, among men or menthol smokers) may
be indicated. In addition, we may well want to capitalize on
our initial learning by later conducting potentially even more
valuable, but less economical and more time-consuming, one-on-
one depth interviews among prime prospect smokers.
Accurate respondent screening is crucial; we feel strongly that
this be the prime criterion in choosing a facility for these
groups. Of course, screening should cover the following areas:
present brand smoked (non-menthol: Camel Lights 100; Winston
Lights 100; Vantage 100's; Marlboro Lights 100; Parliament
Light..100; B&amp;H Light 100's; Virginia Slim Lights; Merit 100's;
Pall Mall Light 100; Tareyton Lights 100; Viceroy Rich Light
100; Raleigh Light 100; Kent 100; Golden Lights 100; L&amp;M Lites
100; Lark Light 100); length of time with present brand (to in-
sure the inclusion of only relatively settled FFLT 100mm
smokers, a minimum of 3 months); previous brand smoked; age
(accurate screening essential); education; income. Because
group discussions will be limited to non-cigarette issues,
screening should include questioning in at least one other
product category. This will mask the smoking selection criteria.
In addition, the groups should be held in a high 100mm develop-
ment area to expedite screening (for example, Dallas, Houston
or St. Louis).
It will be important in this research to explore the validity
of initial hypotheses•regarding the FFLT 100mm smoker. These
hypotheses include:
That the trade-off, modification behavior ex-
hibited in the choice of a cigarette of this
type is echoed in other brand, product or life-
style choices.
. That brand choices in other product categories
reflect common self-image and lifestyle wants.
. That there are common elements to the type of
"style" desired and admired by this group...
that this style may best be described by terms
such as modern; up-to-date; active, but not
trendy; relatively informal; tailored.
. That prime prospects' own lifestyles echo these
style elements in areas such as leisure activities,
entertainment/entertaining, vacations.
. That brand loyalties across non-cigarette product
areas exhibit common characteristics.
Gu+ 1116
pgNbr=2
BBDO
8xicti Bwrtm Qrswx &amp; Qsban inc
3 - February 27, 1980
That brand switching and behavioral/attitu-
dinal changes are induced under similar
circumstances and are responsive to similar
stimuli, across product and lifestyle areas.
. That there is a tension/relaxation/reward
nexus common to these smokers.
To this end, the following areas of questioning are suggested:
Trade-off/modification mentality
Explore brand/product choices:in areas of
. automobiles
. sof t drinks
. coff ee sweeteners/lighteners
Explore behavior in areas of
. life decisions. (marriage/career
(job)/family)
. personal style (wardrobe, hairstyle,
etc.)
. food (family meal planning, dieting,
cholesterol,nitrates, etc.)
Explore brand choices in:
. perfume/cologne
. cosrrietics
- treatment products (e.g.
moisturizer)
- makeup
. alcoholic beverages (including
wine, beer)
(Emphasis on status vs. functionality issue)
Explore any recent brand changes
emphasis on reasons for change
(dissatisfaction vs. novelty)
. perceived differences in brand
chosen/rejected
Explore product/lifestyle areas in which
dissatisfaction exists/no successful
solution has been found
. What is missing? Unsatisfactory?
. What are desired aspects of
solution?
Gen 1116
pgNbr=3
BBDO
eatter; esrtrt arsbne a osbmn. Nc
4 - February 27, 1980
Personal style
Explore brands, possessions, personal
choices, admired figures, which define
desired style.
. if I asked you to describe yourself
to me and you couldn't use any words
but instead had to show me any f ive
products you use, which five would
you show me? Why? (To be written,
then discussed)
(Repeat for f ive" things you own" )
. if I were to give you $500 and you
could do anything you wanted with it,,
what would you do with it or use it
for? Why?
(Repeat specif ically for a home
furnishings purchase and for clothing)
. can you think of a woman in the enter-
tainment field who you particularly
admire? Who and why?
(Repeat for other female public
f igure s )
Lif estyle
Explore leisure activities, hobbies, enter-
tainment/entertaining, vacations.
. What sports, hobbies, etc. do you
most enjoy? (Probe, especially for
spectator vs. participant)
. What is your idea of a great evening
out?
(Probe, especially for types of enter-
tainment, restaurants preferred)
. When you entertain at home, what sort
of get-togethers are most common?
(Probe issues of formality vs. in-
formality, setting or room, meal
vs. other occasions)
. What was your most enjoyable vacation
in recent years? (Probe When? Where?
Who? Formality/Informality•Activities)
.^,en 1116
pgNbr=4
5 - February 27, 1980
Tension/relaxation/reward
Explore recent episodes of heightened ten-
sion/relaxation/reward behavior.
. can you think of a particular time
during the last few days when you
were especially tense, hassled or
upset?
what happened?
how did you cope?
what did you do right af ter
this period?
. can you think of a situation during
the past several days when you were
particularly relaxed -- even for a
short period?
what were the circumstances?
who were you with?
. can you think of an example during
the past week or two when you gave
yourself a reward, or bought your-
self a present, or did something
nice just for yourself?
what did you do?
what were you rewarding your-
self for?
how did you feel afterward?
Belief/Skepticism/Change of Mind
Explore belief structure, flexibility,
stimuli for change.
. would you describe yourself generally
as a believer or a skeptic? Why?
. generally, is it hard or easy for you
to make decisions, or make up your
mind about something? Can you give
me an example?
. once you've made up your mind or made
a decision, is it generally easy or
difficult to change your decision or
your mind?
pgNbr=5
- 6 - February 27, 1980
can you think of a time re-
cently when you changed your
mind about:
• something?
• someone?
what happened? Why did you
change your mind? How did
you f eel af terwards?
can you think of a recent ex-
ample of a decision you made
which you later reversed? What
happened? Why?
Advertising Approaches
Explore several different approaches used
a similar type of product.
for
perfume/cologne
automobiles
coffee
- Ernphasis on approaches relying heavily on
either
• comparisons/hard facts
• positive self-image
We reiterate that these groups should be limited to non-cigar-
ette questioning areas. Of course, further review may yield
revisions, additions and deletions from this suggested outline.
However, the above questions are designed to elicit the
attitudinal, behavioral and lifestyle information required.
Kris, we look forward to your comments on these recommendations.
We are enthusiastic about the opportunity this research will pro-
vide to gain a better understanding of S1's prime prospect for
marketing and creative development.
/ '-
'
=
'
C.
V
-
K
David Traktman
Research Associate
cc: RJR Tobacco: A. Cox, D.G. Fought, S. Strawsburg
BBDO: S. Davis, F.H. Hawkins, T. Neman, L. Pringle,
K. Rogers, R. Salzberg
pgNbr=6
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
