<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aay00d00</tid>
<bt>50357405/7405</bt>
<ti>INTERFERONS AND 2-5A EXPRESSION IN ALZHEIMER'S DISEASE FIBROBLASTS</ti>
<dd>19910000</dd>
<dt>SCIENTIFIC REVIEW</dt>
<au>KARNOVSKY M, CTR; WU JM</au>
<pc>CTR STAFF; FELDMAN; MCALLISTER; PIERCE</pc>
<!-- Note:d:APPLICATION IS VERY DIFFICULT FOR ME TO COMPREHEND AND IS SOMEWHAT BEYOND MY KEN-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>9/20/91 CC:DRS.FELDMAN,PIERCE,McALLISTER,CTR STAFF
MANFRED KARNOVSKY, PH.D.
The Council for Tobacco Research - U.S.A., Inc. Y 1991
• Grant Application No. 2384A
Joseph M. WU, Ph.D.
•
•
Title. Interferons and 2-5A Expression in Alzheimer's Disease Fibroblasts
Critiaue. This application is very difficult for me to comprehend, and is
somewhat beyond my ken. On the other hand, it deals with a very topical
matter, and the author, to judge from his publication list, is having some
success with the problem. This current application focusses on methylation
of DNA in control and Alzheimer's cells. To this end, the authors will also
employ some drugs, such as azacytidine and ethionine. Finally, they will
characterize proteins that bind specifically to CpGs in control and AD cells
with or without interferon treatment. The overall aspect would be to
investigate the role of DNA methylation in determining gene expression in
Alzheimer cells using the differential expression of 2-5A synthetase gene
between control and AD cells as the model system.
My general impressioh was that this was a moderately OK application,
and looking at Table I of the Progress Report, it seems to me that the
effects observed are real, but not cataclysmic.
When I examined Dr. Wu's most recently supplied additional data, I
notee that the papers that were previously reported as being submitted to
the J. Biol. Chem., are now accepted for Biochemistry International.
Putting aside my hope that this application represents a crack in the
AD conundrum, I would give this a ranking of about 2 for merit, and a
3 for relevance, on a scale of 1 is excellent to 5 is terrible.
CTR-CONFIDENTIAL SUBJECT TO P.O. IN US v. PM ET AL. 99CV2496 (SCIENTIFIC PEER-REVIEW MATERIAL)

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
