<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aax05a00</tid>
<bt>529202081/2086</bt>
<rc>LEARY NC</rc>
<au>FAINO C; MARKETING OPERATIONS</au>
<bx>NA</bx>
<!-- Note:b:CAMEL; DORAL; SALEM; WINSTON; WINSTON 85; WINSTON LIGHTS 85-->
<pc>MICHALEK JJ; LOZANO CJ; FAGAN MG; HOLBROOK TM; WILSON SB; BLACKMER E; HUNTER CS; KNOUSE PF JR; ITTERMANN PF; ZIESEMER PL; TUCKER B; LEARY NC</pc>
<dd>19970721</dd>
<dt>EMAIL; LETTER; REPORT</dt>
<!-- Note:co:N-->
<np>KNOUSE PF JR; LOZANO CJ; MICHALEK JJ; FAINO C; HUNTER CS; BLACKMER E; WILSON SB</np>
<!-- Note:br t="o":RJR 417107986; 70032 1681-1686-->
<!-- Note:dl:20040624-->
<pg>6</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 443; US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 287; US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 338; US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 385; US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 444; US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 449; US COMPREHENSIVE REQUEST 450-->
<!-- Note:sh:NA-->
<!-- Note:s:USDOJ; PRODUCTION 15-23; CD; ;-->
<ti>1998 (19980000) WINSTON DATABASE MARKETING PLAN.</ti>
<dl>20040715</dl>
<ot>From: Tucker, Bonnie
To: Lcary, Ned C.
CC: Zicscmer, Phil L.; Blackmer, Ed; Fagan, Mike G.; Holbrook, Todd M.; Hunter,
Cindi S.; Itlermann, Patti F.; Knouse, Paul F.; Lozano, Cressida J.; Michalek, Joseph J.;
Wilson, Susie B.
BCC:
Primary Date: 7/21/1997 4:58:02 PM
Last Modified I)ate: 2001-Nov-20 17:13:45
Last Touched Date:
Sent Date: ] 997-Jul-21 16:58:00
Received Date: ] 997-Jul-21 16:58:02
Subject: 1998 Winston Database Marketing Plan
Attachments:
\\'INST'n1yIL.DOC
Ned,
Please review attached document. We need your feedback by Monday,
July 28.
Thanks, Cal
RJR0000000417107986
70032 1681

pgNbr=1
5 March, 2002
Cressida Lozano
Joe Michalek
® Competitive Trial Program: As you know, the soon to be implemented competitive trial mailing
will go to 175M "best bets" in the top 2 deciles, based on prior modeling efforts. An additional
significant opportunity remains to deliver the same program to "good bets" -- those smokers in
deciles 3 through 6 -- and thus reach an additional 400M competitive smokers. Combined with
this year's plan, this program would yield a total of 305M responders for sustaining efforts.
In Summary....
Overall, when you step back and look at what WINSTON has got to do, it is this: (1) Get competitive
smokers on board with the "new WINSTON" ; and (2) Hold onto a highly valuable, but older and
price-sensitive, franchise in the face of significant changes to their brand and enormous price
increases -- both happening at the same time. Losing part of the franchise is an inevitable part of
these changes, we know. But these losses could be catastrophic if we do not reinforce their
commitment to us by acknowledging and demonstrating our commitment to them.
Secondly, and as a pragmatic consideration, the competitive database universe for WINSTON is
substantial. Failure to take advantage of this opportunity will not only minimize the Brand's growth
potential, but also will result in these smokers being released to other brands who WILL use them.
I'll follow up with you later today to get your thoughts on this recommendation.
Paul
P. F. Knouse, Jr.
PFKJR/mg
RJR0000000417107986
' 70032 1686

pgNbr=2
Ned Leary
Page two
July 21, 1997
However, WINSTON is significantly underutilizing the smokers available to it on the Active
Mailing List. At the same time, CAMEL and DORAL need additional smokers for their
1997/1998 programs. If database marketing is not going to play a significant role in
WINSTON's 1998 plans, we need to reallocate AML smokers accordingly.
Under these circumstances, WINSTON should not do any branded "name generation." This
will free up additional Brand spending for other programs. Also, we will reduce the Database
Marketing Group's '98 Operating Budget as appropriate.
Once we make these changes, we effectively remove database marketing as an option for
WINSTON in the near term. If we change our minds, it will take a minimum of two years to re-
build WINSTON's database marketing capabilities to their current level.
Please advise by Monday, July 28.
Cal
Cal M. Faino
Marketing Operations
CMF/bmt
Attachment
cc: Mr. Joe Michalek
Ms. Cressida Lozano
Mr. Mike Fagan
Mr. Todd Holbrook
Ms. Susie Wilson
Mr. Ed Blackmer
Ms. Cindi Hunter
Mr. Paul Knouse
Ms. Patti Ittermann
Mr. Phil Ziesemer
RJR0000000417107986
700321683

pgNbr=3
5 March, 2002
Cressida Lozano
Joe Michalek
Targeting Rationale
® Competitive Availabilities &amp; Targeting: Recommended programs will reach a significant portion
of W INSTON available competitive smoker bank - 73% , reaching beyond "best bets" to
encompass "good bets" (those in deciles 3-6). Secondarily, and in addition to this obvious
resource and opportunity, you should also recognize that any smokers W INSTON does not use in
its programs will be RELEASED to other brands. DORAL (especially) and CAMEL are chomping
at the bit to get as many smokers as they can.
® WINSTON Franchise Targeting: I strongly recommend that programs reach ALL OF THE
WINSTON FRANCHISE, 21+. Consider that we are changing practically EVERYTHING about
WINSTON: packaging, advertising and product. We all believe in these changes and support
them, but we want the franchise to ACCEPT them as well. Moreover, price increases sometime
next year (possibly early in the year) will raise the carton price by as much as $10, perhaps even
more depending on what individual states do. These changes are hitting EVERY FRANCHISE
SMOKER, not iust 21-49. We need to talk to them all!
Program Rationale
® Quarterly Magazine: The magazine addresses the positioning reinforcement objective head-on,
providing an excellent opportunity to communicate and dimensionalize the positioning to adult
smokers. In addition to getting competitive smokers to adopt the brand, the magazine will also
serve to provide added value to the WINSTON franchise. Importantly, the magazine will provide
the ONLY OPPORTUNITY to deliver the positioning in color via direct marketing, once the
regulations are in effect. We also need to establish our subscription during the 1st Half of the
year. A further key point is that the magazine can also be distributed at various restricted-access
events (retail, at-event, etc.).
® Franchise Loyalty Reinforcement Program: The objective of this program is to communicate
with and show support for the franchise in the face of significant price increases. We want loyalty
from our franchise; we also need to show our loyalty to THEM. We know that we cannot fully nor
indefinitely cover these price increases, even with GAP funds. The $2.00 coupon in this mailing
serves only to demonstrate our commitment -- what we say to the franchise is more important
than the coupon. The relationship with the smoker is what counts. We should keep this program
"on the shelf" for when the prices rise.
® 1st Quarter Volume: I recommend reserving funds for a targeted, incremental 1 st Quarter
volume program as we have "traditionally" done in the past several years. Results from this year's
program confirm that THE MOST VOLUME EFFICIENT OPPORTUNITY is to focus on
responders to prior WINSTON programs.
RJR0000000417107986
700321685

pgNbr=4
5 March, 2002
TO: Cressida Lozano; Joe Michalek
FROM: Paul F. Knouse, Jr.
CC: Cal Faino; Cindi Hunter; Ed Blackmer; Susie Wilson
RE: 1998 WINSTON General Market Direct Marketina
Recommendations
Following our various planning meetings, this confirms my recommended general market direct
marketing programs for WINSTON in 1998. I recommend plan spending of $17.8MM in support
of key competitive smokers as well as the entire WINSTON franchise. This recommendation is
based on what I see to be key objectives for the plan; the recommended plan is also summarized
below.
Objectives
1 Communicate and reinforce WINSTON's positioning, with the goal of competitive
adoption and franchise acceptance of the "new WINSTON".
2 Reinforce franchise loyalty in the face of significant price increases.
3 Position WINSTON to compete effectively in a changing marketing environment.
Recommendation
Priority	_ _ Proaram __ _.__	Smokers	Budaet
	~	_ _-	-- -

_ 1	Quarterly WINSTON Magazine to competitive
and fr-anc_hise smokers ~
-Com etitive 21-49	

1,5400	
_	_Franchise, 21	1 000	
	-Total	2 540	8 900

!
2 -	Loyalty Reinforcement Program to WINSTON
franchise at price Increase tlmel: $2 coupon
--		
	-Franchise 21 +	1,000	15 50

3 I	1st Quarter Volume Program to competitive
smokers (343.00 cou ons		
I	-Competitive responders 21+	330', $	2 000


4	Trial Program to competitive "good bets"
(deciles 3-6) - 3 mallings: 2 free packs + get 4
more (same tactics as '97 ro ram	-	

--	-Competitive "good bets" 21+	__ 350 $	-3,375
-
	[projected res onders 50%	175	
	Overhead (Name processing, agency,
bouncebacks Consumer Relations etc.		
2 00
	TOTAL PLAN		17.82. 0
RJR0000000417107986
700321684

pgNbr=5
July21, 1997
TO: Mr. Ned Leary
FROM: Mr. Cal Faino
RE: 1998 WINSTON DATABASE MARKETING PLAN
I have reviewed Paul's recommendations for WINSTON's'98 database marketing plan. I
consider these recommendations to be the minimum needed for database marketing to play a
meaningful role in helping WINSTON achieve its objectives.
If WINSTON's '98 plans envision a lesser role for database marketing, I believe that Brand
resources would be better spent on expanding other programs.
We currently spend significant resources to acquire and maintain qualified smokers on the
Active Mailing List for WINSTON. These efforts provide WINSTON with a significant database
marketing capability.
Active Mailing List
f'(lOPfLC . •.. ~ . .`i. ;. . m.. . .~ I
	21-34 35-49	50+ TOTAL
Wttda~Tt1N				
Franchise	1o7,b2U	»Ua,bUU	444,yi0	1,U1b,?~:3i;
Competitive	753,205	684,484	518,522	1,956,211
&amp; ~
Franchise	
598,916	
592,926	
265,213	
1,457,05:7
Competitive	675,113	532,892	112,756	1,320,761
,~,~
S~F
"`		\g	w ..._v,. ..a~~o~~~~.~	~oti.~e:
~
,;
Franchise	
97,769	
269,755	
264,314	
031,85&amp;
				
Competitive	170,570	281,204	163,584	615,35t~

DORAI	
~	

E &amp;	

a	a
.
~a
		„~, .,,
,	.,.~,.~,... , ,u,.	~
,.~..
Franchise	237,668	525,350	532,806	1,2i?5,824
Competitive	272,880	511,194	497,589	1,2B1,n6;.t
... .,.....,,
`
~....	
....~.~.~,~....	
,~. .~..,..w...a
r .	
y"M.~.~~..,...~,.	.. .
,...~.,...~,.............\..

\.u		~ . ...	. $	:. . . . .
Franchise	24,662	107,368	196,445	3s:4~,Lir::
Competitive	437,541	726,255	674,773	1,838,569
Franchise	1,126,355	1,898,999	1,703,748	4,729,102
Competitive	2,309,309	2336,029	1,967,224	7,012,562
TOTAL/TOTAL	3,435,664	4,635,028	3,670,972	11,741,664
RJR0000000417107986
700321682

pgNbr=6
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
