<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aae32c00</tid>
<bt>2070370328/0342</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="m":2070370327/0342-->
<dd>19930315</dd>
<dt>CONT, CONTRACT, AGREEMENT RESOLUTION</dt>
<ca>DETROIT TIGERS; PHILIP MORRIS INCORPORATED</ca>
<no>ADVERTISERS PANEL; CITY OF DETROIT; DETROIT BASEBALL CLUB; DETROIT TIGERS; FOX THEATER; JOE LOUIS ARENA; JOHN E FETZER; MEADOW BROOK; PHILIP MORRIS COMPANIES INC; PHILIP MORRIS INCORPORATED; PMUSA, PHILIP MORRIS USA; ROYAL OAK THEATER</no>
<fn>2070369956/2070370470/MISSING</fn>
<!-- Note:si:N725-->
<!-- Note:s:CAPREOL,GARY/CARLSTADT-->
<ti>ADVERTISING AGREEMENT</ti>
<pg>15</pg>
<!-- Note:lu:FEDA/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:20021119-->
<!-- Note:b:MARLBORO-->
<dl>20030115</dl>
<ot>• IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the parties hereto have caused this agreement to be duly
executed as of the date and year first above written.
DETROIT TIGERS, INC. PHILIP MORRIS INCORPORATED
By: By:
Title: Title:
Taxpayer ID#
Filing Status
is
N
0
v
. o
w
15- o
w
.p
K)

pgNbr=1
•
ADVERTISING AGREEMENT
This agreement (the "Agreement"), is entered into as of the 15th day of March, 1993,
between Philip Morris Incorporated, a Virginia corporation with principal executive offices at
120 Park Avenue, New York, New York 10017 ("Advertiser") and Detroit Tigers, Inc.
("Operator"), a corporation with principal executive offices at Detroit Tigers
Stadium, Detroit, Michigan 48226, for advertising at Tiger Stadium, a sports facility located
in Detroit, Michigan ("Stadium").
	1.	Warranties	
	(a)	Operator and Advertiser represent and warrant that:	


0	(i)	Philip Morris U.S.A., a division of Philip Morris
Incorporated, and Detroit Baseball Club, a division of
John E. Fetzer, Inc. ("Fetzer"), a Delaware corporation	
	



ii)


(iii)	with principal offices at Michigan and Trumbull, Detroit,
Michigan 48216, entered into an agreement (the "Prior
Agreement") dated as of March 13, 1980, effective as of
January 1, 1980 for advertising at the Stadium;
The Prior Agreement was amended by letter effective as of November
4, 1981 and further amended by letter dated December 21, 1990 and,
as amended, the Prior Agreement extends through December 31, 1994;
The Prior Agreement was assigned by Fetzer to Operator by
assignment dated August 27, 1992;	




N
0
4
0
w
4
• o
w
N
00

pgNbr=2
.
(b)
(iv) Operator and Advertiser agree to terminate the Prior Agreement as of
the 14th day of March, 1993 and to continue their relationship pursuant
to the terms and conditions contained in this Agreement.
Operator represents and warrants that pursuant to an agreement with the City
of Detroit, the owner of the Stadium, Operator has the exclusive right to sell advertising
space in the Stadium.
(c)
(a
Operator represents and warrants that it has full and exclusive right and
authority to enter into and perform this Agreement granting to Advertiser the rights set forth
herein and that Operator's continuing performance of the Agreement does not require the
approval or consent of any person or other entity.
(d) Operator represents and warrants that the Advertising System as defined
herein, is and will remain free of all liens and encumbrances.
2. Grant of Advertisi Rights
Operator grants Advertiser the right to display its advertising material during
the term of the Agreement on:
(i)
(n)
a 22' high by 35' wide dura-ply panel located immediately to the right of the
main scoreboard, and identified as advertising location "C" on attached Exhibit
A ("Advertiser's Panel"); and
on one 8' high x 29' wide painted wall mural ("Mural") located
inside the food court of the Stadium.
O
2 W
N
~

pgNbr=3
0
3. Obligations of Operator and Grant of Additional Rights
(a) The advertising space existing in the Stadium is defined collectively as the
"Advertising System." Operator represents and warrants that the Advertising System wiil
consist only of Advertiser's Panel, the Mural and the additional space shown on attached
Exhibit A.
(b)
If and when Operator intends to expand the Advertising System or install
additional advertising outside or adjacent to the Stadium, Operator will notify Advertiser, in
writing, no less than 90 business days in advance of, or as soon as Operator is aware of, the
proposed expansion of the Advertising System or installation of additional advertising and
permit Advertiser the first opportunity to purchase the advertising space to be added to the
Advertising System or the additional advertising to be installed (collectively, the "Additional
. Advertising"). Advertiser and Operator will negotiate in good faith the payment to be made
by Advertiser for the Additional Advertising. If Advertiser chooses to purchase all or a
portion of the Additional Advertising, Advertiser and Operator will memorialize their
agreement in a separate writing. If Advertiser and Operator are unable to reach an
agreement within 45 business days after notice to Advertiser of the Additional Advertising,
or if Advertiser delivers notice of its intent not to purchase Additional Advertising, Operator
may offer such Additional Advertising to third parties. If Advertiser does not purchase all of
the Additional Advertising, and, in Advertiser's judgment, the value of the Agreement to
Advertiser is reduced as a result of the Additional Advertising not purchased by Advertiser,
Advertiser and Operator will negotiate in good faith for an appropriate reduction in the
N
payment to Operator hereunder based upon the nature and degree of the Additional ~
O
w
~ V
O
-3- w
O

pgNbr=4
• (d) If any provision of the Agreement is held invalid or unenforceable, the
remaining provisions will remain in effect.
(e) The Agreement may not be amended or assigned except in a writing signed by
both parties, except that Advertiser may make an assignment to any division or any majority-
owned subsidiary of Philip Morris Companies Inc. without Operator's consent. If an
assignment occurs, the assignment will not relieve the assigning party of its liabilities and
obligations under the Agreement. The Agreement is binding upon successors and assignees
of the parties. A waiver by either party of any of the terms and conditions of the Agreement
in one or more instances will not constitute a permanent waiver of the terms and conditions.
(f) Any notice required or permitted to be given under the Agreement must be in
writing and will be deemed given if sent by United States certified mail, return receipt
. requested, postage fully prepaid, to the addresses set forth below, or to such other person or
address as either party may designate by written notice to the other party.
IP TO OPERATOR: Detroit Tigers, Inc.
Detroit Tigers Stadium
Detroit, Michigan 48226
IF TO ADVERTISER: Philip Morris Incorporated
120 Park Avenue
New York, New York
Attn: Director of Media
O
• W
-14- W
A
i

pgNbr=5
i
obligation is owed to attempt to foreclose Advertiser from exercising its rights hereunder,
Advertiser may immediately terminate the Agreement upon written notice to Operator.
9. Records
Operator, its employees and agents will maintain detailed and accurate books
and records of account in connection with its performance of the Agreement. Advertiser or
its designated agent may inspect, review and copy Operator's books and records maintained
in connection with its performance of the Agreement at reasonable times during normal
business hours upon reasonable, advance notice to Operator and at Advertiser's expense.
10. ConfidentialitX
Operator, its employees and agents will hold strictly confidential the terms of
the Agreement and all information and materials provided by Advertiser to Operator or
~ created by Operator in performing the Agreement, subject to Major League Baseball legal
requirements. The information and material will remain the property of Advertiser.
Operator will not use or disclose the terms of the Agreement or information and materials to
third parties without the prior, written consent of Advertiser. Operator's obligation to
maintain confidentiality will survive the termination or expiration of the Agreement.
11. Indemnification
(a) Advertiser will defend, indemnify and hold the Operator harmless from any
and all loss, liability, claims and demands arising out of the character, content and subject
matter of any copy displayed by Advertiser in the Stadium.
(b) Operator indemnifies and holds harmless Advertiser, its affiliates and their
officers, employees, directors and agents from all claims, liabilities, costs and expenses, N
0
V
0
• W
-11- O
W
W
00

pgNbr=6
~ (g) Operator will provide Advertiser, its representatives and third parties
~ designated by Advertiser access to the Stadium's food court or an alternative location
mutually agreed upon by the parties (the "Space") and exclusive use of the Space for display.
of the Marlboro Indy Show Car and sufficient space in an additional or alternative location or
locations selected by Advertiser to conduct additional promotional activities to be designated
by Advertiser, including display of banners, subject to the approval of Operator, which
approval shall not be unreasonably withheld, during time periods to be agreed upon by the
parties, which will include no less than four weekend series ("Series") of baseball events
during each Contract Year. The Series for 1993 will be held during June 2-6 and July 24-
28, 1993 and two additional Series, on dates to be agreed upon by the parties. Operator will
permit Advertiser during each Series to distribute non-tobacco products of Advertiser,
~ incentive items, and other materials to smokers 21 years of age and older in areas of the food
court or the Space designated by Advertiser and approved by Operator, which approval will
not be unreasonably withheld.
(h) If and when requested by Advertiser, Operator will provide Advertiser, at
cost, tickets for admission to events held at the Joe Louis Arena, the Fox Theater, Meadow
Brook or the Royal Oak Theater for no less than four guests of Advertiser.
4. Advertising Copy. Installation and Maintenance
(a) The design, layout and content of Advertiser's advertising in the Advertising
System is subject to the approval of Operator, which approval will not be unreasonably
withheld. Advertiser's use of similar copy in other sports facilities in the United States will
be one standard establishing reasonableness. The copy may be changed at any time; o
-4
O
• W
5- w
w
N

pgNbr=7
- Advertising, the loss of value to Advertiser arising from the Additional Advertising and such
' other facts and circumstances as are necessary to fairly compensate Advertiser. If, within 45
business days after Advertiser gives notice to Operator of its intention to seek a reduction in
the payment hereunder, Advertiser and Operator are unable to reach an agreement with
respect to the amount of reduction, Advertiser may terminate the Agreement upon 30 days
written notice.
(c) Concessionaires may, notwithstanding the foregoing, in the immediate area of
their vending booths, on the scorecards and their employees' uniforms and dispensing
equipment identify and advertise products and services. Operator will not permit or cause to
remain in or around the Stadium any advertising or communication of any kind concerning
tobacco products or smoking, except by Advertiser or as otherwise required by state or local
~ law or regulation. This Agreement shall not operate to limit the sale or display for sale of
tobacco products at concession stands or vending machines in the Stadium or on scorecards.
(d) Advertiser's advertisements may be for any products of Advertiser or its
affiliates provided the advertisement does not conflict with similar exclusive rights granted
other advertisers and will be subject to Operator's approval, which will not be unreasonably
withheld.
(e) Operator will cause each of Advertiser's advertisements to be illuminated
during all professional sports events, and during all other events occurring in the Stadium so
long as such illumination does not materially conflict with the nature of the other event.
(f) Operator will provide Advertiser with four adjacent seats in a prime location in
the Stadium's Den section for all events held at the Stadium. o
V
` O
V
4 O
W
W
W
3

pgNbr=8
_ damage or concerted action by any employee or any labor organization, will not constitute a
' ground for termination, provided, however, if Advertiser experiences a loss of service,
Advertiser will receive a p Qr rt refund from Operator of Advertiser's payment for the
Contract Year, based on the portion of the Contract Year during which the loss of service
occurred. The amount of the refund to Advertiser will be calculated by dividing the number
of professional sports events scheduled to be played in the Stadium during the period of loss
of service by the total number of such games scheduled to be played during the Contract
Year and multiplying this quotient by the total payment otherwise due from Advertiser for
the Contract Year.
(f) If this Agreement is terminated for any reason prior to the end of a Contract
Year for which Advertiser has paid Operator, Operator will make a pW = refund to
+ Advertiser. The amount of the refund to Advertiser will be calculated by (a) dividing the
w number of regular season home games played in the Stadium by the Detroit Tigers during the
Contract Year for which Advertiser has paid Operator by the number of regular season home
games originally scheduled to be played in the Stadium by the Detroit Tigers during the
Contract Year, (b) then multiplying this quotient by the total payment made by Advertiser for
the Contract Year, (c) and then subtracting the product so obtained from the total payment
made by Advertiser for the Contract Year, and (d) refunding the difference to Advertiser.
(g) If Operator becomes insolvent, makes an assignment for the benefit of
creditors, becomes the subject of a bankruptcy, reorganization or arrangement proceeding or
defaults in any third party obligation, which default would allow the party to whom the
. CA
V
IQ t°a
W
4

pgNbr=9
•
provided, that the specifications for the change and any change in the product to be
advertiserd is approved in advance by the Operator, which approval will not be unreasonably
withheld. Operator must notify Advertiser of its intent to withhold approval of any copy
submitted by Advertiser within five days of Operator's receipt of the copy.
(b) Operator, at its sole expense, will be responsible for maintaining, cleaning and
the first installation of Advertiser's copy on Advertiser's Panel and Mural. Operator will
clean and inspect the Advertiser's advertising and maintain the advertising in a safe and
secure manner. Advertiser, at its sole expense, is responsible for producing all copy and
installing additional copy subsequent to the first installation on the Advertiser's Panel and the
Mural. Operator will deliver to Advertiser color photographs showing Advertiser's
advertisements on the Advertising System promptly after each installation of new advertising
material thereon.
5. Term of Agreement
The term of this Agreement commenced as of March 15, 1993 and will
continue through December 31, 1995. The term is called the "Contract Period." A
"Contract Year" is any calendar year during the Contract Period.
6. P m n
In consideration for the advertising rights granted to Advertiser herein,
Advertiser will pay Operator $135,000, which includes all applicable taxes, for each Contract
Year. Payment for the 1993 Contract Year will be made in two installments, one of which
will be in the amount of $120,000 and will be paid upon execution of this Agreement and
submission of an invoice and the remaining balance of $15,000 will be paid upon submission

pgNbr=10
• (b) Advertiser recognizes and acknowledges that the Detroit Tigers and the "Tiger
Stadium" marks and trade dress and the goodwill associated therewith have great value and
are the exclusive property of Operator. Advertiser acknowledges that it has no right in and
to the marks and trade dress and agrees not to act in any manner that is inconsistent with or
damaging to Operator's rights in the marks and dress.
14. Ex 1 iv'
During the term of the Agreement Operator will not, without the prior consent
of Advertiser, render similar services or grant rights to advertise on the Advertising System
or on any temporary or event-specific signage to any company or entity whose business
competes with any tobacco product of Advertiser.
15. Relationship of the Parties
• Operator is and will remain an independent contractor and nothing contained in
the Agreement shall be construed to create any relationship of principal and agent or
employer and employee between Advertiser and Operator or to make them joint venturers.
15. Miscellaneous
(a) The Agreement and all matters collateral hereto, shall be governed by the laws
of the State of Michigan applicable to agreements made and to be performed entirely within
the State of Michigan.
(b)
Operator and Advertiser must comply with all applicable laws, regulations,
and ordinances relating to their performance of the agreement.
(c) This Agreement is the complete agreement between the parties and supersedes
any prior oral or written agreement concerning the subject matter. o
4
0
4
' W
-13- W
.p
0

pgNbr=11
~ giving Advertiser notice and a right of first refusal upon the more favorable terms,
exercisable within 30 business days after the notice is delivered to Advertiser.
(b) If Operator, its agents or affiliates, do not have the authority to grant rights in the
New Facility, Operator will assist Advertiser in its efforts to obtain advertising and other
rights in the New Facility at competitive prices.
(c) If upon expiration of the Agreement, the Detroit Tigers have not moved to and
played their regular season home games in a New Facility, Operator wiIl offer Advertiser
rights in the Stadium no less favorable to Advertiser than the rights contained in this
Agreement, including rights to advertising, suites, seating and promotion, at the then
prevailing terms, conditions and rates. Operator will deliver to Advertiser a proposal
containing the cost of the rights no less than 180 days prior to the expiration of the Contract
_ Period. Advertiser and Operator will, within 45 business days of Advertiser's receipt of the
w_ proposal, agree upon the "prevailing rate" for the rights in the Stadium. If Advertiser and
Operator do not agree within 45 business days, Operator may contract with a third party for
such rights, provided however, Operator will not offer or accept terms or conditions more
favorable to the third party than those previously offered to Advertiser without first giving
Advertiser notice and a right of first refusal upon the more favorable terms, exercisable
within 30 business days after the notice is delivered to Advertiser.
8. Termination
(a) If Operator fails to perform the Agreement and the failure to perform is not
cured within 28 days of written notice of the failure to perform to Operator, Advertiser will
be entitled to: (i) terminate this Agreement, effective immediately, by giving written notice to 0


~		y
O
W
V
	-H-	W
ta
CA

pgNbr=12
~ Operator, and Operator will refund to Advertiser all sums, if any, paid for the portion of the
Contract Year subsequent to the date of termination, computed as provided in Subparagraph
8(f); or (ii) at Advertiser's sole option, Advertiser and Operator will negotiate in good faith
for an appropriate reduction in the payment to Operator based upon the nature and degree of
the failure to perform, the loss of value to Advertiser arising from the failure to perform,
and such other facts and circumstances as are necessary to fairly compensate Advertiser.
(b) Except as otherwise provided in Subparagraph (a), if either party fails to
perform this Agreement and the failure to perform is not cured within 30 days of written
notice of the failure to perform to the non-performing party, the other party may, in addition
to any other remedies which may under the circumstances be available to it, terminate this
Agreement effective immediately, by delivering written notice to the non-performing party.
~ (c) If any federal, state, municipal or local law, regulation, ordinance, or ruling
becomes effective which makes advertising of tobacco products unlawful, generally or as to
the type of advertising contemplated by this Agreement, or regulates the smoking of tobacco
products or requires a modification of advertising copy that materially reduces the value of
this Agreement, this Agreement may be terminated by the Advertiser as of the date such law,
regulation, ordinance, or ruling becomes effective.
(d) If Operator, or a third party, exercises any undue restraint of the advertising
by Advertiser, this Agreement may be terminated by Advertiser as of the date such restraint
is imposed upon the Advertiser.
(e) Delay in the performance of this Agreement from acts of God or any other
cause beyond the control of Operator or because of any strike, work stoppage, picketing, N
0
V
i CD
W
9- 4
0
w
w
w

pgNbr=13
• including reasonable attorneys' fees, that arise from, or may be attributable to errors,
omissions or fault of Operator. Operator's obligation to indemnify and hold harmless will
survive the termination of the Agreement. At its option, Advertiser may defend any suit on
its own behalf, unless such suit is defended by an insurance carrier, but at the expense of the
Operator and without any release, impairment or limitation of the obligations of the Operator
hereunder.
12. Insurance
Operator will provide, at no cost or expense to Advertiser, comprehensive
general liability insurance, including contractual and advertiser liability, and public liability
insurance with limits of no less than $5,000,000 combined single limit for bodily injury,
including personal injury, and property damage, and Operator will deliver to Advertiser
. certificates of insurance evidencing the coverage and naming Philip Morris Incorporated, its
affiliates, employees, representatives and agents as additional insureds. The certificates must
provide that Advertiser must have at least thirty days' advance, written notice of any
cancellation or modification of the insurance.
13. Ownership
(a) Operator recognizes and acknowledges that the MARLBORO mark and trade
dress and the goodwill associated therewith have great value and are the exclusive property
of Advertiser. Operator acknowledges that it has no right in and to the mark and trade dress
of MARLBORO or any other product of Advertiser or its affiliates and agrees not to act in
any manner that is inconsistent with or damaging to Advertiser's rights in the mark and
N
dress. CD
V
O
W
• V
O
12- W
W
Cp

pgNbr=14
~ of an invoice and delivery of color pictures evidencing the proper installation of Advertiser's
advertisement on the Mural. Payment for the 1994 and 1995 Contract Years will be made
upon submission of an invoice on March 15 of each Contract Year.
7. First Refusal Rights
(a) If and when the Detroit Tigers move to and play their regular season home
games at a new stadium to be constructed in the Detroit area (the "New Facility"), this
Agreement will terminate, except that the provisions contained in this paragraph will survive
the termination. If the Agreement is terminated prior to the last scheduled Detroit Tigers
home baseball game being played during the Contract Year, Advertiser will receive a pm
rata refund from Operator, the amount of which will be calculated in accordance with
Subparagraph 8(f). To the extent that Operator, its agents or affiliates has the authority to
~ grant rights to the advertising space, promotion, suites or seating at the New Facility,
Operator will offer Advertiser rights in the New Facility no less favorable to Advertiser than
the rights contained in this Agreement, including rights to advertising, suites, seating and
promotion, at the then prevailing terms, conditions and rates. Operator will deliver to
Advertiser a proposal containing the cost of the rights at the New Facility no less than 180
days prior to the date Operator expects the first baseball game to be played at the New
Facility. Advertiser and Operator will, within 45 business days of Advertiser's receipt of the
proposal agree upon the "prevailing rate" for the rights in the New Facility. If Advertiser
and Operator do not agree within 45 business days, Operator may contract with a third party
for such rights, provided however, that Operator will not offer or accept terms or conditions
more favorable to the third party than those previously offered to Advertiser without first o
V
O
W
-7- w
w
.p

pgNbr=15
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
