<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aaz99c00</tid>
<bt>50304903/4904</bt>
<dd>19891201</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<au>GONIAS SL, UNIV VA HEALTH SCIENCE CENTER</au>
<rc>GERTENBACH RF, CTR</rc>
<!-- Note:d:DESCRIPTIONS OF WHY A STUDY OF A2-MICROGLOBULIN WOULD BE GRANTWORTHY AND A DESCRIPTION OF THREE PRIMARY RESEARCH OBJECTIVES  STUDY ALPHA2-M CONFORMATIONAL CHANGE, IDENTIFY ALPHA2-M BINDING SITES, STUDY ALPHA2-M STRUCTURAL CHANGES INDUCES BY OXIDANTS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>conformational change. This model is shown diagrammatically in
Figure 5 of the accompanying reprint from 1989. In more recent
studies (submitted for publication to J. Biol. Chem.) we have
identified and isolated distinct groups of apparent aZM
conformational intermediates using monoclonal antibodies directed
against conformation specific epitopes. In separate collaborative
studies with Dr. Stephen Weiss from the University of Michigan, we
have begun to analyze the structural changes in a2M that result in
inhibitor inactivation after reaction with oxygen metabolites
secreted by immune cells. Our preliminary unpublished electron
microscopy studies show that these oxidants cause the azM molecule
to fall apart into component subunits or "half molecules".
Interestingly, the morphology of these "oxidation half molecules"
by electron microscopy may be similar to the a2M half molecules
generated by treatment with reductant (first described by Gonias
and Pizzo, 1983, Biochemistry, 22, 536). Of course, the definition
of aZM activity may need to be changed to reflect growth factor
carrier activity instead of proteinase inhibitory activity.
I would envision three primary research objectives in a grant
application.
1. Study a M conformational change by electron microscopy
using nov3 chemical modification agents (crosslinking
compounds); a-macroglobulins from other species that undergo
only partial conformational change under specific conditions
+ (Gonias et al., 1983, Biochem J., 209, 99); and enzymes that
• digest human a2M into well characterized fragments.
2. Identify the azM binding sites for transforming growth
factor-p, platelet-derived growth factor, and related
molecules by immunoelectron microscopy.
3. Study by electron microscopy the azM structural changes
induced by,oxidants.
I think our laboratory is in an excellent position to make
immediate and rapid progress in these areas. We have made no other
applications to obtain support for this work. Therefore, I would
be most grateful to receive a reply from The Council sometime in
the near future. If a rapid response on my part might permit an
early application review, I would be more than pleased to make the
completion of an application a first personal priority.
Thank you so much for considering this letter.
•
Sincerely,
/ i
`
~'_
~
'
,. C,~
~
Steven L. Gonias, M.D.,Ph.D.
Assistant Professor
Pathology and Biochemistry
50304904

pgNbr=1
UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA

0
t 114A1 J'I I
SCIh.'NCh:S
CI4;NTI:R
DEPARTMENT OF PATI IOLOGY
December 1, 1989
Robert F. Gertenbach, President
Council For Tobacco Research
U.S.A. Incorporated
900 Third Avenue
New York, N.Y. 10022
Dear Dr. Gertenbach:
I am writing to you at the suggestion of Dr. Salvatore Pizzo,
a Council For Tobacco Research grant recipient from Duke
University. My laboratory has developed a very exciting and
successful direction of research at the University of Virginia. At
this time, we would like to obtain extramural funding to continue
our work. Based on my laboratory's reputation and the subject of
our studies, Dr. Pizzo suggested that your foundation might
consider providing support. In this letter, I will briefly outline
the studies we wish to pursue. I have included my curriculum vitae
and two recent reprints from the Journal of Biological Chemistry
that are directly applicable to our proposed investigation. If the
Council considers this project worthy of further evaluation, I
would be most pleased to provide more information or complete a
full application.
az~-Macroglobulin is a plasma proteinase inhibitor that I have
studied since 1978. As a student and fellow, working with Dr. Pizzo
at Duke University, I performed some of the initial studies
demonstrating the massive structural changes that occur in aZM when
this inhibitor binds a proteinase. More recently, my interest in
azM structure has been rejuvenated by a body of literature
concerning the role of azM as a carrier and regulator of growth
factors such as transforming growth factor-p and fibroblast growth
factor. An important point in all of these studies is that azM
conformational change significantly changes affinity for growth
factors. For some growth factors, reaction of azM with proteinases
increases affinity, and for others, reaction of azM with
proteinases decreases affinity. In our laboratory, we would like
to develop a new model for the function of aZM. Instead of thinking
of a2M as a regulator of proteinases, we would like to
conceptualize a2M as a regulator of cell growth and proliferation.
The aZM might then be modulated by the enzymes secreted by normal
and neoplastic cells in the environment.
This laboratory has used electron microscopy, supported by
diverse biochemical techniques to develop a new model of aZM
HEALTH SCIENCES CENTER BOX 214, CHARLOTTESVILLE, VIRGINIA 22908
•
•
50304903

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
