<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aaz86d00</tid>
<bt>TCAL0172235/2236</bt>
<au>AZ LEGISLATURE; DELONG # AZ SENATE</au>
<np>MARTIN HALEY</np>
<dd>19870128</dd>
<dt>LEGISLATION / LAW</dt>
<ti>SB 1129  AN ACT RELATING TO CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS;  PROVIDING THAT A DIREDTOR OF A NONPROFIT CORPORATION IS NOT PERSONALLY LIABLE FOR DAMAGES OCCURRING SOLELY BECAUSE OF HIS MEMBERSHIP ON THE BOARD; MAKING A TECHNICAL CHANGE, AND AMENDING SECTION 10-1017, ARIZONA REVISED STATUTES.</ti>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":PECHANGA RFP-60-->
<bx>273</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:11/07/2000-->
<pg>2</pg>
<!-- Note:s:TI STORAGE BOX 1172-->
<!-- Note:cn:PECHANGA-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010124-->
<dl>20020925</dl>
<ot>REFERENCE TITLE; nonprofit corporations;
directors; immunity
STATE OF ARIZONA
38th LEGISLATURE STATE FEB D 4 1987
1st Regular Session
S E N A T E Referred on January 28. 1987
S,B. 1129
Introduced
January 27, 1987
Rules
Commerce and Labor
Introduced by Senator De Long
THE MARTIN HALEy (NPM~
A
STATE SERVICES GRp(lp
2o1515th bTRE{-T N.W
~WJGTOft DC
27pp6
AN ACT
RELATING TO CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS; PROVIDING THAT A DIRECTOR OF A
NONPROFIT CORPORATION IS NOT PERSONALLY LIABLE FOR DAMAGES OCCURRING
SOLELY BECAUSE OF HIS MEMBERSHIP ON THE BOARD; MAKING A TECHNICAL CHANGE,
AND AMENDING SECTION 10-1017, ARIZONA REVISED STATUTES.
1 Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Arizona:
2 Section 1. Section 10-1017, Arizona Revised Statutes, is amended to
3 read:
4 10-1017. Board of directors
5 A. The affairs of a corporation shall be managed by a board of
6 directors except as may be otherwise provided in subsection C. Directors
7 need not be residents of this state or members of the corporation unless
g the articles of incorporation or byiaws ~u require. The articles of
9 incorporatlon or bylaws may prescribe other qualifications for
10 di rectors.
11 B. The board of directors of a religious, charitable, educational
12 or eleemosynary institution may be affiliated with, elected by and
13 controlled by a convention, council, conference or association whose
14 membership is composed of representatives, elders, delegates or messengers
15 from any religious institution.
16 C. The articles of incorporation of a religious institution may
17 vest the management of the affairs of the corporation in its members. If
Ig the religious institution has a board of directors, session, council,
19 vestry or similar body, it may limit the authority of such body to whatever
20 extent is set forth in the articles of incorporation or bylaws. Religious
21 institutions organized prior to =_ J ""` "'` "' "°°' JULY 21,
22 1979 and having no express provision to the contrary in the articles of
z3 incorporation or bylaws shall be deemed to have vested the management of
24 the affairs of the corporation as follows:
TCAL0172235
pgNbr=1
S.B. 1129
1. If organized and operating under a hierarchical fonn, in the
hierarchy as established.
2. If organized and operating under the presbyterian system, in the
session.
3. If organized and operating under a congregational system, in the
members_
D. DIRECTORS OR TRUSTEES OF A CORPORATION OR PERSONS WHO SERVE ON A
BOARD OR COUNCIL IN AN ADVISORY CAPACITY TO THE CORPORATION OR BOARD OF
DIRECTORS WHO ARE NOT PAID FOR THEIR SERVICES TO THE CORPORATION ARE IMMUNE
FROM PERSONAL LIABILITY'AITH RESPECT TO ALL ACTS DONE AND ACTIONS TAKEN IN
GOOD FAITH WITHIN THE SCOPE OF THEIR AUTHORITY.
-2-
TCAL0172236
pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
