<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aad00f00</tid>
<ti>MEETING - ECUSTA LASER AND ELECTROSTATICALLY-PERFORATED TIPPING</ti>
<dt>REPT, REPORT, OTHER;MINU, MINUTES</dt>
<dt>MEETING MATERIALS;REPORT</dt>
<dd>19780614</dd>
<au>NEFF,CC</au>
<rc>HUME,J;ESTERLE,JG</rc>
<pc>ESTERLE,JG;HEYWARD,RM;HUGHES,IW;LANGFORD,RF;LITZINGER,EF</pc>
<np>BOSEWELL,W/ECUSTA;ESTERLE,JG;LITZINGER,EF;NEFF,CC;OWENS,WF/ECUSTA;TOWNSEND,JW/ECUSTA;WOODARD,BG/ECUSTA;X/ECUSTA</np>
<!-- Note:b:KOOL;RALEIGH;VICEROY-->
<!-- Note:co:MARG, MARGINALIA-->
<!-- Note:br t="o":SRP322-->
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":A4;M128-->
<pg>3</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:50002-->
<fn>322 - CIGARETTE WRAPPER STUDIES (780000)</fn>
<!-- Note:dl:19990326-->
<bt>650513673/3675</bt>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>._. - b^. L L. 1lCJ_.~•.
, ~ -. .. Pllt. 1L _.. I1LiCCF.L'~
I
LS'P41T;,_ ,G
-~.'.. . .. . . . - _
rairectoc:, Tobacco Indust&gt;.y R,search t.r. J. l:. T( .~.: - Director of Sales, Domestic Paper
t-tz. ls. c:. 1ard -Tobacco Accounts Supervisor
:,ttr. ts. Poc.-::cll - eusiness Manager of Convertor Products
Lc ;, D&amp;W personnel: '.
L
. . . . . ~ ~ ' ~ ~. .
GJ
stated a$1,000,000 capital expenditure is required to provide
tipping to meet a 3% share of domestic market. m
0
Ecusta asked if B&amp;W could project their requirements for laser (fl
and/or EP tipping and what intentions we had in convertinc RJOL W
ie~ [custa's cr.rrent manufacturing capabilities fo
rcc, .:;i,ati:_L]J.s-perforated tipping and to discuss
crmaticn on availability and pricing £ollows.
'DUring the discussio,,, Ecusta expressed concern about their ability
to support the industry requirement should a large existing ba nd
cwitch to lascr or EP tipping. They ccmmentcd their policy would
be to keep ahead.of demanc forprojected new'brand launches, but _
not to commit speculative capacity to cover existing brands. They
pgNbr=1
- ? -
84mm. They were tol-1 this couldn't be determined at this time.
They again stated they were unwillinc to cemmi-~ capital without
a guarantecd volume and pointed ozt the extended lead time.
TABRR PERFOFATIOPd Eccsta currently has sufficient capahS.li.ty to manufacture
laser perforated tipping to meet 1% of the domestic market .
sharc. They plan to add an additional 3% capacity to come
on-stream in October/november 1978. There is a nine month
lead tine to bring additional capacity of 3% on line and an
addit.i_onal 3% per month could be added after that, assuming
that the appropriate lead time had been yivea.
They indicated the price for laser perforated tipping,
equivalent in porocity to one-line mechanically per£orated
tipping, would be approximately equal in cost to mechanically
perforated material. If three or mcre lines of,laser
perforati.ons arc required, the price could increase by $3-$4
per bobb-_n.
ELECTROSTPTICP.LLY-PSRFORZaTED TIPFIVG
. Ecusta currently has ea_uipment on-2ine that will produce EF
tipping equivalent to 1/ U_S. domestic mar]cet share. Further,
. they are L, Lhe process of cozmerL_i_g Lt.eir EP cigareLLe paper
equipment to the capability o: perforating tipping. This
conversion will give them another 3id market sSare and will be
in production in August. In addition, Ecusta could add an
additiona- 3/ cape.city within 6 months since they have some
eq_u_pment already in-house. Additional capacity in 3%
increments would have a nine month lead time. At this time,
Ecusta has no firrr. plans to add this later capac.ity.
Ecusta personnel advised that the lowest cost EP tipping is
achieved when thcy havc the naxim,.m basd width in which to
per°orate and the least porosity per unit of area. The lowest
cost material would have an 8-12 mm wide perforation band with ~
porosity equivalent to a one-line mechanically perforated
material. Any chanyes Eror.t this speci:Cicatiod would be	~
reElected in higher cost. As a reference, the ctu-rent r_ork	~
tinping materi.al used on ICUUb, V1ChYtUY and HALEIGI3 Kings is	W
	Q)
I
1P.
pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
