<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aay07d00</tid>
<bt>TNWL0000107/0109</bt>
<au>GRAHAM RJ</au>
<dd>19860224</dd>
<dt>REPORT</dt>
<ti>WEEKLY ACTIVITIES REPORT WEEK OF: FEBRUARY 24-28, 1986</ti>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":RFPLOBBY-001, RFPLOBBY-008, RFPLOBBY-010-->
<bx>223</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:5/18/1999-->
<pg>3</pg>
<!-- Note:s:TI STORAGE BOX 2260-->
<!-- Note:cn:NORTHWEST LABORERS-->
<!-- Note:dl:19990812-->
<dl>20020925</dl>
<ot>WEEKLY ACTIVITIES REPORT
WEEK OF: FEBRUARY 24-28, 1986
NAME: Robert J. Graham
REGION: Northwest, Region 5 -
LEGISLATIVE SUPPORT ACTIVITY
* Met with Phone bank operators in Seattle to discuss
their involvement in the possible initiative drive in the State
of Washington. Designed program that would "chase" petitions
with key contacts with retrieval of petition as the goal. Also
discussed involvement in the final get-out-the vote drive.
* separated informal petitions into counties in
preparation for putting names up on the Tobacco Institute's
computer. Names have been gathered for use in the upcoming
Washington State initiative drive.
* Discussed with Bill Buckley the hiring of one high
school student to put names up on the computer for minimum wage.
Project to take place on weekends
` Met with, and discussed the initiative drive with Lou
Hibdon, President of local #126, Bakery,Confectionary and Tobacco
Workers Union. Meeting was held in his office 'in the Tacoma,
Washington area. Meeting lasted almost four hours. He wants
assistance in forming a coalition of eight unions in return for
an all out involvement on their part. Will sit down with the
entire coalition next week.
* Discussed possible avenues relative to filing a law
suit relative to the constitutionality of ESSB 4519 ( McDermott D
43 Seattle). Possible avenue is to sit down with Ken Eichenberry,
Attorney General of the State of Washington. Any constitutional
challenge will have to have an opinion written by this office.
If we receive an opinion that is favorable then we should
consider taking action to get an injunction against implementing
ESSB 4519.
* Placed call into Eichenberry's office to establish
meeting time. He will not be in the office until late in the
week of March 3rd.
* Briefed Doug Ellis, Executive Director of the
Washington State Republican Party, relative to progress in
TNWL 0000107
pgNbr=1
forming coalitions. The Republicans have begun running radio ads
in the Bellingham area. Purpose of ads is to go after democrats
that voted in-favor of ESSB 4519. He indicated that if we wanted
to run ads against Representative Fisch ( D 24 Port Angeles),
they would create the ads and buy the placement time to saturate
the district for $500. Discussed possible language, or direction
of language of proposed initiative.
" Flew to Boise Idaho with Alexander King to meet with
the Tobacco Institute's counsel, Bill Roden. Also met with Dick
Kading and Mike Brassy, also TI counsels. Had luncheon meeting
to discuss general problems and attitudes of the Idaho State
Legislature.
* Paid visit to Cecil Wright of Capitol Distributors, one
of the industry distributors, in Boise. Shown how cigarettes
were stamped and discussed a tax deferral bill that he wants to
see enacted.
* Met with Bill Roden and an informal group of
legislators, consultants and key Senate staff personnel. General
overview of the session to date, and of things to come.
* Dinner meeting with Alexander H. King, Bill Roden and
Representative Doug Jones ( R 23 Idaho) to discuss pending
legislation relative to a proposed sales tax amendment that will
be offered Tuesday. Discussion revolved around the tax, which is
discretionary at the local level, and it's possible impact on our
industry.
* Spoke with Mac McAddams, President of the Washington
_State Bartenders Union, about their involvement with the
initiative drive in Washington State. There are a total of eight
thousand members in the Pierce and King County area. (Tacoma and
Seattle).
* McAddams is setting up a meeting between his
counterpart in Seattle and myself for mid-week of march 3rd.
* Called Tina Walls, Phillip Morris, to open the door for
us to sit down with their counsel Martin Durkan. Permission was
granted.
* Contacted Durkan's office to set meeting. Meeting will
take place, possibly this weekend. Durkan will contact Bill
Fritz, the Tobacco Institute's counsel, and also counsel for
R.J. reynolds, Dean Morgan.
• Updated Bill Fritz relative to initiative coalition.
* Contacted Vito Cheichi who will be the new chief of
staff of the Minority House Caucus. Discussed the caucus
involvement with initiative. Also discussed in detail the pros
and cons of running with an initiative.
TNWL 0000108
pgNbr=2
* Met with Jennifer Dunn, Chairman of the Washington
State Republican Party. She sees the initiative as the vehicle
to take control of the House of Representatives, wants to assist.
* Obtained list to break down legislative districts by
zip codes from Doug Ellis.
* Contacted Congressman Larry Craig, (R Idaho) and
invited him to address the annual meeting of the Washington State
Association of Tobacco and Candy Distributors, to be -held in
Idaho in June.
NEXT WEEK'S ACTIVITY
* Fly to Portland,Oregon with Alexander H. King to meet
with TI counsel, Hank Crawford.
* Meet with Lou Hibdon and other union members relative
to cementing package on grassroots coalition.
* Meet with Ken Eichenberry to pursue the
constitutionality facet of overall game plan relative to ESSB
4519.
* Meet with and up date Vito Cheichi relative to
initiative drive.
* Call Bill Roden to discuss writing a campaign plan for
.Gary Robbins, a Member of the Idaho State House. He is running
for an open Congressional seat.
* Attempt to finalize initiative campaign strategy
relative to making recommendation to William P. Buckley.
* Meet with Bill Fritz, Dean Morgan and Martin Durkan to
go over campaign structure.
* Establish rough budget for qualifying the initiative.
* Set meeting with individuals involved in the initiative
drive for time convenient with William P. Buckley visit.
TNWL 0000109
pgNbr=3
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
