<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aay3aa00</tid>
<bt>10398616/8617</bt>
<dd>19690526</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<au>WILLIAMS AC</au>
<rc>GRANT R, ACS</rc>
<pc>ADAMS L;HOLLEB A</pc>
<bx>190</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19960628-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":135-->
<np>JAMES EWING SOCIETY;SOCIETY OF HEAD AND NECK SURGEONS;AMER RADIUM SOCIETY;AMER SOCIETY OF CLINICAL ONCOLOGY</np>
<!-- Note:d:DISCUSSES NEED FOR CHAIR OF ONCOLOGY IN MEDICAL SCHOOLS AND ORGANIZATION OF SINGLE ONCOLOGICAL BODY-->
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>~ _.__..;,z. ,.:... .
ASHBEL C. WILLIAMS, K D.
1661 RivMUDt Av[ND[
JACK50NVILLE. FLORIDII 32204
PNONC 396•/40
May 2r•, 1969
t
1
Dr. Rnald Grant
American Cancer Society
219 East 42nd Street
New York, N. Y. 10017
D I
ear Rnald:
T appreciate your recent communication relative
to the possibility of the chair in oncology. I also
irecall our conversation which took pl.ace in Washinsaon
at the Breast Conference and in Cleveland at the
recent Board Meeting when we discussed this matter.
It has long been my feeling that one of the great
weaknesses in our cancer teaching area as reQards
doctnrs, medical students and interns and residents
lies in the fact that we don't have the proper rep-
resentatiorr in the medical schno).s. The coordinators
have done a good job in a numiler of schools and a pnnr
job in a number of others but the problem has gotten
too big for coordinators at this time as it cuts across
faculty problems, postgraduate educatinn, and cont inuinp
education as well,as the Heart, Cancer, and Stroke and
kerinngl Medical Frogram field. There would seem to me,
as you have pointed out, and I could agree completely
that there is a definite need for a chair in oncology
in the medial schools. I understand that some schools
are receptive to this idea now and I think it is fittine
and timely forr the American Cancer Society instead of
endc+wing any more chairs in research to endow several.
chairs on perhaps an experimantal basis ir oncology in
schools whicr are, receptive to the idea so that vv can
test nut this method of boosting the standard of nncc+lo^,-
ical education in the profession. I would.'like this to
be brought up at the Yrofessihnal Education Committee
and tn the Clinical Fellowship Committee•and to he c on-
sidered perhaps at the Survey Committee in September if
there is to be one. The Regional Medical Pro?rams are
based upon the philosophy that we are not getting the
cancer message across to the practitioners and clinicians
at the community level and certainly not at the medical
school level either. This would be one way of accomplishine
this and it may well be that if we succeed in our pilot
studies with several experimental oncoldnical chairs
,

pgNbr=1
i
{
that this might spread, and probably will, to other schools
and maybe eventually to all of them. This would be a
tremendnus accomplishment on the part of the American
Cancer Society and on the part of the sufferers from
cancer throughout the United States.
I will be most interested to know how this is received
and feel that a special subcommittee should be appo`inted
frc+m the Educational Committee probably to develop in-
f ormation in depth along this line and come back with
some answers which will be helpful.
7 also feel that it is perhaps proper for the
American Cancer Society to make some suggestians to the
varimus oncolo;ical organizations such as the James Ewi.no
Snciety, the Radium Society, the Society of Head and
Necic Surgeons, the Society of Clinical Oncolojzy, etc.,
to sub,^,est that they might find an umbrella underwhich
they could all gather and thus strengthen the oncological
movement in the country which is badly splintered and
ineffectual in many ways at the present time. These
organizations themselves have already felt this lack and
bave made some probes in the direction of cesllabrration
but n-ne in the way of unification. This, again, could
and should be brought up perhaps before the Professional
Educational Cnmmittee for discussion. I don't think the
Society would be regarded as a meddler if we sent a tact-Fnl
letter to each of these organizations making scm+e su;pesticirs
a1 orp, these lines and of fering the service&gt; of the Cancer
Sncierl, in any way that miRht be helpful in brirdng al:~ur
snr.:e discusstnns, etc., in this direction. We could point
etit: t n thea: the advanta ;es that we as a Cancer Snc ietv see
in tlte potential strength and organization of a sir.;le
n„rnln&lt;;ical body.
T will *ae rost interested in the reaction of you
pec+pie to these d:trections and hope that ttiey c1 •ill be
e
T:ivnrabty received as T think they are in a pnsitive diYect-'.-.
and are timely.
Si.ncerely vrnirs,
i
~~i
A~ be C. 1+'illiams,*S,D.
C . t:. 11+'. Arrvir
' ;r . t.-Ir,f- Ada-s
,

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
