<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae14d00</tid>
<bt>507950968/0969</bt>
<rc>HUMAN RESEARCH REVIEW COMM</rc>
<au>ROBINSON JH</au>
<bx>RJRC1376</bx>
<!-- Note:b:NOW 85;VANTAGE ULTRA LIGHTS 85-->
<!-- Note:rn t="p":1RFP72;1RFP76;1RFP77;1RFP88;1RFP115;1RFP116;1RFP117-->
<dd>19920107</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<!-- Note:co:Y-->
<np>FTC;BELLOMY CARRIGG;BLIXT CA;RJR</np>
<!-- Note:dl:19980227-->
<pg>2</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":MINNESOTA 1RFP71;CASTANO 1RFP1;BURTON 2RFP16-->
<!-- Note:sh:19960229-->
<!-- Note:s:R&amp;D;BIOCHEM BIOBEHAVIORAL-SCI AFFAIRS;STEELE RH;R&amp;D TOXICOLOGIST-->
<ti>2MG XB 7-CIGARETTE BLOOD STUDY.</ti>
<!-- Note:tp:NICOTINE AND ADDICTION; SMOKING BY-PRODUCTS-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>TO: Human Research Review Committee
FROM: J. H. Robinson
SUBJECT: 2mg XB 7-Cigarette Blood Study
January 07, 1992
A. BACKGROUND: The Biobehavioral Division has conducted numerous,tests in
support of Project XB product development. The most recent test, conducted in
July of 1991 indicated that the addition of "smoothing agents" into the tobacco
blend could modify smoking behaviors and result in blood nicotine
concentrations that are higher than what might be predicted from a particular
cigarette. The possibility therefore exists that multiple smokings of
cigarettes prepared with smoothing agents could result in undesirable-blood
nicotine concentrations. Since all of our previous XB blood studies have been
conducted with subjects smoking only 1 cigarette, blood nicotine concentrations
following multiple smokings of XB products should be investigated.
The purpose of this proposal is to obtain approval for a human test that will
monitor blood nicotine concentrations of smokers in a multiple cigarette
smoking test using a 2mg XB prototype cigarette. This test will provide data
that will indicate whether these products can be tested in an extended-use (2-3
carton) consumer test.
B. NEED FOR HUMAN SUBJECTS: Human smoking characteristics, plasma nicotine
concentrations, and physiological responses following smoking can only be
obtained using human subjects.
C. SCIENTIFIC AFFAIRS REVIEW: Relevant data on the XB prototypes to be used in
this study were presented to the HRRC and approved in the following proposals:
R9132 - Approved use of G7-25 in FF to ULT configurations at inclusion rates of
up to 30% by weight of tobacco. Use in any SED or consumer tests with up to
400 subjects and up to 2 packs exposure was approved.
R9128 - Approved "reverse osmosis" KDN in XB prototypes.
R9126 - Approved XB prototypes of either ca. 1 or ca. 5 mg 'tar' that included
KDN. G7-10-M-HE (G7-25) also approved.
D. PRODUCTS: Three products will be tested in this study. All products are
re-makes of products in the CT2338 series (see Appendix I). Two products
(CT2338 AA and CT2338 AB) are the commercially available NOW 85 and Vantage
Ultra Light 85 cigarettes. The XB prototype to be tested is a re-make of
CT2338 AE. Relevant mainstream smoke yields (FTC conditions) for all these
products are provided in Appendix I.
E. &amp; F. Procedures: Subjects will be 10 male Caucasian volunteers recruited
from the local community by Bellomy Research, Inc. All participants will be
regular smokers of at least 20 ULT cigarettes per day. The study requires the
subjects to participate in three, approximately 4-hour test sessions. Subjects
will smoke 7 cigarettes each session approximately 30 min apart. Subjects will
smoke only one type of cigarette each session and will be tested with a
1
pgNbr=1
different type on each of the 3 test sessions.
Upon arrival at the test site (ist visit only), each subject will be asked to
sign an informed consent (Appendix II). After signing the consent form,
subjects will be asked to sit in a reclining chair. An indwelling sterile
catheter which allows multiple blood samples to be drawn with only one vein
puncture will be inserted into a vein in one arm. Due to the length of time
the catheter will be in place, the catheter will be "locked" using sterile
heparin solution (10u/ml). Care will be exercised to prevent the injection of
heparin into the subject. A Finapres (TM) finger cuff used to.monitor heart
rate and blood pressure will be attached to the middle finger of one hand. Two
elastic bands will be placed on the subject for purposes of monitoring
breathing patterns using the commercially available Respitrace (RTM) system.
Testing will begin as soon as is practical after the subjects have been
prepared. Subjects will be instructed to smoke 7 cigarettes during the session
(roughly 30 min between smokings). All cigarettes will be instrumented with a
plastic flow probe to allow measurement of the "puff-profile".
Blood samples will be drawn according to the following schedule (times
relative to lighting the cigarette:
Cigarette # 1 - -2, 0, 5, 7.5, 15 and 30 min (30 min = 0 for next cig)
Cigarette # 2 through Cigarette # 6 - 5, 7.5, 15, and 30 min
Cigarette # 7 - 5, 7.5, 10, 15, 20 and 30 min
All samples will be drawn into 7 ml Vacutainer (TM) tubes for subsequent
determination of nicotine concentrations. This represents a total of 31 blood
samples for each subject during each 4 hour test session (less than 1/2 pint of
blood). Heart rate and blood pressure measurements will be made before and
after smoking each cigarette. Breathing patterns will be monitored during the
smoking of the 7th cigarette only.
G.' FORMS COMPLETED BY SUBJECTS: Subjects will be required to.sign an--informed
consent approved by Mr. Blixt. All subjects will be asked to complete a
"thermometer scale" and attribute questionnaire following each cigarette.
H. SUBJECT HANDLING PROCEDURES: For participating in this study, volunteers
will be rewarded in the amount of $450.00. All subjects will be escorted by
RJRT personnel when at the Bowman Gray Technical Center. There will be no
"deception" of subjects at any point during the test.
SAFEGUARDING PERSONAL DATA: All data collected by RJRT researchers will be
confidential. These data will be handled under normal security
currently followed for confidential information. No personal
will be included in any future publication which may arise from this
2
pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
