<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aab00f00</tid>
<ti>TALIN: EVALUATION AS A FILTER ADDITIVE AND AS A TO</ti>
<dt>MEMO, MEMO</dt>
<dt>CORRESPONDENCE</dt>
<dd>19790406</dd>
<au>CRAVOTTA,TJ</au>
<rc>SANFORD,RA</rc>
<pc>DEINES,WH;JEWELL,JN;REYNOLDS,ML;ROSENE,CJ;STRUBEL,DG</pc>
<np>LYLE;MAILLARD;TATE;X/BAT;X/AMERICAN FLAVOR + FRAGRANCE;X/STEPAN CHEMICAL</np>
<!-- Note:co:MARG, MARGINALIA-->
<!-- Note:br t="o":SRP316-->
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":A4-->
<pg>2</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:52420-->
<fn>316 - FLAVOR RESEARCH - 790000</fn>
<!-- Note:dl:19990326-->
<bt>650518452/8453</bt>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>C C_
SROWN tlWILL1AM5ON TO3ACCO CJRPOPATIaf.
INTERNALCORRESPONDENCE
TO .
DEPT. -
C.C.to ,
rFlOM
SUBJECT
DR. R. A. SP.NFO%D __ ,
MR. .*1. L. REYVOLDS DR. W. H, DEINES
MA_._C.__J_. ROSENE.,__ DR. d. N. JEWELL MR. D. G_,_.STRJREL _ .
MR. ^_. J. CFAVOTTA/vr/316 DATE APRIL 6, 1979 TALIN: EVALUATION AS A FILTER ADi)1'TLVE AND AS A TOBACCO SECTION ADDITIVE FOR
MAILLARD REACTION FLAVOR AnpLICATIDWS
3_y
Investigations using Ta1in as a filter additive yielded u impressive results.
several mebhods of application were eu.ployed, n e of which were considered
beneficial to overall cigarette flavor character.t However, inceresting effects aere achieved when Talin/fructose was applied ..
to the tobacco section. Generally, this method of addition improved smoke
quality by i ing amots body and decreasing inieation. This is another
in a series of useful findings from our recent study ot Maillard reaction
flavor applications. - . Talin as a Filter Additive
1'alin, a protein sweetener received from BAT, was evaluated as a filter
additive.
Talin, or morespecifically Tnaumatin I and II, is a sweet tasting isolate .. .
Eroa the West African shrub Thaumatococcus daniellii, known by the natives .
as Katepfe. The molecular compositions of Thaumatin I and II are similar as shown by their amino acid content; molecular weight is about 21,000. The proteins pacsees a degvee of eweetnesn about 1600 timaa that of a v c
on a weight basis (sacchariT.e is 500 times sweeter than sucrose), but lose
their sweetenir.g abilities when heated or at pH values below 2.5. .
Tobacco applications are suggested in the patent issued Tate and Lyle (German
2, 817, 092). According to this patent, the protein should be applied to the
filter end of the cigarette. To perceive the sweetness, physical coatact
must be made with the protein. They also apecrtfy the product has no useful
effect when combusted.
In our investigations, an aqueous solutisn of Sa1in was injected into the N
filters of 8 mg 'tar' unflavored cigarette.c at a rate of 0.7 mg per Eilter. ~
With this application, some sweetness was perceived upon "dry puffing" the ~
cigarette. This eftect was perceived because some '1'alia was present on ~.i
the extreme mouth end of the Eilter tow and, therefore, physical contact ~
was made. Lberall snoke quxlity, howeven, aas left relatively unchange3. K"
The inner-plug of a dual section acetate filter was then injected with the (fl
protein. Since no phyeical contact wes made, a effect was perceived. N
This is a T2asonable result since one would not expect a protein with a
moleculan weight of 21,000 to have mobility. .
pgNbr=1
A Talin solution was also "atreakerP" on the outside of the tipping. Based
on a limited number of trials, when an effect v per ived, it was ar. -
pleasant experience leaving a strong, lingeringas sickening sweet aftertaste.
The petent also claima Talin to be a menthal/spice enhancer. I did not
find this to be true. X5L 100 filters were in]ected with (.7 mg) Ta1in and
little if any affect was perceived.
Our investigation does not indicate Talin is useful as a filter additive.
Amino Acid/Suear Ma111ard Reactions
A far more interesting effect was achieved when Talin was applied to the
tobacco section in conjunetion with fructnse_ Talin i a polypeptide com-
posed of 18 different amino acids. When these amino acids are combusted
in the presence of fructose, Maillard reactions occur. The effect was not
wirh fructnse or Talia alone on the. tobacco section. The a cid/
sugar additives iaparted a full-bodied mouthfeel, redaced irritation and added a slightly sweet taste. This application has a more apparent affect
than additiun to the filter which cas suggested in the patent. - I have found that amino acid/sugar reaction products can be very useful as
, tobacco £lavorings. The Ta11n application is one in a series of useful
findings involving these reactions. End product flavor characteristics axe
as numeroua as the amino acid/sugar combinations one starts with. . .-
To date, I have found three methods of producing desirable taste effects
with amino acid/sngar omplexes. Pirst, they have shovn unique flavoring
capabilities added a a cigarette to~ flavor. In this application, the amino acid/sugar mixture was pre-reacted in a reaction vessel by Amer_can
Flavor ard rragrance prior to addition to the tobacco.
Secondly, in SIR WALTER RALEIGH cocoa replacement work, an amino acid mix-
ca.inZ . , a11nved tn r act with the. AVAi.APF -
ture w G added to the .sa
pvesentduring redrying.s This i
amnoacid mixtune composition attempted te~' mimic that found in cocoa. A lab forced hot air oven, which simulated .
redrying, supplied the necessary heat for Maillard r action. As a sult,, the test tobacco acquired a"nutty^ pyrazine type pouch axoma and flavor which had been missing when the cocoa was deleted. .
The Talin investigation has shown n a Lhird mechuuiam wlrcre pruLeins aud
sugars can be reacted, using the burning cigarette coal as a source of heat.
Several of our recent 5 ng menthol consumer ofterings contain APP reaction product flavors. These flavors are very useful in low delivery cigarettes .
because of their ability to increase "body" and decrease irritation. Theee .
problems are inherent to low delivery cigarette designs.
~
Amesican Plavor and Fragrance Corporation and Stepan Chemical Company have (J/
been working with reaction products for some time, and their activity in O these flavor applications will be monitored. As part of our ongoing fla- ~vor research, we wi11 continue eo study reaction products and their ~
applications. .
pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
