<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aac80a00</tid>
<ti>TMA Executive Summary</ti>
<dt>Newsletters</dt>
<dt>Publication</dt>
<dd>19871022</dd>
<au>TMA</au>
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":25-->
<pg>4</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:60142785-->
<!-- Note:dl:19981123-->
<bt>947114792/4795</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="a":ATX05 0194945/ATX05 0194948-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>EX"ECU'I'IVE SUMMARY
tAR%LL DLtNAN
PFlESiOE+dr
C*_IAN'EE aTTALX ON °OBACrOIN SENATE FINANCE : : fiIC7OOD . - ~`-1 1' i •.SCSgg
HIKR9IDROP OLIT,..iUST Ali REAGAN u^I)EM HOr- I't-1I tu r,,.:-iyt:~ ry~s~6
Naving aaowed jcnate Flnanee Elemocrats to draft phe r ry'eady
endorscd House Ways Is Means deficit cutting pact hr,k o tho
table on If1/16 with oniy t mn,ior ntlack, - n. , ~I ~ ~ tc., the 5'b
. tension on the telepiione tax with a Ib cent st - - +... _ tzx_
Chal'ee failed .2-3. P.s rcporled, hy 2 13--? zax bnt rnmud- -, ut ro
..
the Senate Dedgct Ccmmittc., the Scnare's :I}-Ib~ =-.ion I I I . c..-
:vrnie I'or FY&amp;g, exacUy half of the ~.".9tsn rc,v¢ed.
-_reEons inciudc provisions to continue or inereaaa cnrtain u.'°r te.-,, caily
,e oxtension of occupationttl taxes to uisdH,r,d spirits A'anta, -:ner
bacco mauufacturnrs at n highcr $1,000 per trcvr i tal. Furthcrmorc, sccuPatioual
:xcs f!ir aieuhod wholcsale and retail dcalars rrerc n r•n.ecr. 44,14 i:.nt tupT s-mmAded
. = includc tcba-ca. The currcnt Q.?'M zd vmiorcm taz on a11 i i arts for ronsumnliwr
,'ts ectended to 9/3h/0, or sII of she items in the Senufe but aot in the
_Iause oersiun, -epeal of the ;4t i00 wage fintit mr the i.wiM' r medmare lrcntth
tnsuranee wlll raisc cPre must 5..."bn en PY88. 'Thesc Pnnds I wsure the
:~Ivssev
ol the Hospital tlnsuranon :rust Fnno, a br.ricPlciary aamcd in . host of siovge hills
~ veking such narmarking &lt;.m -igarerte e. . tr rkr. (Tee ,te 'Foaay 3/:6,
1 :/19i. Though Dukakis ha~ e( to vr~.e his , i.w „n ;peaific Inarc,-cs, only
Lar- iiorc, ©f all wf the other Democratic p«•.idential m3ndidaw. ! ruied out
-.gislated rerenuc dncreases. Both Simon and Jackson scpport tob;&lt;:. - •e hikes
tUPI 1(1/1y). Rcspunding to the stock market crash and accusations ...stmnanc
leadership, Reagan modified his anti-tax stand end nnnolrnced "ha tn look
et' tas Incroases." Again the following day, Treasury's Saker, me-'~h Hmise
-eakcr Wright, said "thcy had °(ummon ground' in working t•r a ..~ ya -.:;z,€ of
speudiug cnts aad reveuue inoreason"(WSJ 10/21, IQ/22/87).
WEISS NEASUBES" LINK ki) AI±DUCTIHILITY WITH ANl'1 ,OBAi7CO MI'.`iAGES
On 10/15, Rcp- SVeiss introduced legislation (HR 95b}) and a resolution 'URes 2Eti)
which call fbr incrcased enti-rnbacou aud anCi-smoking messageee ui the .~-dia. Hft
3593 would disallow the deduction ror tobacco advertising and ptom.,3nnal pensrs
unless tobacoo products maaufaetures I'und "health-awaronos.c" sdvort, -og '1, . ioanas
that exceeds "5 percent of thc tobacco and tobacco pmduet saie prour.~~mi nies the texpaven ior the taaable ycar.- Thc bill dcftnes "hcatthawarcness" _~. tls:ug
to mean 'any advertisement which is for purposes of intonning the : on Hre
health effects af smoking or using smokclcss lobaceo pref:ucts, uud., tich is
. approred" ty HEIS. The bill, which was referrcd to Ways $&amp;iefsns, dcfincs 'tobacco
producis" to inclndc all tobacco products. 'i'hough analogons in its cail tur
acrezscd anti-tobaeco advcrtising, HRw 216, which •.vas ;cfcrrcd to Energy Is,
. vmmerce, i restricted to cigarettes oniy; it cStcs a purporied heaith csre cost :-
sne fr.derai govcrnmant of i4.2bn, and cails on ¢he aovernment to "aneouragc b(th
elcctronic aud print media to air or print :nore antimoking ads zs a pubiic snrcic,a"
1.EG 10/l7). Meanwhile. broadcasters, having wun (he Cinantial FaUle I- na:nlain
~ "e deductibiitt of tobacco advertising, are oox faced with eaislation approved
yesterday in the 8cnate Commerce Committee, that vr,uld horh tax sales of broadcast
stations and revecse the FCC's elimination of the Fatrncus Lloctrrne, evhion had been
used effectively in the 7yti0's to drive tobacco off the airwaves (WS1 IQ/2:/37).
~ 1 r~ MFHl4ANli ll lN( It -NNf/1/Yd/I&lt;Y(Y~n,~d- ~ tIN( r nN N~ ) 549-5iqy111
lr u - . INl ' 6111/L/F/'bkq'E +il
pgNbr=1
UEPB. PL,qRiG ''w i?A-rSNP.MEYER C"6C7 RTLL5 5CSEDULED FOR i.iEA'a°2NGIV
On ;0/27, Fforio'S Energy &amp; i'ommercC Subcommittee on Consumer Proie4tion £niii meet to
hear both HR 33;3, Plorio`&lt; bill to limit Che power of the Consumer Pro4nr,t Salet'v
Co:Ctmissi0n's chairman, cffectivr,ig forc.ing the CPSC €o shift from voiuntsrp to
mandatory prOduct standards, and Rep. Dannemeyer IiR :3443 legislation ounrdneed t
10/7 to establish an Administrator for Consumer Prodt t Safety -thin Health &amp;. auman
5ervioes and to shift a0 curreut funetions or the CPSC to HHS (i:EG i0/2Ci187).
AIRLINE 2-HOUR SMOKING BAN AWAITS RORK DEBATT.
Once Seaate debate on the Nark aontination is completed, now ®-ected -. .,,-. nuddlr, of
nexi week, debate wiil bea_in on HR 2R40, as ntnended in ±an, .nbe- ~ . n3poetation
Snbcomtnittee (ESS7-at), banning entoking un inmes}ic a_¢rtine. {tik-• -I - hours or
less (LEG 10/21). f:ipiinge says expected fifihuste_r ^wdl uot snccee,',." (;or° '-1.
Y"IGARETTE EXPORTS SKYROCKET, NC &amp; MICHIGAN ;:A'. _ OUT
With US cigarette nxporls up S1.3'h dn quanrity ?&lt; 50,, c w~.bn units &amp;
$1.Ibn reapeetively, through i/&amp;7, the US will 3upuian, .. -~a ar. Ilc ~rid's
pleading cigaceite r.xporter, and totnl cigarette p, -inc'~rrv ..
in 1987, the biRgest prodtwtion year since E98: ,TP, i',~~ _ ._ .anr.r-. "utni-
ltl)121- NC State Proi. Toussaint writin4 th: .. of
agricultural sales in NC &amp; (buriey inarkrs _i i '. I ;' .,,.. .uat ar;.
fz~ uers wh0 use family Iabor net 45 cents P~r I
Neither "economic havoc" nor a big 'sociai co.st" ~,ui,ll , ,.id _,ar i ie smoking, reports MC Prof. Warner in n review i( ,iinri .1 .: i.
3-i1 . the Chase "Economic Importance of Tobacco," and othct dars I .•.5' iU/.fi,
EARNIN'GS N: PM1I UP 2£.495, I1ST UP 25%, R rl UP to ;a,, i` W`y!' rr
Philip Morris Cos reported a?1.496 incrczse in net 4unnga or Q87 to a_,, ::mu =8.B".6 gain in 1perating ecvunues to $76n. UST rept ied a 26% racrease ht ri rr
to $r35mn for )Qgr on a F2°f increase in net sales o$147,2mn (NOTE: ES3
"
'
the O-T.C
s US] ll
. T.ruses ,•arnings) not U,S. Toba cosj. RJR itiaulscu
,
announced lhee elevation o£ Robert Carbonnetl to its 3rd Vice f]hairman spot and:
common shares repurchase program, reported e 19.4% iucrcase in nct enrnings !-
to n3&lt;'0m n'0mn on a J.B'y, increase in aaiee. Operating income from contlnuina' nrr,
i
at Amer
can ilrands resr: to 5288.dmn (up 3-iold) on a d1,5r%i jump to .rom continuing operations (PRNewswdre 10/20, 10/21, NpT 10/IS, 10/16),
ADVERTISINGr DOC LAUNCHES PARODIES; PM REHIND LiNILL'= , u -
Doctors Ought to Car.: ;annched P-U. Prujecq an t
"best advcrtising narodies of cigzretie brands
rproduots'" (WSJ !0P!2), At Ef!bn in forecasteJ L48A ~
Philip Morris P-oa, would hoid 2nd place worldwide,
Nabisco would eome in at just nnder $(bn rcpo.- Pa.:acpbu,
`
analvsis nf udvcrtlsing-to-salcs ratios. Marlboro .-in,..,.,
~
things to different cultures in a croas-culturai snaf
ys,e
instructor at Northwestern (AA 10/'.2,'87).
ARKANSAS: SMOKER FILES SUIT rLGA1NST STATE
Walter Skelton fiied n suit on behalf of etate workers who smoke saying that
the smoking restrictinns are discriminatoryJuncnnstitutionai (USA i0/i5/87)-
F'LORIDp: HER JICE TAX lSSI.IE DENERRED TO DnCEMDER
With the Senate calling fpr a 1% increase in the sales tax, nnd the Housc
seeking both ezemptions to the S% xerrice tax or weti as a referendum on ihe
included servleos, the issue was dcl'arrm.i to December I (WSJ i0/ii)87).
MASSACHUSETTS: ziAAhPLING DAN STILL AIdVE.
Ya_atcrday, a morion to withdraw Che sampling ban bill, It 195, , was tah
keeping the biil aiive; a 3rd reading or *[ 3697. u hdi In han arnok
regtaurants, wae ordered (CCH €U/20/&amp;7),
t)Ri'GtiN: $12 MN FOR SMORiNG CESSATION
Two Portland instltntiUna will spend $12mn to deVetop amoking CC3LahOn
lTlethods for heaith-Aare OrganlZabons (IJPI IL1/17/571.
pgNbr=2
I-ANRFI.L L1FLtJJ,\
PHEbII)FT
ES g7-45
October 30, 1987
•
•
SENATE BANS SMOKING ON FLIGHTS OF ONE AND ONE-HALF HOURS OR LESS
On 10/29, after Senators Lautenberg, Helms, Byrd, and Ford agreed to a compromise,
the Senate passed g-0-10 the Department of Transportations appropriations bill, HR
2890. The Senate previously passed, on voice vote, the following revised language:
"On and after the date of expiration of the 4-month period following the
date of the enactment of this subsection, it shall be unlawful to smoke in the
passenger cabin or lavatory on any scheduled airline €light in intrastate,
interstate, or overseas air transportation, if such flight is scheduled for one and
one-half hours or less in duratien...the provisions [above] are repealed effective
on the espiration of the 23 month period following the date of the enactment of this
subsection."
In contrast with the 1 1/2 hour limit and the 2 year duration described above, the
bill as presented on the Senate floor (i.e., as it left Sen. Lautenberg's
Appropriations Subcommittee and the full Appropriations Committee) would have
required a 2 hour limit and a 3 year duration. The Scnate-passed bill differs from
the tfouse-passed version, w'ith the Durbin amendment, in the following ways:
1. The House version has a 2-hour limit and would expire with the FY 99
appropriations process i.e., until a new appropriations bill was etac[ed;
2. The House version would enforce the ban by withholding airport
improvement funds from airports servicing flights that fail to follow the ban, while
the Senate bill g[ves the DOT enforcement &amp; regulatory authority and provides for
fines of up to $1,000 on airline violators and up to $2,000 on individuals who
tamper with smoke detectors.
3. The House version denies federal funds to the Long Island Railroad
unless it prohibits smoking while the Senate version has no similar language.
In order to bring the nieasure into the budget reconciliation process as soon as
possible, a conference is iikety to be scheduled shortly. Sen. Lautenberg said he
hoped the conference "would approve a direct smoking on flights of two hours or
less." Pres. Reagan previously threatened to veto the $11.1 measure, which came in
about $2.bbn over the Administration's request (ESg7-29). A one and one-half hour
limit reportedly affects between 50-70% of all flights (WSJ 10/30, UPI 10/29/87).
E1 iA-e 4_i 7, l I
? SUMMARY
HOUSE PASSES PRO-FORMA $12.3 BILLION TAX BILL
While House and Senate representatives continued negotiations with the White House
on 10/29 on a FY88 deficit-cutting budget package, the House passed 206-205, HR
3545, the $12.3bn tax increase package that had been carved out in Ways &amp; Means
(F.Sg7-42,-40). (n the negotiations the White House is reportedly encouraging a
spending freeze at FY87 levels to save $9-11bn (WSJ 10/28).
ir H 1,9.,ING
7nMOddf~15
(J Ijl{ V
MNCI TUN N I l"°13-8019
pgNbr=3
[OWA DENTAL COLLEGE &amp; AAFP A:iSEMBLE ANTI-SMOKELE5S, ANTI-SMOKING XITS
An information Bit cre.=.ted 'ny the University of Iowa'c Dental College, together with
several state and national groups, inctudcs cancer und other health "facts," und is
designed to health ttrofessionais discourage srnokeiess tobacco consumption (UPI
10/49). The Americau Academy of Family -hysicians is distubuting a new Stop
Srnoking Kit to its 59,000 members; the kit, devefoptA for doctors, eonrains charts
on patient progress, smoker contracts. doorknob hangers etc. (PRNewswire 10/2?/87).
TRADE CONFERENCE RESUMES: HELMS AMENDMENT, HARMC/Ni7.ATION INCLUDED
In an affort to avoid a Presidmrtial veto to HR i, the rnammoth trade bill that
includes among other measures the Helms amendment to provide equal access to
government cxport programs fnr K,IS exporl tohaCcii 2nd ittCorporration o'r tire 8russets
Nomenclature (the Harmonized Commodity Classification system) into US earifif
classifications, conferces approved an c::ension past I/3/R8 to the Pre=ident's
"fasbtrack" negotiating authority to providc for op &amp; down votes only on
international trade treaties, including the aaoected resuits of the Uruguay round of
multilateral trade negotiations. Thre new classification aystem uggrogates aad
disaggregates current TSUSA item numbers for imports and achedule Fl numbers for
sxports - a TMA Report will be iorthcomiog. bieanwhilt, ea the CiS trade defL.;it
registered a$114.Ibn defieil through August, tobacco's trade surplus set a new 3-
month record at $1,5441m, up 36.&amp;'16 from t98ti (TMA i7ade Raroroerar 10/27/87).
HOUSE ETHICS TO HEAR REP. ROSE
North Carolina Demecraz, Charlie Rosn, will nppcar before s heering of tire
House Ethics Committee to explain S101;496 in alleged ioans and I$63.993 in
funds allegedly borrowed from his reelection committee iWS7 10/29/87?.
SUPREME COURT'FABES "ALC'OHOliISM" CASE
Is "a€coholism" a disease or tne s'esutt of "w"r€iful misoonduct"? The
Supreme Court has e€ected to hear a case invoiving a plaintiff denied S'A
br,nef'its due to the vA's exclusion of "alcohoiism" amon_e its list of
qualifying "diseases" (NYT 10/2.5,87).
UNIVERSAL'S EARNINGS UP; LIGGETT CREDIT LINE IN PLACE; AB UP, ilST 9AME
For the Qtr cnded 9/30, Universal Lcaf Tobacco Co. rcportsd a 45.6%
increase in earnings to $13_Smn on a;6.695 fnerease in sales to $4039mn.
llniversai's board approved a repurchase plan for Imn shares. Liggett Group
Inc. completed a$50mn rsvotving iine of credit with a syndicate of
commercial banks; Canadian Imperial Battk nf Commerce aiil ae.t as site agent
bank. American Brands increased ita dividend to $7.2A/share np from $2,08;
UST maintained its dividend ut .'.OQ a share (PRNe`:vswire I0/2g, l0/29,/g7).
RJR NABISCO FORMS RdRN GOLF, P.EPORTS TO HI1RRiGAN
All of RJR's professional golf spmtsorship is now in a ncw business unit,
RJRN Golf; RJR Nabisco named Wavne Robertson the nnit's SVP (PRN 10/2S),
GEORGIA: NUMBER I IN SMOKELESS CONSUMPTION
According to its Department of Human Rcsources, snuff and chewing
tobacco consumption is highest in Georgia ftIPI 10/29/87).
IOWA: INCOME TAX SIGNED, CIGARETTE TAX HIKE DEFERRED TO 1988
While Gov. Branstad signed an income tax reform restructuring on 10/28/87,
plans to push for a higher cigarette tax were deferred to 1988 iUPI 10/28).
VERMONT: POIRER DECLARES FOR CONGRESS, OPPOSED TO EXCISE HIKES
The State House btajority Leader Poirer, deciaring his run far Congress,
said he was opposed to tobacco ercise hikes (UPI EO/23).
®
•
pgNbr=4
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
