<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aaz91f00</tid>
<bt>TIOK0017223/7225</bt>
<au>SPARBER PG # SPARBER AND ASSOCIATES INC</au>
<rc>HRYCAJ C; GLEASON M</rc>
<np># FAMILY COURSE CONSORTIUM; DUDA M; # RJR; SANDEE; TELLO; MARTINLEE</np>
<dd>19920402</dd>
<dt>MEMO; MINUTES</dt>
<!-- Note:co:MARGINALIA-->
<ti>ACTION ITEMS FROM FAMILY COURSE CONSORTIUM MEETING</ti>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":OK1-22-->
<bx>177</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:5/29/98-->
<pg>3</pg>
<!-- Note:s:TI STORAGE BOX 6074-->
<!-- Note:cn:Oklahoma AG-->
<!-- Note:dl:19990524-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>Sparber
and
Associates, Inc.
April 2, 1992
MEMORANDUM
TO: Carol Hrycaj, Martin Gleason
FROM: Peter G. Sparber•
RE: Action items from Family C.O.U.R.S.E. Consortium
meeting
The following action items came from Saturday's meeting:
1. Drafting of a Family C.O.U.R.S.E. Consortium 6osition paper
on the "Joe Camel" controversv
. ~ ~
~
In the next several days I will contact those members who
attended Saturday's meeting for their views. Based on
Saturday's discussion, we seem to have a range of opinions.
I spoke briefly with some of the members afterwards and
suspect that the group will endorse a position with these
features:
No one disagrees with the objective of discouraging
youth smoking. That is a primary goal of the
Consortium and we are proud of the progress we have
made. We appreciate the tobacco industry's support and
view that support as evidence of a good faith effort by
the industry to actively discourage youth smoking.
~
Cigarette companies should not only refrain from ~
promoting cigarettes to youngsters but should avoid the
appearance of doing so. The appearance of promoting /
cigarettes to youngsters may undermine the credibility
of industry-sponsored programs that make an important
contribution to the fight to discourage youth smoking.
Anti-tobacco groups harm their own credibility and do
nothing to discourage youth smoking when they rely on
claims such as those suggesting that "Joe Camel" is
more popular than "Mickey Mouse." The research is
offensive to those dealing seriously with child
welfare.
`! ,- TIOK 0017223
pgNbr=1
Ms. Hrycaj, Mr. Gleason
April 2, 1992
page 2
The position paper will be drafted following my
conversations with each participant at the meeting, and
should be ready for review next week.
I have some thoughts on how we might use this document but
need guidance fairly soon on how you want to deal with Mike
Duda's request for a meeting with RJR.
This matter should be treated as a priority. The Consortium
needs a position on this subject well before any of its
members are again asked to testify.
2. Alerts and progress reports
Sandee asked that we make fairly regular reports to keep
members better apprised of Consortium activities. The group
expressed strong support for this project.
Last year, we put a "Bulletin" project on the shelf because
of lack of time and recn11-oc. We may want to review that
memo for ideas. In any event, we should be prompt and
responsive to minor requests such as this.
Please let me know if you wish to proceed.
3. Minutes
I have attached a draft. In keeping with an earlier
suggestion, they are concise. However I believe it is
important to accurately reflect the discussion of "Joe
Camel."
In keeping with past practices, we should distribute the
minutes with our announcement of our next meeting.
4. Next meeting
~
We tentatively set June 23-24 and June 25-26 as possible
dates for our next meeting. I am to check those dates as I
make calls related to the "Joe Camel" matter. Please let me
know if those dates suit you.
I assume the meeting will be in Washington, D.C. Since late
June is heavy duty tourist season, I suggest that you make
hotel reservations very soon.
IIOK 0017224
pgNbr=2
Ms. Hrycaj, Mr. Gleason
April 2, 1992
page 3
Members have been asked for their ideas for a theme for the
June meeting. I will advise you once I have heard from
them.
.&lt;
We had agreed to consider Mr. Tello and Ms. Martin-Lee as
possible West Coast speakers bureau members. Clearly, Ms.
Martin-Lee would be well-suited to the job if she has time.
With your approval, I will make the suggestion to the Bureau
members.
5. Speakers Bureau member
6.
Honoraria and Expense Reimbursement
The members noted in the minutes should each receive $400
honoraria for their two days of participation. I will ask
all members to immediately forward their reimbursable,
incidental expenses such as taxicabs so that you can process
these Family C.O.U.R.S.E. Consortium checks without delay.
attachment
TIOK 0017225
pgNbr=3
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
