<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aay00c00</tid>
<bt>2085126532A</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="m":2085126532/6532A-->
<dd>20010728</dd>
<dt>EMAI, E-MAIL</dt>
<au>WALK,RA</au>
<rc>SOLANA,RP</rc>
<pc>DESEL,P; HIRNIKEL,DJ; KEANE,D; LAU,RW; MERLO,E; SANDERS,E</pc>
<np>CARCHMAN,R; HIRNIKEL,DJ; LAU,RW; SANDERS,T; SCHORP,M; WALK,RA</np>
<no>WSA TEAM</no>
<fn>2085126480/2085126627/ETS POSITION</fn>
<!-- Note:si:N921-->
<!-- Note:s:CULLEY,ELIZABETH/OFFICE-->
<ti>ETS TARGET LEVELS - TIMETABLE</ti>
<pg>1</pg>
<!-- Note:lu:FEDA/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:20030121-->
<dl>20030215</dl>
<ot>-----0riginal Message-----	
N
From:	Walk, Roger A.	O
Sent:	Saturday, July 28, 2001 6:19 PM	00
To:	Solana, RiCk P.	~
Cc:	Merlo, Ellen; Desel, Paula; Keane, Denise; Sanders
Edward; Lau
Raymond W.; Himikel
Daniel J.	~
Subject:	,
,
,
ETS target levels - Timetable	N
		OIN
		CJ1
Dear Rick,		W
		N
As you know we are currently evaluating several scientific/technical long-term and short-term approaches for reduction
target levels i.e. guidance for the goal to minimize ETS exposure. Last week we have discussed 4 options and our expert
group has suggested to assess three of them further with our ETS experts. As a next step we will specifically evaluate their
scientific merits and their technical feasibilitv (= activity objective)._
These 3 potential target definitions are:
• Reduce to outside/supply air levels for non-smoking areas;
• Percentage reduction of existing ETS markers levels;
• Ensure levels of ETS components do not exceed regulatory levels.
The 4th target definition (levels of ETS components do not exceed sensory irritation levels) will not be pursued at this time.
The WSA team addressing these target options at this time includes Raymond Lau, Ted Sanders, Dan Hirnikel, Roger
Walk and may involve M Schorp and Richard Carchman (consultant). Raymond will lead this activity.
We plan to complete our analysis until the end of September 2001. We will keep you posted of our progress. The
deliverable will be a presentation which will address these 3 strategic target options from a scientific technical point of view
focusing on
• Situational analysis
• Target definition
• Technical feasibility
• Strengths/opportunities
• Weaknesses/challenges

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
