<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>aae31e00</tid>
<bt>80709444</bt>
<dd>19750904</dd>
<dt>LETT, LETTER</dt>
<au>ELLIS,CE</au>
<rc>JUDGE,CH</rc>
<np>MAU,TH</np>
<ca>EVERHART MUSEUM</ca>
<cr>LOR, LORILLARD</cr>
<no>EVERHART MUSEUM</no>
<!-- Note:co:MARG, MARGINALIA-->
<fn>80709319 /80709469 /KENT BICENTENNIAL PROJ.; 80709335 /80709468 /MISSING</fn>
<!-- Note:si:G1-->
<!-- Note:s:ADVERTISING/BASEMENT GMP-->
<pg>1</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":R1-004; R1-129-->
<!-- Note:lu:STMN/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:19980605-->
<!-- Note:b:KENT-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>T:.-],:lzl[A1?,I• M l:'-~ l:l' N1
( ) ,:
tiA [. Ilisr~~uti. ~( [I :tic•I: AN n A}rr
~cHnVIiUN, }'liNVhY]NAN IA 1F15 ]()
September 4,, 1975
Mr. Curtis H. Judge
Off-ice of the President
LORILLARD
200 East 42nd Street
New York, New York 10017
Dear Mr. Judge:
The Everhart Piuseum appreciates and wishes to accept the
portfolio of twelve lithographs and serigraphs offered as
a Kent Independence Bicentennial gift for the Museum's
permanent collection. It^ our understanding that the edition
is limited to 125 signed and numbered items, the gift coming
to.the Museum being from this edition. It is my personal
belief that this is an outstanding undertaking on the part
of your firm.
The Everhart Museum would indeed assure you that the entire
suite would be exhibited for a substantial period during
the bicentennial year, 1976. It is my assumption that these
prints are not framed, and therefore, some time would be
required in preparing the prints for exhibition here at the
Museum. With this in mind, and other tentative scheduling,
it would be difficult to specify the month or months that
the suite would be on view. However, it would have to fall
within the period of April through September, 1976.
I will look forward to hearing further details of this pro-
gram as they develop. Again, let me commend the company for
its outstanding effort in making the visual arts a significant
part of the Bicentennial.
Sincerely yours,
Carl E. Ellis, Curator of Art
Associate Director
CEE/htk
pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
