<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aao03a00</tid>
<bt>518424615/4617</bt>
<rc>WILMESHER D</rc>
<au>RJR; YOUNG M</au>
<bx>0</bx>
<pc>OROURKE R</pc>
<dd>19970814</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<!-- Note:co:N-->
<np>GUANERI J; URBAN LEAGUE; ST PETERS COLLEGE; ST FRANCIS COLLEGE; HOFSTRA COLLEGE; ST JOHNS UNIV; RJR; DRAKE SCHOOL OF BUSINESS; RAINBOW COLLATION</np>
<!-- Note:dl:20030617-->
<pg>3</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":0-->
<!-- Note:sh:0-->
<!-- Note:s:SALES; NY METRO SALES OFF; YOUNG MA; REGIONAL SALES MGR-->
<ti>PERSONNEL / RECRUITING FOR DIVERSITY.</ti>
<dl>20030915</dl>
<ot>Situation #2 .... dealing with geographical areas where qualified/educated candidates are
not willing to work (Newark, Bronx, Harlem, Center Brooklyn, Crown Hts):
With the geography of the NY Metro Region, the fact is that I have a tremendous
amount of area that is high crime, poverty and minority dominated. Quite honestly, in
most cases only a street smart person that is familiar with / or that is a product of the
environment (grew up and already lives there) would be willing to work everyday in
these conditions. Jim Guaneri, as you are aware, conducts college recruiting in
approximately 15 area University's, College's and Community Colleges. When we find
a qualified College diversity applicant, the comment more often than not is quite simply
.... "I will not consider working in that area". A current example of this is the Newark
Territory Rep opening that I mentioned earlier in this letter. The assignment has been
open for 6 months Listed below is a recap of the steps that Jim Guaneri has taken to fill
this position:
O The Urban Leanue: Jim personally contacted this organization by letter
and in person, in an attempt to interview qualifred minority canidates
(copies of letters attached). Bottom-line, this organization has no interest
in recommending RJR or any other Tobacco Company to any of their
associates.
O The Rainbow Collation: Jim tried several attempts to get past the
Collation's receptionist, and then even sent a letter to the Director (letter
enclosed). Once again, this organization would not even talk to RJR.
U Ran help wanted ad's in two Newark Inner Cfty Blac ublfcations
along with ad's in the large "Star Ledger North JerseyNewspaper":
These ad's were very specific to the geography that would be worked
(Newark). After spending over $1, 000 on ad's and several weeks, Jim
ended up with a total of 5 replies for the position. These individuals that
sent resumes included: a shoe repairman (23 years experience working in
a shoe repair shop), a house painter, a retired Corrections Guard, one
individual that would not return our calls and finally one individual
(B1ack,Female) that we felt might be able to do the job. This one ha f way
qualified applicant ended up "Failing" the Yale background check All
information from driving record to education was falsified.
O St. Peters CollePe in Jersey Citv: Two interviews and neither would work
in Newark
0 St. Francis College: No qualified applicants
0 Ho(stra Collere: No applicants willing to work in Newark
O St. Johns University tboth camnum ): Several interviews but all either
had a problem with the Cigarette industry or working in Newark

pgNbr=1
A
%
Mark Young
New York Metro
August 14, 1997
To: Dave Wilmesher
Subject: Personnel / Recruiting for Diversity
Dear Dave,
Over the past several months, we as a region have placed hiring of minorities a top
priority. As you are aware, with the NY Metro region, this is just good business due to
the diversity within the region's geography. There are a couple of situations that we have
been running into lately:
The first situation :
Has to do with not only the need for good Black and Hispanic candidates, but also a real
need for Indian, Russian, and Asian employees. In the Boro's of NY City, you have
neighborhoods or pockets of foreign immigrants that make up not only the primary
residents of the area, but also the store owners. In many cases, we have a real problem
with communication. For example, we're currently advertising in an all "Russian"
newspaper in an attempt to find a Sales Person to work a predominately Russian area of
Brooklyn. Another example has to do with a predominately Indian area next to Newark,
NJ. In this area, for business purposes, we desperately need a Territory Representative
that can communicate and understand the customs of the large Indian population. For
this position, we have been interviewing and advertising for a Black Male or female for 5
months. No qualified candidate that has been offered the position, is willing to work in
Newark. The next example has to do with Chinatown, where we have been attempting
to fill a Retail Representative position for several months. While we know the
importance of bringing Black and Female candidates into the company, hiring the right
person (or nationality) might reduce our long and short term turnover.
The point is, when we concentrate strictly on Black or Hispanic diversity candidates, in
many cases this truly ties our hands on selecting the right nationality for the specific area.
It would make sense to me to not only have Black / Hispanic / Female EEOC
classifications, but also Asia, Indian, Russian, etc. In my opinion, these are definitely
considered minority groups when you're dealing with large inner-city regions.

pgNbr=2
O Drake School o_fBusiness (NYCi/y &amp; NJcampusesl: Jim set up
interviews with a total of 21 individuals. It ended up that 3 appointments
did not show, 6 individuals did not have drivers licenses, 4 had already
gotten other jobs, 3 showed up and explained that after thinking about it
..... were not interested in working for a tobacco company, and the
remaining 5 were interviewed Once again all 5 either had a problem
working in Newark or simply were not good candidates for the TR
position.
O Next Jim contacted the unemnlovment o,( rce: This quite honestly
opened the,flood gates for the requirement of having weekly interviews to
continue receiving the unemployment checks. Lot's of bodies, no
qualifred candidates.
O Used the Region Bi-week(y sales newsletter (Metro Report): To go after
the employee referrals .... which normally prove to be solid candidates.
No luck!
O The only thing left .... place Job Notices at Newark area Food Stores:
Thirty notices were placed last month, with no responses to date.
To make a long story short, over the past months Jim has only talked to one qualified
candidate, that wants the position .... passed the Yale test .... doesn't have a problem
working in Newark. He also likes the cigarette industry and does have a very solid work
history. When running all these ads, we have a policy that we will interview all
applicants according to the EEOC guidelines. In this case, an Indian Retail
Representative from Central Jersey Division along with two RR from the NY Metro
Region requested and were allowed to be interviewed for the position. As you are aware
we select the most qualified individual for the position, and in most cases it is not a RR
due to the needed skill set of the position. However, at this point the most qualified
individual that we have is the Indian Retail Representative from Central Jersey.
I think you can see the problem that we have. Do we continue to hold the assignment
open and hope for the best in terms of finding a qualified applicant that truly wants the
position, or go against the direction of the company and hire the qualified Retail
Representative and get on with business?
Dave, from time to time everyone needs to vent their problems to somebody and I guess
that's what this letter is all about. I look forward to continuing my "Venting" with you
the next time we're together.
Sincerely,
W" ?t°uag
cc: R. O'Rourke

pgNbr=3
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
