<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae3aa00</tid>
<bt>ZN14417/4422</bt>
<dd>19740000</dd>
<dt>PRESS RELEASE</dt>
<au>KLOEPFER WK, TI</au>
<bx>138</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19960329-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":135-->
<!-- Note:co:MAR-->
<!-- Note:s:ZAHN-->
<np>SURGEON GENERAL;KORNEGAY;NATURE;TERRY LL;USPHS;NATL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES;TI;HARVARD LAW REVIEW</np>
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>7</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>c
The Tobacco Institute, 1776 K St., N. W., Washington, D. C. 20006
Contact: Wa.lliam Kloepfer, Jr.
Office 202/296-8434
Home 301/229-0414
FOR RELEASE, A.M.'S, FRIDAY, JANUARY 11, 1974
Ten vears ago today, after months of secret work, ten
scientists appointed by the U. S. Surgeon General dramatically
released a severe indictment of one of the world's most popular
social customs--cigarette smoking.
The charge that the custom was,responsible in some
degree for some of mankind's most prevalent ailments
front-page news everywhere.
was
But last year the famous 1964 "Surgeoh General's Report,"
viewed in perspective, was noted in a Harvard Law Review article
on govcrn:;cnt agencico' p::blicity practiccs aa a"delAberate
attempt to oversell a narrowproduct" which resulted in "mis-
leading media coverage."
Still e,,other view was expressed today by Horace R.
Kornegay, president Of'The Tobacco Institute, the cigarette
industry's Washington based trade association.
"That report," he said, "was intended to answer ques-
tions raised about tobacco ever since the discovery of America.
To many, at the time it was issued, it did.
"Now, ten years later, judging from the enormous
scientific inquiry of the past decade, it appears it raised
even more questiGns N,,hile settling few, if any."
'(more)
jZN 14417
I

pgNbr=1
Kornegay noted that the 1964 report contained 387 pages.
"Under law the Surgeons General have had to report periodically to
Congress on new sm©king-health research developments since them,"
he said. "The six additional reports issued so far have run to
more than 1,300_additional pages."
He said the newer reports have cited more than 550 re-
search studies on lung cancer alone. "Yet ten years ago, the
then Surgeon General felt he had a closed case on this subject
and made it his most categorical indictment," he added.
Kornegay quoted from an editorial in Nature, a British
,
scientific journal, of last October: '.it is the mark of the,
successful scientist that he has rich enough an imagination to
look for ...alternative hypotheses, particularly,when the
conventional one is pbpular.'
"As a layman," Kornegay said, "I must pay tribute to
I
those who have tt4rned from proving the 'proven' in the past ten
years into pathways of research which clearly show us now that
the Surgeon Ge~eral'p report was much more a beginning than an
end in the smoking-health controveray.
"In the foir,eword to the 1964 report, Surgeon General
Luther Terry wrote that the smoking-health subject 'does not lend
itself to easy answers.' But he said 'it has become increasingly
apparent th.at anY~.:er:• a:ast be found.'
(more)
01% 144ts
,

pgNbr=2
..~.v4?....1s~..., . ~ ~..:. - .•.' -. . .
r Y ~ ._-_....... . _ . _ _...._ _ . l.,_.~...~J
-3-
"No doubt to the disappointment of many, it is evident
now that the answers indeed were not 'found' in the Surgeon
General's report," Kornegay declared.
"As we look now ht more recent findings with redpect
to such influences on health as environment and pollution, sex
and race differences, geogtaphy and genetics, it becomes obvious
that the research which lies ahead will be much more significant
than what has already been done. -
"Take genetigs alone," Kornegay continued. "A recent
study of 18,000 twins showed that among identical twins, there ,
was no difference in mortality even when one twin smoked and the
other did noto while there were higher mortality rates among the
smokers in general..
)
J
In other words, when genetic traits are virtually the
same, the 'association' between smoking and,mortality disappears."
He noted that other researc;hers reported last year on
AHIi, an enzyme whose activity they found to be highly associated
with lung cancer.
"Could it be, " Kornegay 'asked, "that a high AfiH level,
rat.ier than cxgarettei, is in fact responsiLle--thus explaining
why the vast aiajority of smokers do not develop lung cancer?"
(more)-
14419
~

pgNbr=3
-4-
Kornegay said that similar work has been reported, since
,
the Surgeon General's 1964 pronouncements, with respect to another
enzyme. AAT, in the absence of which there is an apparent tendency
for emphysema to develop.
"Perhaps this is why, despite so much of the popular
propaganda we have heard, the LT. S. Public Health Service weighs
all of our knowledge ofemphysema and says currently that 'the
cause or causes of emphysema are not known,"' he said.
)
I
"Another confounding factor has arisen from the reports
that women smokers tendto have slightly lower weight babies.
A study of more than 13,000 women showed that those who began
before they.began.to smoke!
smoking after bearing children had•had lower weight babies
"Clearly, smoking could not have been a factor in
these cases--perhaps genetics was, in some way," Kornegay observed.
I
He pointed out that the Surgeon General's report was
based largely on statistical studies. But he said that in ensuing
~ , .
years more refined stuAies have been published, showing substantial
differences between blacks and whites with respect to cancer,
heart ailments and respiratory diseases--even where smoking patterns
were similar.
(more)
. 1449
~iNt
I

pgNbr=4
a
-5-
"What, other than smoking, might be responsible ?" he
asked.
"We know now," he declared, "that there are unexplained
sex differences in lvng cancer rates. For c§xample, the maib-woman
ratio in the U. S. is about five to one. ]Cn the Netherlands it
,
is about 1-3.5 to one--and in Nigeria, lung oar.cer occurs more
frequently in women than men!
"Ten years ago, the Surgeon General's report brushed
aside air pollution as a significant factor;," Kornegay recalled.,
"Last year a massive report from the National Academy of Sciences
left no question.about the fact that air pollution is implicated-
the question was'only to how great an extent.
"What other explanation could there be for reports that
lung cancer rates are twice as high in cities compared with rural
areas,. even when allowance is made for different smoking rates?"
Kornegay said that 'tar' and nicotine are areas in
which, in spite of published suggestions of their possible harm-
ful effects, "we seem to have seen the least progress in research
since 1964. We are still right at the point where the Surgeon
General's report said we were then:
(more)
~ZN f qqZO0
j
I

pgNbr=5
-6-
"'Tobacco tars have been found to be carcinogenic for
..... .•..... a-.. 1 .... . ..-., 1, '.
i.nrninnrtPil7 nl f'V nf +nhannn twrie has not
been demonstrated in man. ..' And, 'There is no acceptable
evidence that prolonged exposure to nicotine creates either
dangerous functional change of an objective nature or degenera-
tive disease.'
"in fact," lie said, "it remains true that there is
no agent as found in cigarette smoke that can be specifically
pointed to as a cause of disease in humans.
"So much for hindsight," said Kornegay. "Clearly,
cigarettes have become the world's most researched consumer
product.
"AnEwers to the questions raised about them have been
agonizingly sj•ow iri coming. What does this suggest for the
future?
"For onR thina," Kornegay said, "'scare' stories and
propaganda clearly will not resolve this controversy. The
adversaries of tobacco have drilled us in slogans and staifistics
until they have ceased to have any meaning.
"Sim'ilarly,,we have learned that scientists cannot;
and likely will not, produce simple answers overnight to the very
profound questions which confront them.
(more)
t
r
1
NZN 14421
~ ~ • '

pgNbr=6
-7-
"The "The current, and future o'bligation of ths tobacco
;,,A„~+r,~ hoa1+A nraaniaat.ions. aovernments and the public
itself," he concluded, "is to provide even greater support to
those scientists with 'rich enough an imagination' to contiiiue
seeking real, objective~knowledge of the countless factors,
beginning before birth, which may a~fect our health regardless
of the single effect of our use cignonuse of tobacco."
® ZIN

pgNbr=7
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
