<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae02f00</tid>
<bt>TIOK0002849/2880</bt>
<au># TOBACCO INST</au>
<np>SURGEON GENERAL; FISHER ER; HAMMOND EC; # ACS; RHOADS J; SCHIEVELBEIN H; # GERMAN HEART CENTRE; SCHILLING R; BOUHUYS A</np>
<dd>19790316</dd>
<dt>REPORT</dt>
<!-- Note:co:CONFIDENTIAL-->
<ti>A WORD TO SMOKERS AND NON-SMOKERS</ti>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":OKPJ-->
<bx>172</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:05/06/97-->
<!-- Note:br t="o":TIMN 263430 - 263441; TIMN 263443; TIMN 263445; TIMN 263511-->
<pg>32</pg>
<!-- Note:s:NONE-->
<!-- Note:cn:Oklahoma AG-->
<!-- Note:dl:19990524-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>Following page shows sketch for spread. Smoker-nonsmoker
copy blocks and heads will be in upper left and right segments
of spread, respectively. Space between copy blocks and above
sketch will be empty.
CONFInENTIAL*
T~ 263434
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIOK 0002853

pgNbr=1
Flight #2
Page 2
takes guts. But once you've broken the ice, it's easy.
And you feel exhilarated."
Such people clearly do not represent the nonsmokers
we all know and work with. They would not last long in any
working environment where people must cooperate to get the
job done. And we doubt very much that the "zappers" will find
2,000,000 others to go along with them. Americans just don't
think that way.
Such anti-smokers are not only anti-smoking. They're
giving themselves the reputation of being anti-individualism,
anti-freedom of choice, anti-everything that does not agree
with their special prejudices. And in that they're as much
a threat to nonsmokers as they are to smokers.
The Tobacco Institute
1776 K Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20006
Freedom of choice is the best choice.
Warning: The Surgeon General Has Determined That Cigarette
Smoking Is Dangerous to Your Health.
CONFIDENTIAL:
A263431
NNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION T~N
MI NNESOT
TIOK 0002850

pgNbr=2
Flight #2 Test execution 3/16/79
A word to smokers
(about working together)
Whether you're a billboard painter or just, as you
obviously are, a reader of magazines, you've discovered that
there's a difference between nonsmokers and anti-smokers.
We all work with nonsmokers -- and they work with us.
Roughly 60% of the people around us are nonsmokers, and 40%
of them are smokers -- so we have to work together. And, like
our sign painters, we do.
Anti-smokers are a breed apart. They don't want us
to work together with nonsmokers. And they.go to some extreme
lengths to see that we don't.
Two examples:
1. A nationally known TV and film star was prevented
from performing by a band of anti-smokers threatening violence
because the star frequently smoked on stage. The occasion was
a benefit to raise funds for handicapped children.
2. The executive director of one anti-smoking group
announced plans to build an "army" of 2,000,000 anti-smoking
militants who would go about "zapping" smokers in the face with
spray from aerosol cans.
"You don't know what a rewarding feeling it is," he is
quoted as saying, "the first time you spray a smoker in the
face. It's hard to work yourself up to the first spray. It
CONFIDENTIAL: rIMN 263430
MIlVNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
-TIOK 0002849

pgNbr=3
Page 2
We know that such anti-smokers do not represent the
great majority of nonsmokers. And the anti-smokers know it,
too. But there is a danger that others will think they do.
"When I went to the legislature," says one anti-
smoking lobbyist, "they thought I had about 10,000 people
behind me. That was a laugh. It was just me. I had the law
passed by myself."
If it is a "laugh" for the anti-smoker, it is no joke
for the rest of us for we must all, smokers and nonsmokers
alike, pay the cost of such foolish laws. All of us are losers
when any one of us is denied freedom of choice.
We don't think that, over the long run, that's going to
happen We think that, like our billboard painters, we'll go
on working together tmtil we get the job done.
The Tobacco Institute
1776 K Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20006
Freedom of choice is the best choice
Warning: The Surgeon General Has Determined That Cigarette
Smoking Is Dangerous to Your Health.
CONFIDENTIAL:
1VIINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION ,~'~ 263433
TIOK 0002852

pgNbr=4
A word to nonsmokers
(about working together)
Wherever you work -- even if you're a billboard
painter -- you work with smokers, and always have.
There's nothing remarkable about that. Forty percent
of the people around you are smokers, and 607e are nonsmokers.
Still, we work, live, and enjoy ourselves together.
Lately, however, we've all become super-sensitive to
each other and to each other's privileges and obligations.
And that's not a bad thing.
We agree on many things. There are places (crowded
elevators, to take the simplest example) where smoking is not
appropriate. In closed and private places, the ancient courtesy
of "Do you mind if I smoke?" is still the best rule. Smokers,
we believe, have become more generally conscious of that
courtesy. The occasional careless smoker, waving a lighted
cigarette or cigar, should, in our opinion, be as quickly
reminded of others' preferences by a thoughtful smoker as by a
nonsmoker.
There are those, however, who will never be satisfied
with our sensible accormodations to each other. They don't
want us to work together at all. Instead they want to segregate
us by law -- literally to build walls between us -- at considerable
expense to both smokers and nonsmokers -- in places where we
work, shop, eat or just go to amuse ourselves.
CONFIDENTIAL:
MIlNNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIlVIN 263432
TIOK 0002851

pgNbr=5
I
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIIVIN 263435
TIOK 0002854

pgNbr=6
Page 2
crowded elevators, poorly ventilated spaces or, indeed, in
any place where it is clearly inappropriate. And individuai
managers in their own interest should see to the mutual
comfort of their smoking and nonsmoking patrons. It is only
when the long arm, and notoriously insensitive hands, of
government regulators start making these private arrangements
for us that we all, smoker and nonsmoker alike, begin to lose
our freedom of choice.
In the long run, the wall-builders will fail, and the
walls will come tumbling down -- if not to the sound of a
trumpet, then at least to the slower but surer music of com¢non
decency and courtesy practiced on both sides of "them.
The Tobacco Institute
1776 K Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20006
Freedom of choice is the best choice.
Warning: The Surgeon General Has Determined That Cigarette
Smoking Is Dangerous to Your Health.
COrFI]DEN'rLAL: TIMN 263439
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
. TIOK 0002858

pgNbr=7
Flight #3 Test execution 3/16/79
A word to nonsmokers
(about people who build walls)
The chances are that you made up your mind about smoking
a long time ago -- and decided it's not for you.
The chances are equally good that you know a lot of
smokers -- there are, after all about 60 million of them --
and that you may be related to some of them, work with them,
play with them, and get along with them very well.
And finally it's a pretty safe bet that you're open-
minded and interested in all the various issues about smokers
and nonsmokers -- or you wouldn't be reading this.
And those three things make you incredibly important
today.
Because they mean that yours is the voice -- not the
smoker's and not the anti-smoker's -- that will determine how
much of society's efforts should go into building walls that
separate us and how much into the search for solutions that
bring us together.
For one tragic result of the emphasis on building walls
is the diversion of millions of dollars from scientific
research on the causes and cures of diseases which, when all
is said and done, still strike the nonsmoker as well as the
smoker. One prominent health organization, to cite but a single
instance, now spends 28ph of every publicly-contributed dollar
M~'SOA T~B CC~O ~GAZ'ION T'IMN 263436
TIOK 0002855

pgNbr=8
A word to smokers
(about people who build walls)
It's no secret that there are some folks these days
who are trying to build walls between smokers and nonsmokers.
The theory behind all this is that some smokers annoy
nonsmokers and, of course, that can happen.
But if you want to get an idea of the ridiculous lengths
that some of the wall-builders would like to go to, you have
only to consider this:
In one state alone it was estimated that the first
year's cost of administering and enforcing a proposed anti-
smoking law and building the physical walls required was nearly
$250,000,000.
The proposal was, of course, defeated -- for the plain
fact is the one you have observed in your own daily life, that
the overwhelming majority of smokers and nonsmokers get along
very well and don't need or want to be separated.
This infuriates the wall-builders. Since they cannot
have their own way in a world of free choice, they would like
to eliminate that world by government fiat, by rules and
regulations that would tell you where, and with whom, you may
work, eat, play and shop. And the enormous burden that would
place on all of us, in higher taxes and costs, does not bother
them.
Certainly no one, including smokers, can properly object
to the common sense rules of, for instance, banning smoking in
COrrFI]DErrrIAL: TIMN 263438
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TI0K 0002857

pgNbr=9
Flight #3
Page 2
on "education" (much of it in anti-smoking propaganda) and
only 2C on research.
There will always be some who want to build walls,
who want to separate people from people, and up to a point,
even these may serve society. The anti-smoking wall-builders
have, to give them their due, helped to make us all more keenly
aware of the value of courtesy and of individual freedom of
choice.
But our guess, and certainly our hope, is that you are
among the far greater number who know that walls are only
temporary at best, and that over the long run, we can serve
society's interests better by working together in mutual
accommodation.
Whatever virtue walls may have, they can never move
our society toward fundamental solutions. People who work
together on common problems, common solutions, can.
The Tobacco Institute
1776 K Street, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20006
Freedom of choice is the best choice.
Warning: The Surgeon General Has Determined That Cigarette
Smoking Is Dangerous to Your Health.
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TININ 263437
TIOK 0002856

pgNbr=10
CONFIUENTIAL:
MIlVN~~'~SOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION 1. TIMN 2634•
TIOK 0002860

pgNbr=11
Following page shows sketch for spread. Smpker-nonsmoker
copy blocks and heads will be in upper left and right segments
of spread, respectively. Space between copy blocks and above
sketch will be empty.
CONFIDENTIAL:
M' MOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION TIMN 263440
TIOK 0002859

pgNbr=12
CoNFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TUdN 263512
TIOK 0002864

pgNbr=13
:&gt;.
CONFIDENTIAL:
MMNEBOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
llrvV 263513
TIOK 0002865

pgNbr=14
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIOK 0002869

pgNbr=15
CONFiDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIMN 263555
TIOK 0002867

pgNbr=16
smoker bothers them as much as he bothers us smokers. And then
there are people, perfectly rational about everything else,
who turn kind of paranoid when a smoker approaches.
We don't know what to do about these anti-smokers any
more than you do - except to treat them all with the courtesy
and kindness we deserve from them.
It works with our friends, the nonsmokers; it may also
work with the anti-smokers.
The Tobacco Institute
Freedom of choice is the best choice
CONFEnErrrtAL: TTMN 263692
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TI0K 0002876

pgNbr=17
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION _
TTNiri 263696 -
TIOK 0002819

pgNbr=18
(about riOnsmokers and anti-smokers)
In the expressive jargon of jazz, a
lot of folks are "into" segregation
thes e days - f or smokers.
If you've ridden any planes
lately, you've found yourself
banished to the back of them, last
to be served, last to leave.
Here on the ground there's a
sudden sprouting of "No Smoking"
signs. And if. by mistake, you
happen to light up in the wrong
place, you get a sharp remindez:
annoyed frown or cold shoulden
When that happens, its easy
to get the feeling you're being
picked on, and made to feel like a
social outcast
But there's another side to
this.
In Seattle some time ago.
two restaurants tried segregation
- an area for nonsmokers.
After a month. one had
served 9.389 meals in the
smoking sida and only 21 in the
nonsmoker side. In the othez: of
17,421 customers, only 23 _„
asked to be segregated
from the smokers. ti ,}-
, ..
The point is that most non-
smokers think smokers are O.K
and they like to be around us -
when the choice is left up to them.
So take heart.
That doesn't mean that the
tiny minority of anri-smokers are
going to go away. They won't
Some of them have very sensible
reasons for objecting. Smoke
bothers them. And a discourteous
smoker bothers them as much as
he bothers us smokers. And then
there are people. perfectly
rationall about everything else,
who turn kind of paranoid when a
smoker approaches.
We don't know what to do
about tisese anti-smokers any
more than you do -except to
treat them all with the courtesy
and kindness we deserve from
them.
It works with our friends,
the nonsmokers; it may also work
with the anti-smokers.
i
THE TOBACCO INSTITUTE
i776 K SL N.W wahogton. D.C. 20006
Freedom of choice
is the best choice. i
,
.,
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIMN 263443
TIOK 0002861

pgNbr=19
k
What the experts say: 1.
Dr. Edwin R. Fisher, professor of pathology at the University
of Pittsburgh and author Cf 450 scientific publications, said
in 1977, "My careful review of the literature, confirming the
conclusions based upon my own experimental data and related
work reveals a lack of scientific information which would
allow me to conclude that atmospheric tobacco smoke or its
constituents represent a health hazard in non-smokers."
Dr. E. Cuyler Hammond, a vice president of the American Cancer
Society, stated at an international conference held in 1974
that there "was no shred of evidence" that a nonsmoker can get
lung cancer from "secondhand" smoke.
Dr. Jonathan Rhoads, former president of the American Cancer
Society, said in 1975, "To my knowledge it (other people's
smoke) is not, in fact, actually harmful (to nonsmokers)."
Professor H. Schievelbein of the German Heart Centre in Munich
said in 1976, "According to the present state of our knowledge,
passive smoking does not cause physiological injury to non-
smokers."
Drs. Richard Schilling and Arend Bouhuys, who headed a Yale •al
University lung research team, published this conclusion in
1977: "Exposure to low levels of smoke produced by cigarette
smokers does not result in chronic resoiratory symptoms or
loss of lung function among children or among adults."
SG warning box
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LTTIGATION
TIMN 263612
TIOK 0002873

pgNbr=20
them from your company in just about everything.
And the further trouble is that even the tolerant ncn-smokers,
and that's most of you,
are honestly annoyed by the occasional sniff
of tobacco smoke that's a little too pervasive.
It annoys us smokers equally.
But it would be a shame if we allowed a tiny handful of in-
tolerant anti-smokers, and a small group of discourteous smokers,
to break up the enjoyable harmony we find in each other's personal
style.
Maybe if we ignore thmm both, they'll go away and leave the rest
of us to go on playing together.
The Tobacco Institute
Freedom of choice is the best choice.
CONFIDEN'1'IAL:
MIlVNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION _.
TIMN 263694
TIOK 0002878

pgNbr=21
I
~
~~~~~~l4l~+:! ~I ~i
E ~ .sy
~	I ~rt~~=~~;r~ ~ ~~~ ~F tt ~ ~ralstf
~, r
~ ~ ~~.I E~~~~1~ ( ~f;I
(~ E~ F 4 f! ~~ E~ ~ ~
sl
~ ~~
~
~
~
~	~~~
~I f
If
i
.~~~~ ~~~~~4
~~ ~`€:~ i~r #1 ~~$
~
E
E
r~

~ts~~pt~~t~i fri
H.~-f€~i#iffie~~	~
~
~~ r ~1
.1,~~F~~~~ t
~
~~E~
~~,~~&gt;~~ -~ ~i~~~~~_ ~~tr~t ~~l, ~ R {~~
~~r ~r 1;j~ +~ t: ~r ~ R~ Et~r :#i}0
.
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIMN 263511
TIOK 0002863

pgNbr=22
A word to smokers
(about nonsmokers and anti-smokers)
In the expressive j argon of jazz, a lot o£ folks are
"into" segregation these days -- for smokers.
If you've ridden any planes lately, you've found yourself
banished to the back of them, last to be served, last to leave.
Here on the ground, there's a sudden sprouting of "No
Smoking" signs. And if, by mistake, you happeri to light up in
the wrong place, you get a sharp reminder, annoyed frown or cold
shoulder. '
When that happens, it's easy to get the feeling you're being
picked on, and made to feel like a social outcast.
But there's another side to this.
In Seattle some time ago, two restaurants tried segregation
an area for nonsmokers.
After a month, one had served 9,389 meals in the smoking
side, and only 21 in the nonsmoker side. In the other, of 17,421
customers, only 23 asked to be segregated from the smokers.
The point is that most nonsmokers think smokers are O.K.
and they like to be around us - when the choice is left up to
them.
So take heart.
That doesn't mean that the tiny miaority of anti-smokers
are going to go away. They won't. Some of them have very sensible
reasons for objecting. Smoke bothers them. And a discourteous
CONFIDENTIAL:
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION ~
- 'TIlVIN 263691
TIOK 0002875

pgNbr=23
A word to nonsmokers
(about smokers)
A great jazz musician once said of his art, "If you don't
understand it, I can't explain it."
That's the way it is with smoking.
If you've never smoked, it just looks puzzling -- the whole ritual
of lighting, puffing. What's the point?
There's really no way to explain it.
We've all heard from the people who think the 60 million American
smokers ought to be, like you, nonsmokers. But even those people know
there's something going on that smokers like.
Maybe that's the key to the whole tobacco thing from the beginning.
It's a small ritual that welcomes strangers, provides companionship in
solitude, fills "empty" time, marks the signif icance of certain occasions
and expresses personal style.
For some people. And by personal choice, not for you. That's the
way it ought to be. Whether your preference is carrot juice or bot_led
water, beach buggies or foreign cars, tobacco smoking or chewing gum or
none of the above. Personal style.
What we're saying is that, like jazz or chamber music, some people
like it and some don't. And most of you nonsmokers understand that . It
would be a dull world if everybody liked the same things.
The trouble is that some people (anti-smokers, as distinguished
from nonsmokers) don't like those who march to the sound of the differ-
ent drumer, and want to harass smokers and , if possible, to separate
CONFmENTiAL: - TIlVIN 263693
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION r _
TIOK 0002877

pgNbr=24
CONFmENrIAL: _
MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIMN 263697
TIOK 0002880

pgNbr=25
~}R !N~~rR:•~! ; s# eR i~ ~' st !! R . s ~•~..~; . . .* 3~~i -~a .
~iRois=~j~~~It &gt;~is#~9 aBa~~,I :;~l#"~~~ ' s~~~
% M g
A~~l~~r~~ `i ![t lsi=~~g
H
~~~l ~jIflill8 i~~~~~ FI~
l~~ i.~:.~.
!
~ gt ~ r i~,~ Tr ~ a '~g
~~~tS~ a +" ~;R~ ~~a"!~ ~~. ° ~~~~~q^$~' ~3 ~•€
..~t~=F~3. ~'~~~~.[~s~j~~ ~s;~ilC~~ ~&gt;~~lllkli ~.x~l4=~.~~e=~ ?d.~a~
CONFIDENTIAL:
MNNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIMN 263549
TIOK 0002866

pgNbr=26
f
CONFIDENTIAL:
~q MINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
J
~ aIlitlf~l~
!(A
lGU'~r~GUtG(/. KGt~ZZIw
~ ~
u4luNV
y~'`
0
2
.(L
0
9
uf~u•~us ~ry ?c~,U~ i t(,~t~uv~u.~t.i.cw ~...,.,...,~,.._-
c,~loY~.tA'~(,G
I
TIMN 263578

pgNbr=27
Aword to
nonsmokers
(about smokers)
A great jazz musician once said of
his art, "If you don't understand
it. I can't explain it"
That's the way it is with
smoking.
If you've never smoked. it
just looks puazling - the whole
ritual of lighting, puffing. What's
the poinVI
There's really no way to
explain it.
We've all heard from the
people who think the 60 million
American smokers ought to be,
like you, nonsmokers. But even
those people know there'ssome-
thing going on that smokers like.
Maybe that's the key to the
whole tobacco thing from the
beginning. It's a small ritual that
welcomes strangers, provides
companionship in solitude, fills
"empry" time, marks the
significance of certain occasions
and expresses personal style.
For some people. And by
personal choice, not for you.
That's the way it ought to be.
Whether your preference is caurot
juice or bottled water: beach
buggies or foreign cars, tobacco
srnoking or chewing gum or none
of the above. Personal style.
What we're saying is that,
like jazt or chamber music, some
people like it and some don't _
And most of you nonsmokers
understand that It would be a
dull world if everybody liked the
same things.
The trouble is that some
people (anti-ssnokers, as dis-
tinguished from nonsmokers)
don't like those who march to the
sound of the different druasmec
and want to harass smokers and, "
if possible, to separate theern from
your company in just about
everything.
And the further trouble is
that even the tolerant
nonsmokers, and that's most of
you. are honestly annoyed by the
occasional sniff of tobacco smoke
that's a little too pervasive..
It annoys us smokers equally.
But it would be a shame if
we allowed a tiny handful of
intolerant anti-smokers, and a
small group of discourteous
smokers, to break up the
enjoyable harmony we Snd in
each other's personal style.
Maybe if we ignore them
both, they'll go away and leave
the rest of us to go on playing
togethec
THE TOBACCO INSTITVTE
1776 K it N.W. llWiieKton, p.C. 20006
Freedom of choice
is the best choice.
Wunmq, The Surpeon Generei Has Daermmed
TM Ciperstte Smoking Is Dwgrors to Your Hqkh.
CONFIDENTIAL:
1VIINNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TIMN 263445
TIOK 0002862

pgNbr=28
~~~~~ Ujpiit!ihij 7H'!IiI . ~~~li If~~~~~ ~=~183~~ja
~~it
IiI1P;I1iIIt s . s
L
l~PIS ~
~. Ya.W~~~s~t-~,
'~1'Z Z dp ~ g7~~=3t=~is~a a '~!~E~.~~.~ ~~ l1~!
E/.a
CONFIDENTIAL:
1VIINNFSOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
6
TIMN 263690
TI0K 0002874

pgNbr=29
Some people are saying America needs a lot of new laws
restricting smoking. Before you decide, you should know this:
OTHER PEOPLE'S
SMOKE HAS NEVER
BEEN SHOWN TO
CAUSE DISEASE IN
NON-SMOKERS.
You've probably heard anti-smoking groups calling for more
laws against smoking in public. Because, they say or imply, it's
a proven fact that smoke causes disease in non-smokers.
But the fact is, it simply has never been shown that smoke
causes disease in non-smokers.
Here's what an eminent doctor who was an advisor to the
Surgeon General's Committee was quoted as saying in 1976: "Irn
very direct terms there is no medical proof that non-smokers
exposed to cigarette smoke in ordinary relation with smokers
suffer any damage."
There's much more testimony like that. From government
agencies, other doctors, researchers, medical investigators.
Much of it from sources that are strongly against smoking. Some
of it is quoted in the box at the right.
Certainly smokers and non-smokers can sometimes annoy one
another. But what's needed to solve that problem is more courtesy,
not more laws.
More and more Americans are coming to believe that government•"~
interference isn't the answer to every problem. We agree.
The Tobacco Institute
"The detaited e.tatemen.t o6 .the expe•tt quo.ted .i•,a too .Cengthy to .ine,eude in .this
adve,tt.ieement. Bu.t you'ZZ S.i.nd d,t -- and much moKe .teatimony -- .i,n .ehe 6xee
book.eet "Smohe and .the Non-Smoken. - what yoec anouCd lznow."
Iz' a a co.P.Cec.t.Lon o 5 d¢,ta,i.ted medi.e.a.Y• evi,ienee 6n.om a,GPt cur.ound 'the won.Ld
zha.t bhoetd SuX.Psj eonv.i.nee you tha.t .i,t'a neven been ehown .tha.t emoke cnu.aea
d.ideaae ,i.n .the non-amoh". Get yout 6hee copy by twci,ti.ng The Tebaceo tne•ti,tute,
1776 K S.tAeex, N.W., Wa•shirtg.ton, D. C. 20006.
(more)
CONFIDENTIAL:
MIIVNESOTA TOBACCO LITIGATION
TV4N 263611
TIOK 0002872

pgNbr=30
i
:
rl~'tY~Yt v~1"k'
~
a2" I~~
~
a~s~t
o'' .,'J i4'112 !k _.
,;
za
~ [! rl~t~
Jl'_Y_U-1~ 1Gf Tw,/~3
9JIrY1~MU(&gt; m'1ur~a•Yra~x
(VVlfi'I i
•YZ.I'1~7i7y , 1 ~T'Y~ni
/ra
~
n
'm ~
t~.
~~GfYL
Z^ Y•1 Yl ~ilA t?7h'tii l'vy
n,~ unrpa,
rn,
~.
dYN~UI:G. 4'i71~~1
171), %t~i,; ~ 1 r
~ ~Y ~%~,~
Jnc 17~y~~ ry
tv•n^`.n
.
..
t
r'...
rl"%.
`Ci e ~ll ~~~r.( 1!c6~~~i! ~l':~iil+wrG,G!~CUr %tiN

pgNbr=31
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
