<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aad01a00</tid>
<ti>Behavioral Patterns And Emotional Stress In The Etiology Of Coronary Heart Disease: Sociological And Occupational Aspects</ti>
<dt>Books</dt>
<dt>Publication</dt>
<dd>19770000</dd>
<au>Russek-HI;Russek-LG</au>
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":42-->
<pg>10</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:60323146-->
<!-- Note:dl:19981123-->
<bt>955014784/4793</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="a":MNAT00696418/MNAT00696427-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>Sercu and rAe Hr..rt. edited by D- WMatley.
Raven Pmv. New Yarh. e 1977.
2
Behavior Patterns and Emotional Stress in the
Etiology of Coronary Heart Disease:
Sociological and Occupational Aspects
I
Henry I. Russek and Linda G. Russek
Long ignored in major epidemiological studies, emotional stress is finally
gaining credibility as a potent etiologic factor in isohemic heart disease.
Whereas earlier clues to its importance stemmed from the efittital.in,
pressions of astute physicians, current support of its etiologic role is deHved
from the more convincing data of controlled observation and prospective
studies. ' .
PERSONALITY TRAITS AND BEHAVIOR PATCERYS '
Before the turn of the century, Osler (I) descnbed the typical patient with
coronary disease as "a keen and ambitious man, the indicator of whose
engines is always set Yull speed ahead."' Arlow (2) observed "a compulsive,
striving for aGtievement and mastery which never seems to end." Kemple
(3) found the coronary patient to be an aggressive, ambitious individual with
intense physical and emotional drives, unable to delegate authority or responsibility with ease, possessing no hobbies, and concentrating all:hls
thoughts and energy in the narrow groove of his career. In recent years, Wolf (4) has characterired the coronary-prone individual as one who not
only meets a challenge by expending extra effort, but who takes littlesatis-
J fection from his accomplishments. ,'
.
Friedman and Rosenman (5) have also stressed the prevalence of intense
ambition, competitive drive, sense of utgency, and preoccupation with dead-
Ilnes among persons predisposed to clinical coronary disease. Among such
persons designated as Type A subjects, they found more than 80% exhibited
a behavior pattern characterized by "excessively rapid body mnvement,-
tense facial and boddy musculature, explosive conversational intouation's;
hand or teeth clenching, excessive unconscious gesturing and a genefalair'
of impanence." In our study of 100 young coronary subjects (6), such visible
mandestations were not frequently encountered, and the great majority did' -
nat exhibit such easily recognized outward behavior chamcterislics. '(Te
description quoted above would appear to represent a caricature rather thae
pgNbr=1
16 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE SOCfOLOOICAL STRESS iN CORONARY DISEASE 1]
a poNaft of the average coronary patient under the age of 40 in our series. 25% had been holdlnSdown two.jobs;' and an additional 46% had worked
In fact, most of the young patients seemed to show a striking degree of selR 60 hr or more per week for long pestiods immediately preceding thebnset of
eontrol, dfgnified reserve, and outward eomplacency during interrogation. symptoms. In another 26% there:was unusual fear, inseeurity, diseontent.
In many ofthese subjects, psychological factms would have remained vn- frustrztion restlessness, or seuse`of inadequacy in relxtfon toemployment
recognized had we not made a special inquiry regarding their presence. Although positiuns of responsibility.and jobs with deadlines to meet were
In almost every insfanee, the young coronary paUent proved to be a victim significantly more frequent in the coronary group than in controls, in a great
Of pverwork, often as a result of his unrclcnting drive, intense desire for many instances stress assumed signififant proportions only as a result of too
recogoitlon, or profound sense Of obligation to his employer, his fam0y, or many hours of work or as a cotisequCnce of secondary vocations or activi-
others, but more commonly simply as a consequence of meeting life's chal- ties pursued during "leisure" hours- Buell and Rreslow (9) have also re-
lengeswith maximum and unstinting effert. Compulsive about time and over-
meticulous, these patients were often concerned about trivia, impatient with
subordinates, and worrisome. As perfectionists they generally chose to do
the work tficroselves rather than delegate it to others. It was their usual
practice to take on more responsib0ities at an occupational, social, or do-
mestic level than goodjudgment would dictate. They minimized their symp-
toms and neglected prudent rules of health. Perhaps the most characteristic
trait of the young coronary patient, however, was his res0essness during
leisure hours and his sense of guilt during periods Of ^relaxation." Conse-
quently, he rarely took vacations, and such leisure time as he did possess
was frequently regimented by obligatory participation in an assortment of
social, civic, or educational activities. It is evident, therefore, that behavior
pattervs, quite independently of the demands of the job itself, may "gener-
ate" high degrees of emotional stress.
7Lcse observations by independent investigators show s W king similarity,
and thea validity has been confirmed by prospective studies (7) demonstrst-
ing a high corlelation between the presence of the described behavior
pattern and the subsequent development of coronary disease.
The hereditary origin of the cot'onmy-prone personality would be con-
sistent with the prevaJing concept of heredity as a m§jor factor in ather-
ogenesis but evidence suggests that Type A behavior, m least, is acquired.
Since coronary heart disease may develop in persons without discernible
hereditary predisposition and without overt behavior characteristics now
held suspect, the role of psychic stress per se as related to mode of life could
also be etiologically significant.
6I7OIACIC ROLE OF EMOTIONAL STRESS
Weiss el al. (8), as well as others, have reported that gradually mounting
tension of emotional origin, months or years in duration, occurred prior to
' the onset ofcoronary, oocclusion in a large segment of the patients who came
under investigation. Our observations (6) afe in accord with these findings.
In a group of 100 coronary patients under 40 years of age, prohrnged emo-
tional strain associated with job responsibility preceded the mtack in 91%
of the caves, as compared with 20% for controls. In the coronary group,
orted findings which support a relationship between hours o
p
death from coronary discase. In a study ofthe registered mortal(ty mh of
men in California, they observed that7ight workers under the age of 45 who
are on the job more'than 48 hr a week have twice the risk of death from
coronary heart disease comptired with'other light workers of similar age. In
addition, our study cleady demonstratedd that young coronary patients could
be differentiated more readily from.eentrol subjects by evaluation of occu-
pational stress than by measuremenVof differences in fat intake, hereditary
influences, obesity, tobacco consumpHon, physical activity, or other factors.
It could be expect&lt;d thatthe yourtg candidate for coronary disease. en-
dowed with tmits of intense ambition and'competitive drive, might be
distinguished froni, controls by occupational achievement or type of po-
sition held. The careful siudiea-of6ertkr et aL (10) and Yater and Ce-
workers (11) have, in fact; demonstrsted a significant difference in the kind
of positions held byyoung patients with coronary disease as compared with
controls. The young patient,theyYound, almost always had occupied a
position demandingg responsibility.-and frequently one assooiated with
emotional stress. Although tMs-was often the case in our studies, all types Of
occupations were welll represented in the coronary group, and there was no
indication that premature coronary artery disease is restricted to any spe-
cific level of vocational endeavor (6). The findings appear to indicate that
emotional stress of.occupatiooal ori&amp;n, as well as ambitious goa4directed
traits within the person, may be.causally related to coronary disease in all
socioecmrornic sVata of our sAciely.Whereas emotional stress due to over-
work wa.s oftedaconsequenedbf the nature and demands of the job, it was
more frequendy found to be a by-product of domestic obligations, multiple
T,tatg 9t Inolem.g ot ierleus bUOrs in coronry end control 9roups

Group	Her¢dny
tla (p^cHMe)	NI9htat .54ress sntl stram
aeb - 'lnccnpauanep	
phesnr	Tooecco
(sa cigs )	
E.ercae
Ccronery	t00 .61'M1 '	Sa%	91%	26%	10%.	59%
60%
Comroi	1au '.4e%	. zaw .	20%	zow	35%	
natlo	1.71.1	2.Tto-1- -	4stat	13ta1	xtul	
pgNbr=2
/8 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESSfN CORONARY DISEASE SOCfOLOGlCAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE 19
goals. an established behavior pattern within the person. or a combination ofrnBae n-z. pereente¢e urevnenc&lt;of oomnery neert disease m/ovrspene/b categodes
mnked EY slro;ifulneaa
these. It appeared obvious. Iherefore. that occupztional tilles alone were un-
reliable from the standpoint of correlating epidemiologic data with any Age.isur,.ey
conclusive effects of uccupation. or the 100 young patients in our coronary -
$Pe&lt;ianY &lt;G-d9 50-59 ~EU-89 CO-69 $ae#rank
group. 25% had been holding down two jobs prior to their illness, and, in ,
many instances. the secondary occupation was totally different from the oer,,,mompy n-s 51 78 3.2 ie%s1
main type of employment. Moreover. we observed, as did others, that the vetholoqy .18 '&amp;211? ° 1
stress and strain of employment may be assessed diRerendy "by the com- Mestnes,ology 2.6 137 30.0 6.9
GenemN prsotlce ' 60 - 12.0 23.3 11.9 mosl
munity at large and by the individual jobholder himself." Just as there ' '
are all deze as tae zo
grees of stressful experiences, there are all gradations of resistance nveraqe ttena oi?m.alence mm snd suess ranks
and sensitivity within the person. Consequently, only careful appraisal of the individual reaction to these experiences can provide an index for eni-seuare ..11s r.5 et 36&lt;
quantitating stress factors. prooaceny &lt;0001 . .&lt;U.% &lt;o.Ot &lt;o mt
EMOTIONAL STRESS AND CORONARY DISEASE IN PHYSICIANS vulnerability in the general practitioner has also been noted. Morris, Heady,
To «st the validity of the findings that emotional factors play a major and Barley (13) have reported that fulL-time general practitioners, aged 40
role in the pathogenesis of coronary artery disease, it was decided to com- to 64, had about twice as high'an incidence of coronary heart disease as
pare the prevalence of this disorder in various occupational categories in other members of the Profession. Consistent with this view. our data show
which obvious differences exist with respect tu'Yensions' created by rou- thst in the United. Stslesy coronary disease is naw three times more pre-
line demands of the job (12). For this purpose- physicians themselves ap- valent among general practitioners than smong denvatulogists and pztholo-
pearcd uniquely suited for survey by questionnafre. This appeared to be so, gists- Anesthesiologists, judged to be'second when ranked in the order of
not only because of greater reliability of the anticipated data, but also be- greatest stressfulnes3, were close to general practitioners, and in the sixth
causeofstrikingdifferencesinthedemandsofprofessionallifeamongthose and seventh decades ectually'xxceeded them in frequency of reparted
engaged in various segments of medical practice. Although premedical and coronary disease. . `-'- undergraduate medical education in the United States is essentially similar Although personnlity traits whsh~ are geneticaRy inked may not only
for all physicians, it is chiefly in specialty practice that distinct differences determine the selection of'ohe.spebfalty over another but also influence
prevail among the emotional stresses that develop at work. Obviously the prevalence of coronary diseasrindependently of occupational factors Per
burdens and responsibilities of the general practitioner, the consultant, and se, the 100,000 or more general~practitioners in the United States must be
the speeial'ut provide as marked a contrast as may be found among other regarded as a fairly representstive:croSS-section of all personality types in
occupaNonsl categories more difficult to study. the general population. Moreovpr,.if "amintion" and "drive" are character-
On the basis of rankings by eight independent judges, four professional istics of the coionary-prone behavior pattern, it appears improbable that
groups were selected, of which two were prejudged to be in a"high stress" these traits would be less prevalent'among specialists than amuvg general
area of medical practice (general pactitioners and anesthesiolo5ists) and practitioners. On the contrary-the reverse would seem more likely. There-
two in a "low stress" area (pathologists anddennatologists). Questionnaires fore, despite the fact that emotiopa)s(ress muy uften be generated by be-
were sent out to 4,000 physicians, 1,000 in each of the fourcategones under havior pattems within the individua4 himself, the burden of occupational
study, in order to determine the prevalence of coronsry hean disease in each demands cannot be nlinimizedin-Gght of these findings. Observations in
of these groups (12). From an analysis of the 2,587 rcplies (64.7%), it was various other categories of employment support this view.
clearly evident that general practitioners and anesthesiologists have dis- There is undoubtedly an inferplay.'of many factors in the causation and
tinotly higher coronary heart disease prevalence rates than dermatologists progression of coronary atherosclebosis. Among those currently receiving
and pathologists. special emphasis arc heredity; diet, other diseases, electrolytes, hormonal
The prevalence of coronary disease was least among dermatologists 40 patterns, anatomical configurztions,, personalily traits, social practice, and
to 69 years of age and highesl among general practitioners in the same age adaptations to life situations,Although the proportional cnntnbution of
group (3.2% as compared with 11.9%). Among English physicians a greater each cause varies from case to rase,.there is mounting evidence that emo-
pgNbr=3
20 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISFifSE
tional slres3 of occupational origin is a m.ryjor influence in the etiologic
spectrum of corolsary artery disease. If this concept is correct. the practicing
physician, whose routioe duties encompass not only responsibility for health
but also for life itself, should be found among the most vulnemble in our
society. The high frequency of the disease among members of the medical
Profession has indeed attracted attention for mmy years and has led to the
desigrretion'1lqrbus medicoruln" for angina itself. in 1910, Sir William
Osler (14), commenfvlg on the high prevalence of the disease among doctors,
wrote the following:
In a gmup of 20 men, ercry one of whom 1 knew personally, the outstanding
feature was the incessant treadmill of ptactice; and yet if hard work_that'badge
of all our {dbe'-was abne responsibk, would them not be a great many more
csaes? Every one of [heae mcn had an added fwor_ wony; m not a single case
under 50 years of age was this @ature absent.. . Listen to some of the com-
ments which I jotted down of the circumstances covnected with the onset of
attacks:'A man of grea[ meull and bodily encrgy, wurking early and la4 in a
practico, involved in speculations in land';'domestie infelicitiei ;'worrles in the
Fa&lt;ulty of Medidne ;'voubles with the tmstees of his institution';'law suiti ;
'domestic worties.... At least 6 or 7 men of the 6th decade were carryinq
laads light enough for the 5th, but too mucM1 for a machine wi{II an ever lessening
reserve.
Support for this clinical impression is also found in the observations of
Smith (15), which have shown the incidence of coronary sclerosis in physi-
cians to be more than double that recorded for other occupations replo-
sented in the clientele of the Mayo Clinic. Similarly, our own studies appear
to indicate that the prevalence rates for coronary heart disease among
general pmctitloners in the United States are significantly higher than those
reported for other population groups at home or abroad (12).
EMOTIONAL STRESS AND CORONARY DISEASE
IN OTHER OCCUPATIONS
We have conducted similar studies of coronary disease prevalence among
members of various specialties in the dental and legal professions (t6),
among personnel at the New York Stock Exchange, and among members
ofotJrer professions.
Our survey of 25,000 professional men in 20 occupational categories
has clearly.demonstrated that a marked gradient exists in the distribution of
. coronary disease which appears strikingly related to the prejudged stress-
tLlness of occupational activity (17a). These findings add confirmation to the
growing belief that emotional stresa is one of the more irnporr/ent etiologic
factors in the genesu of coronary artery disease in Western society.
SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE 21
F16. t-1. Ooronary pe+alence Ey age andsvess group. 6lassilicxtion accord/ng to stress
Is as tollows: Inw: dermmologlsb. onhoMntlste. patent Ixwyer6. and penodontisls:
,nedwm: oral suJeans, otner lewyers: Gmndogislz. secvriry analysts, and nial Is+yers;
nqh: eneslEesloloqist&amp; general practice demistry. qenerel practiee law, generW praclice
medicinC, and se[Ynry o-3dsra .
PATHOGENETIC INTERRELATIONSHIP BETWEEN PSYCHIC
-STRF$S-AND`DIETARY FAT
Much evidence now suggests that most of the lethality of n high fm diet in
Western society may actually be dependent on the "catalytic" influence of
stressful living (6,17)..Moreover, it is equally apparent that the athero-
genicily of emotional stress'is conSideiably diminisbed, if not nullified, by
subsistence on a diet low in fat Snapper (1g), in studying the Chinese
populetinn under the s&lt;vere stress of Japanese invasioq long ago concluded
that stress has little or no.eRect if the diet is poor (n amrnel fat. Racial
groups in othergeographical' areas such as Korea Yemen, and Japan have
also exhibited a distinct immunity'to coronary disease, despite obvious
emotional stress in their patterns of life.Since this "immunity" seems to be
lost when high fat diets are ingested, the role of the emotions has often been
assigned a position of secondary significance. The fallacy in such reasoning
is made apparenrby the strikiog pathogenetic interrelationship that exists
between psyctiic stress and dietary fat. This phenomenon is observed both
in the animal kingdom artd iti Irlsn. Stress andArteriosderosis in AnimsB
Inasmuch as diemryhabiEv~among various population groups reflect
profound differences in paUerns oLliving, "diet cannot be readily isolated
pgNbr=4
22 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISF.ASE SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE 23
from the matrix of man's total transaction with his environmenv' (19). In same as other Europeans. wher&lt;as the Trappists do not cat fish, meal, eggs.
the animal kingdom, however, major environmental factors have been or butter. Although there is a much higher level of blood cholesterol among
identified and controlled far more readily and more completely than is the Benedictine monks, no striking diRerences were observed in coronary
possible with corresponding factors in human society. For example, at the heart disease prevalence, and not a single instance of significant disease
Philadelphla zoo mammals and birds who have been on a constant diet were was encountered under the age of 65 ineithergroup. Moreover, both groups
reported to have had a 10-fold increase in arteriosderosis of the coronary showed a far smaller incidence of coronary disease than the general popula-
arteries within a decade (20). Their increased susceptibility to vascular tion. It.secros significant, therefore, that although the "unstressed" Benedio-
degenerative lesions has been ascribed to the psychological disturbances line monk eats zs much fat as.the greatly harassed general pmctitioner of
caused by soeiaf interactions resulting from increased population densities medicine, he suffers only about one-fifth as often from clinical coronary
in the zoo. Man's response to population density appears to correspond disease (12). '
closely to that of other animals. This is reflected in the significantly higher Similady, it is noteworthy that Somali camel herdsmen are relatively free
death rate from clinical coronary heart disease that has been found in from clinical symptoms suggestive of coronary atherosalerosis, although
metropolitan communities as compared with tural areas (2t)4 they subsist on a high fat diet derived.from approximately 5liters of&lt;amel's
Experirrrentally.theprofoundbutdependentroleofstressinatherogenesis milkperday(27).Althoughmany.theoriesmaybeadvancedtoexplainthis
has been clearly confirmed. It has been shown that hypcrcholesterolemia seemingly paradoxical immunity, a major factor for these people, whose
and aortic atherosclerosis in cholesterol-fed rabbits may be either augmented pastoral and patriarchal way of life has remaioed unchanged for centuries.
or reduced by drugs which stimulate or depress the central nervous system could be their relative freedonf from serious psychological stress. Similarly,
(22). Greaterdegees of hypercholesterolemia and coronary atherosclerosis although physical fitness as a result of vigorous activity has been reported
have also been evoked in rats fed an atirerogenic diet and exposed to a to protect the East African Masai: freedom from coronary disease in this
particular form of stress than in their unstressed controls (23). Similarly, pastoml people. despite a diet rich in animal products and dairy fat (28),
although intimsl changes are rare in the coronary arteries of wild imrruture
monkeys, changes in the intima observed in immature caged Rhesus mon-
keys are common after I'!, to 3 months of captivity, and have been inter-
preted as a response to emotional stress (24). Additional experiments were
needed, however, to determine whether such stresses alone are capable of
initiating atherosclerosis, when the diet is low in fat. Clear answers were
provided by the careful studies of Gunn e[ al. (25) in rabbits. These authors
found that on a choksrero6rich diet, hypothalamic stimulation, like other
forms of stress, increased the atherogenicity of diet alone, More important
was the observation that hypothalamic stimulation in controls on a low
cholearetW diet left the vascular system unimpaired. As will be shown,
these experimemal studies seem to correlate with epidemiologic data ob-
tained in man. Thus, like "stressed" animals in the laboratory, "stressed"
human beings do not appear to manifest an increased susceptibility to
atherosclerosis unless the composition of the diet has been relatively high
in animal fat.
Emotfonal Stress and Diet In Man
The findings of Groen et al. (26), in a study of Benedictine and Trappist
monks, provide insight into the role of fat, as related to stress, in the genesis
of coronary disease. Both groups live in rural areas removed from the
stresses of urban life and, in the monastic environment, are free from eco-
nomic and family problems, The Benedictines have a diet substantially the
also could be largely an outcome of the simplicity of their way of life.
In like manaer, the uduswlly,bw incidence of death from myocardial
infarction reported for the noncompetitive, content Italian-American
community of Roseto, Pennsylvania (29), also suggests that way of life may
be an important determinant of the alherogeniciry of a high fat diet. Thus,
while both habitual diet and stressful living appear to be implicated in the
pathogenesis of clinical coronary disease, mounting evidence suggests that
each is dependent on the'other for pathologic significance.
EMOTIONAL STRESS'AND .TOBACCO CONSUMPTION
Despite the statistical relationship between tobacco smoking and clinical
coronary hearl disease, ourstudies suggest that smoking may be merely a
manifestmion of undedying.e'rnoiional stress and not an etiologic factor
in atherogenesis (17,30). We oliierved a rising frequency in the smoking
habit with increased occupational stress and afower coronary heart disease
prevalence among persons.who,stopped smoking than among tM1OSe who had
never smoked. (Since oursurvey was undertaken before the current inter-
national campaign against the sinoking habit, those who stopped smoking
in our study did so of theit own free will without medical indication.)
The data indicated thait whereas the smoking of tobacco may be imVli-
cated in the pathogenesis-of coronary heart disease, the relationship is not
clear. No explanation-ls a( hand. to account for the low prevalence of
coronary hean disease among persons who once smoked. It is possible,
pgNbr=5
24 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESSlN CORONARY DISEASE
ticing physician surely knows that'nervous strain elevates blood pmssure,
aggravates dubetes. induces Qr augments hypercholesterolemia, and in-
creases the tendency to obesity and excessive smoking. Emotional stress
also frequently contnbutu to the failure to achieve daily exercise. by
promoting fatigue and decreasing motivation. Consequently, even such
indirect effects of emotional stress: barring all others, should have elevated
this factor long ago to a posilion Dfconsiderable significance in the complex
etiologic picture oflschemlc heart disease.
suoacp saa~wu °1e E LIGHT HEAVY
EMOTIONAL STRESS AND THE PATHOGENESIS OF
rm.n eiaxnrTTE ATHEROSCLEROSIS
SMO[ERS EYOLLERa
F16 L], Cpronary prevaknce by smok/nq haa;t.
e a n ,
however, that the ability to stop smoking without duress implies a resilient wall leading to an increase in its lipid receptiveness, augmentation of
personality response to stress and thereby a diminished vulnerability to myourdial oxygen requirement;,and increase in the coagulability and
atherogenic influences (I7,30). viscosity of the blood all appear to be implicated.Thus, prolonged emotional
On the other hand, although it has been reported that 100,000 physicians stress, acting through the cerebral curtex and hypothalamus via neuro-
in the United States have given up smoking (31) in fear of itsconsequences, hormonal and hormonal mechanisms. may contribute not orrly to the iniGa
we have found no favorable change in recent years in the average age of tlon and progression of atheromalosis but to Its clinical complications
physicians who die of coronary attacks before the age of 70. or in their ns well. '
average age at death from all causes (32-34). This is a disappointing ob .
servation since no group in our population has practiced greater abstinence '
from tobacco in recent years. Influence of Eriw4ona Stress oo Homeostasls .
A recent sampling of physicians in the United States has actually shown Numerous investigators have shown that stressful life experiences are
that 75% do not smoke and 81% of those who had ever smoked have capable of evoking hypercholesterolemia despite constant diet and exer-
sropped. It is also obvious, however, that no abatement has occurred in the
stressfulness of daily life during this same period. cise. RogGonoff ct al. (35) tiave also shown that emotional episodes cause a
rapid mobilization of nonesmiified fatty atids from the body tissues into
the circulation; these authois have obtained similar results with infusions
TASU; 2-3. oeerns amorq u. s. pnys;c;ans of epinephrine ladrenalinej Hndnorepioephrine (noradrenaline). Steinberg
	Jan. Apm
1955	dan-Aprii
1966	Jana nyrn
r%7	Jan._Aprn
ig&gt;p
Avera9e a9e at eean, (yeere)	59s	58.g	69.6	si2
Averape ape. coronary Cesms
ly (&lt;ru years)	
61.0	
60.8	
BoE	
gsn
rownp.prdemns	t,tae	1.091	1,251	tota
SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE 25
obesity, and lack of
t mellitus' ci arette snwking
d' b
es
h
,
, g
e
ypenensron, ia
x
x i297 exercise. Although psychic stress has rarely been considered: every prac-
At present, there is no clear understanding of the manner in which cmo-
tional stress may hasten lhe advent of clinical coronary anery disease.
metabolic changes in the vascular
in blood cholesterol level
El
v
tio
and Shafrir (36) and others have, shown in animals that it is cortisone that
enhances the ability of epinephrine m trigger sharp hiood lipid irMreaxs
under the influence of psychic stress. They observed a marked and almost
immediate rise in the uonesterifiedfatty acids, followed by a slower but
definite rise in serum cholesterql:;Accarding to Sabin (37), free fatty acids
are irritating and- in excess, may cause subendothelial hemorrhage and
small mural thrombi. Whatever.thee exact mechanisms underlying such
responses may be, hyperlipem/a so evoked is believed to "provide meta-
EMOTIONAL STRESS AND OTHER RISK FACTORS belie substrate for the arouscd orgaoism:'
As a result of stress, sympethetic adrenergic effects on vascular tissue
The risk factors in coroaary heart disease that have received the most metabolism may prepare the soil for subsequent lipid depositions by
attention are a positive family history, high fat diet, hypercholesterolemia, primarily damaging the intim$.'Prolonged vasoconstriction could reduce
pgNbr=6
26 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEISE 27
blood flow in vasa vasorum and produee vascular wall ischemia. leading to ~
County, Ocorgm. Hames observed'[hat there are genetic differences in the
increased pernstability and intramural edema. Raab and Humphreys (38) capycity of individuals to mount a physiologic response to challenge,
have shown that catecholamines also diminish myocardial efficiency by
varied suscepdblhty to
wasting oxygen in a disproponionate fashion. Through this action, the hor- and that these differences snay account for the
. mones are capable tot only of increasing myocardial vulnerability in the corooary attacks. The coronary prnne were found to be involv d in changing
presenee of cauonary atherosclerosis. but of inducing severe, potentially roles, reyuiring an ability for new adaptation or coping.'Ihe were found
necrotiring myocardial hypoxia in animals with perfectly normal coronary to be less physically active. smoked more, had recently acquired more
vessels. Indeed, Raab and his associates (39) have produced myocardial of the status symbols such as educa[ioo, ownership. or prnperty, and had
Their
necroses in rds solely by subjecting these animals to sensory and emotional less intemal strength as reinforcement from Ihe family s[ructure. prone
stresses. Groover et al. (40) have also reported myocardial infarction physiologic forces for coping with change were accelerated. The mnre
produced twice as much epioephrinens the less prone in a 24-hr period.
i
h
w
t
outdemonstmbieatherosclemsisinbaboonssubjectedtotheemotianal At the same time, their platelets were more aticky and the fibrinolytic
i
d
stoms
n
uced by trapping and caging. It seems probably, therefore, that
occult disease in man tnay surface to clinical view, solely or prematurely,
as a result of stressful life experiences.
The blood clotting elements have also been found to be susceptible to
emotional stresses. Dreyfuss and Craczkes (4l) measured clotting time
and found it to be accelerated in 36 medical students on the morning of a
final examination in medicine. Still and Heitfer (42) observed sharp increases
in viscosity, mediated through the action of the sympathetic nervous sys-
tem, as the result of emotional stimuli in animals. Similarly. Haft (43)
has demonstrated that microvascular platelet aggregation, often associated
with neerosis, may occur in the hearts of animals receiving prolonged
epinephrine infusion. More significantly, stress-induced platelet elevation,
with reduction in blood clotting time, has been reported in human subjects
(45). Such changes appear m be part of an adaptive response to combat,
designed to prevent blood loss. When this mechanism reacts excessively
over a prolonged period of time, blood with increased coagulability and
decreased fluidity may slow sufficiently, in passing through narrowed
coronary or cerebral arteries, to produce thrombosis. Even in the absence
of coronary atherosclerosis, microcirculatory platelet aggregation and/or
catecholamine-induced myocardial hyposia due to emotional stress may be
responsible for the instances of "unexplained" angina pectoris and myo-
cardial infarction observed clinically.
SRfERg AND THE CANDIDATE FOR A CORONARY ATTACK
Obviously nm all persons subjected to prolonged emotional'stress will
develop coronary heart disease. Reference has already been made to the
apparent immunity of "stressed" populations subsisting on a low diet.
'More difficult to understand, however, is the varying susceptibility that
appears to exist between persons in different socioeconomic groups and
within specific groups themselves. The studies of Hames (45) have shed
important light on determinants of individual as well as group susceptibility.
In s long-term study of the prevahmce of coronary heart disease in Evans
activity of their blood was decreased.
Endocrinologic profiles indicated that those hormones that related to
mediating hypothalamic impulses were.diminished in the less coronary
prone, suggesting the possibility of an inability to marshall the physiologic
responses to cope with the greater demands. Hanses (45) has shown that in
a period of less than 10 years, the difference in social class in coronary
heart disease prevalence in white inales has disappeared (initially upper
socioeconomic white males had 2'6 times the frequency of coronary heart
disease found in lower socioeconomic white males). The obvious implication
is that as lower socioeconomic white males become more competitive and
assume increasing responsibility, the incidence of coronary episodes in-
ereases. From these findings. it would seem that "achievement" and "suc-
cess" exact a costly toll from those whose physiologic mahanisms over-
reactto challenge. .. . , . -
PREVENTIVECARDIOLOGY
Problems are nm solved on the kvel ofproblems. Andyring a problem to
find its solution is like trying to restore freshness to a leaf by treating the leaf
ioelf, whereas the solution hes in watering the rout (46).
What Has Been Accomplished?
In the past two decades we have witnessed a significant change in the
saturated fat content of the American diet, along with the introduction of
eRective hypocholesterolemic egrnts. There has been a growing awareness
of the need for exercise and nurmal body weight and the avoidance of
tobacco. Diabetes and hypertension have been more effectively managed
through better understanding and-new dntgs. Nonetheless, despite these
apparent gains, there has been at best only questionable improvement in the
mortality risk from corohary heart disease among the general population.
Even among physicians, who are ubviously the most knowledgeable in Ihis
area of prevention, no favorable alteration in longevity has occurred over
pgNbr=7
28 SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE
SOC)OLOGlCAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE 29
the past 20 ytars (32-34). One must conclude, therefore, either that the longer permit books to be read leisumy for pleasure or profit; but only
"advaoces" thus far have been ineffective in dealing with the plague that superficially for grades. Frustrating assignments during holiday racations
now confronts us, or that inroads uf progress are being counterbalanced or the scheduling of tests immediately thereafter destroy both the oppor-
by the growth of etiologic in(fuences about which we have done or can do tunity and the inclination for wholesome recreation and beneficial exercise.
little. A new orientation appears long overdue. . Other antidotes for stress in the form of hobbies, an, music, recrration,
d
The strea ar Modern Life
According to the data of statisticians, people in the United States enjoy
maee lefsure than any civilization in history. Theoretically, at least, there
can be no disagreemem with this finding. In reality, however, this em of less
work and more play is a tormenting illusion. It has been pointed out that the
oWjorfty of the population work barder-at something-than we have ever
done before (47). More than one in every 20 workers, according to
the United States Census Bureau, is holding down two jobs and some are
mznaging three. Smre owners work more than 50 hr per week, and physi-
cians commonly work more. Despite mechanization, farmers are still en-
gaged in their occupation for at least 50 hr per week, while top corpmation
executives spend 60 hr a week at their jobs, including the work they take
home. More than a third of marcied women are now employed outside
their home, thus adding a job to the one they already have, and many men
whose wives work also take on the extra job of helping to run the house.
It is not until the average American arrives home at the end of the day,
however, that the pressures of his society really start to close in on him
(47). Far from being free from the demands of work or duty, much of his
lesiurc time is regimented by participation in adult classes at night school,
bowling, volunteer work, dancing lessons, bridge, community drives for
funds, club meetings, and the like. Such obligatory use nf leisure is not
satisfying and may represent a poor antidote for the emotional stresses
of daily business competition.
Atherasrlerosis as a Pediatric Problem
In underdeveloped areas of the world. atherosclerosis is seen as an aging
process in the latter decades oflife; in Westem society it arises as a pediatric
disorder. This is clearly demonstrated by the results of studies performed
un soldiers killed during the Korean and Vietnamese wars (4g). Although
the dangers inherent in the typical American diet have frequently been
emphasized in relation to the growing child, it seems incredible that the
"stresses" to which a student is exposed during his 16 to 20 years in edu-
cational institutions have not been scanned for possible detriments to health
(32-34). Quality education has become a scarce commodity and dedicated
teaehers an endangered species, nexssitating more and more self-inswc-
tion at home. At the same Ume, demanding schedules and assignments no
ucsuon.
rest, and sleep are being sacnfieed for the bette8ts of modesn e
In the regimented settingat school, prescribed physieal training is often
neither enjoyable nor resaing and may actually discourage continuation
of athletic pursuits later in life. The once-popular ball games on city streets
after school have largely vanished as a consequence of demanding home-
work assignments or easy access to television. Through activities such as
science fairs, educators and parents alike seek to areate scientists out of
youngsters who scarcely have had time to be childrea Compounding the
effect of these pressures, unrelenting competition for high scholastic smnd-
ing and college placement makes formalized education in the United States
a highly tmumatic experience for most students. Confirming this view, a
recent study by the Carnegie Corpomtion has characterized most public
schools as "aggressive: "'grim-^ and "joyless."
With these considerations in mind, it would be difficult to conceive of a
group of candidates more prone to ischemic heart disease than the graduat-
ing class of any medical school in the United States- unless they were the
same individuals after the completion of their internship or residency. Little
wonder that even 75 years ago Osler (14) called it the "doctors' disease."
Preven4se Medicine
,
Treatment today is largely focused on the end result of a disease process
rather than on its prophylaxis.Thesapeutic interventions may someday
block the atherogenicity of n high fat diet. hypercholesmrolemia and emo-
tional stress; until then, however, hygienic measuresand' preventive
medicine must begin in childhood and continue throughout life if any r.zl
impact is to be made on the mortalily risk from coronary heart disease. It
has long been evident that the menlal, emotional, physical, recreational,
and spiritual needs of the young arC being increasingly unfulfilled, both in
the academic and the home environment, despite unpreaedenmd afBuen&lt;e.
The resultant stresses may be responsible for the precocious atherosclero-
sis observed in our young people. American educational institutions cer-
tainly can play a crucial role. ih preventive cardiology. By teaching and
encouraging the practice of sound prophylactie measures both at school and
at home, we may finally curb the black plague of the 20th Century. To
accomplish this goal, education must be made an integral pan of living,
not a substitute for it. In 1905 Santayana (49) wrote, "That life is worth
living is the most necessary of assumptions, and, were it not assumed, the
'
most impossible of conclusions."
pgNbr=8
30 SOCJOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE
CONCLUSIONS '
1. Despite the application of primary and secondary preventive meas-
ures and significant advances in the treatment Of angina peetoris and myo-
cardfel infarcliun, it appeals that the overall morbidity and mortality from
Ischefmc heart disease has Ilot been appreciably altered in the past two
dCcBdCs in the United ST/teA It IS clearly evident that, tU date, effort5 have
faled dismally in preventing the inexorable pfngressioD of coronary sthero-
scferosis and its disabling and fatal complications.
2 Abuvdant evidence now exists to indicate not only that high fat diet
and stressful living fonn a most lethal combination, but also that each is
dependent upon the other for pathologic signifrcance. It appears probable.
therefore, that dietary atteratiun, physical training, and environmental
relaxation could prove effective prophylactically oNy if instituted early in
childhood and maintained as a lifetime practice.
A(:KNOWLEDGMENT
This study was suppoM1ed by The Russek Foundation, Inc., Staten bland.
New York.
REFERENCES
1. Osler. W. Lecmres on aneine yeaods and a01ed sm¢s. N.Y. Mrd. J.. 1896.4.224.
2. Arkna,J. A.Idenrdkatien medlsnisms Inoororeryoodusws.pry[hruan. Med.. 1965. ).
193.
3. Kampte, C. RersdwTnxahadand psychasuvruic Naymaix: Pcnunality traits oremknts
th rheamuk dimase, hYVenensive cardiuvasculv disuse, comnary ocdusion and
hanure Pryr6owm. Med.. 19a5. ), BS
/. Welf, S. G. CardiaraseWar «actbm tu syrnWlic stimdi Circulurinn. 1958. Itl, 28T.
5. Fr'sJman. M.. and Rosene,n,e,n, R. H. Assucotion of spccific overs bchaviour paner, wlm
Hood rvtd urdiovaxWar findisRs: 91ood chdeskrd level tJoud ckl4ng time. incidenec
of arcus serdps..rW Girtical coronary enery disease. J.A.M.A.. 1959, 169. 1286,
6. Russek. H. I.,anJ Zohnan. B. L. Relative sgnilkancs of hereditY.diet, anU occupoiorvl
errtss In mraury heart diwm in ynung adulryAm, / Med. Sel. 1958, 235, 266.
). Roanmaa. R. H.. FtlMapn, M., Slnus. R., Wurm, M., Jenkins, C. D., an] Mefsinf.er.
H. B. Comnvy hprt disease br the Wenem cdhbuntine group AWy. J.A.M.A.. 1966.
195. 86.
8. Wtlsy E n d Emulbml 6ebrf in cnmuarY ocelusion. A.MA. AsM1. Jm. Med.. April
1937. 99, 628.
9. Buell, T., and Bmsbw, L Monaliry from mrnnary h.arl disease in Californu men who
work long M1eura J. Chwn. Dia.. 1960.2. 615.
10. Genkr. M. M. u al Curonu.y Neun Diseuse in Young AdMa: MulriAixdnlianr..Yn.dy.
Published rorCammunwsalth Fund by Hmvard Uruver.hy Press. CambrWBC, Mass.,
195a. P. 63.
1I. Yatcr. W. M. e1 al. Cormvy artery diseese in snen 1810 39 yean efagc Repon of866
6831N6m.Fandia agentIPSY examinatons.Arrr. Hrunl.. 19A8, 36, 334 (Scyt.). d811IXt.1.
IL Rass[k, H. 1. F&gt;nwimW 9rtss and cponary nCert disease in American Physic'uns.
Am.l. Med. SeJ., 1960, 2eB, )11.
13. Monts, J. N., Heady, J. A., and Barky. R G. Coronary Mvt disease in mdid prac-
1%Jmxn Rr. Med. J., 195Z I. 503.
11 OYer, W. Anyna pedqls. Jyrtrl, 1914 1. 692,
SOCIOLOGICAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE 31
15. SmiN. H. L. Irnidenee of caonary seknovs among phnsiuu. Jd.M-I.. RS). IUN.
132).
16. Russek. H. I. Emotkmal slttss anA cwonary Iren disuse in Ameri®rl phYsicians. den.
tists sN 1&gt;wyen. Am. J. Med. Sri.. 1962,213,716.
I). sOL wrvcY otfa l2a~m n~ l6wamrpaional &amp;ouPS. ~: 1965 91L~89
1)a. Russck. H. 1. UnWblisheA dala
18. SnalRCr. L Chi.rre laerov ro Wearem Medirint: A CmrrMaHOn to Geagwphi[nl
Medi[inr Jrom rhe Clinl[a I Pnping Unioe MrJicat Cdlege. IntersdeMe PuHishers.
Inc..New York 19&lt;I.p-29.
19. Lown. B., aM ~urs. F. J. AlMrosckrosls. iNarction and nuulti9n Clrcalarmn. 1959.
2u.161.
20. Ratcliffe. H. L.. YerasmHes. T. H.. and FJliws. G. A. Changes in the character and 10-
cation of anvial Iesions in msmmaH and binds in shc PhibJelphu Zeuleecal Gankn.
C'vcufnFiun, 1960. 21. )30.
2L Rikli, A. E. U al. US. Public Heallb Survry. PuDlic Hedtb Reports, WahinBton D.C..
August.1960.
22. .Myumkav. A. L. IdWCnu ef some facsors an derdapmenl orexperimennl dwlestcral
athercsclerosia. Cbcuiutiun. 1958. IV.99.
23. Uhky. H. N.. and Friedman. M. Bloud liyids" clottlng and eoraoary atMroscieros's in
rat. exposed a a PanicuYr tonn ot strcas.Am. J. Phy.:al.. 1959. 19).396.
24. V kdavec Z.. Medalic, J., and HeufeM, H. N. Corunary anerin in irmnature munkeys,
prdiminary repon af 0e reWrunsM1ip%to actirYy and dkLJ. A(br.ot[Im. Rea. 1968, 8.
923.
25. Gunn. C. G.. Fdeiman. M.. and Buen, S.O EBect ofdvmk hyposNlanric slu^"kr'°n
uynn cbWeaserol induced asheroederosis in Ne mbbit.l. CBe. Insen. 1960, 39, 1963.
26. Gwen. J. l..TiJong. B. R.. WiBebran, A. F., eM Ranrmipa. C. J. InMUrnce efmlrirbn
inaivimantr .na Jlkrcnt rmms or %trtse an Hooddrokasad; RewlH of m CxpMment
of 9 munths duration in 60 onnnal ydunmen. Proc Jnr. ConB. DIN.. Voedae. 1959. 19.
27. 'arp~i~ccire~IqaOhpuWppnnimleuvMSSbr&gt; sdele5amelie9uisenaunlssentuukmemde
lait BuB. WHO. 1962.27 .6g1.
28. Manro G. V..SchaRer. R. D..and Rich. A. Physkal funesaaMlmmvdlY tohesrsdixaxs
inMasai.J.Arhreoa[kr.,Rea,.1965,2.1308. _
from 29, t y«ardial infaictiroan~' Study oflan Ita4an-AmenU[mueonunuY mr Pen~^sYha^ia
JAM.A_ 19". 189.945
30. auas&lt;.GerioT~n~.lroune~i963°1~~emorianalsv9ssinNeelidcqYnfcurwqrylezrt
31. U.S. Yublic Health Service Repen. Wzshingtan, D.C.. 1968.
32. Russet H. 1., anJ Russek. L G- FJiologic faclors in ixhaemic hcendiseau: Tbe elusive
rnle nfemc6onal .sness. ln: MyoroMiWOiy. ed'rted by E. BnNss andG. Rona Unirenity
Yark Press, Baltimore, 1972.
33. Rmsek. H. I. Emnl/orel slress as a cause of comnary heart Nseau.J. Am. Coll. Heelrh
Aasu[., 19)3.22.1)A.
34. Russck, H. I. Behariwr pattems, strese and eoronary hun disease. Am. FomiN PhY
un. April 1974.9. 11).
35. Boedu,ofi. M. D.. Exes. E H.. Jr., and HxrYn. W. Prychophys+dngk studim of Gt
metabalism ReaE befum the Amer. CoO. of Physiciam. Chi[ago, April 21, 1959.
36. Steinbery D.. ard SM1afrlr. E. Cortimne hekl'ViaP' to IipH dse in s4eae Med. N.wr.
196q 6, I.
37. In Pege. 1. H. Atherosd[rasis-a commenrsry. Fed. Prue., 1959- 16- &lt;).
38. Raah W.. anL Humphmys, R. J. Dnrg acYOn upon mYocard'ai epinephtlne-sympatbin
Intion and hprt rate: (Niuoglycerin0. Wpsrcriee, prixul, dTmamine hydro,
aloridel.l.Pharmueol.ltrp.Thrr. 191].g9,60.
39. Raab, W.. Chaplin. J. P., anC Baiusz. E. Myoeard'al neerosq pruduW in domeaticat W
rzts and at wBd rau by sensory aIW &lt;mwural atressea. Prc[. So[. EWBb(. IN.Y.1.
1964. 116, 665.
0. Gruuvec M. R., Jr. Beljeakq, 8. L, Hs81in. J. l., and HBChmck. C. R. MyowNial
pgNbr=9
32 SOCfOLOG7CAL STRESS IN CORONARY DISEASE
iN tion In Ihc Reeya babaon wiJwut d&lt;mnnstmbk aM1Crosderesis. J. An8/o1.. 196).
Id.d09.
al. Ureyfuss. F., aM Cvcrkes, /. W. Bbud chnkstervl and n/ic xid of I[mlthY mcdiul
AudrnB under stma ef an examNNbn ArcE. Inr. Med.. 1959. 103. ]08.
Ci SN1.1. W., and Hdflcq M. H. Bbud vixo.ity in responx to raricus simu4. Repa[ed al
Fad. Am. Soc, for Erp. &amp;of.. Apri136. 1958.
43. Hafl, l. L MicaYCUlalup ylateln pereyliion in Ihe Lor[ wiN eyincpbrire Infusbn.
In: CnAiuvasnlar PraMema: Perspe&lt;uv&lt;r and Pmeress, ediktl by H. 1. Rusxt. Us:.
erv[y Park Pxss 1/u M pnMrYhrdl.
tA SlurwF.l. O. 4rtsetiauxd ppselet rise calkd 4eY to post-op, clots. RcpanM in Med. '
Nrws from nzetine of Amer. Soc. Qin. Pa1wl,.
45. Hanws. Q"MOet Yk&lt;ly to cutt'eN'ss a caMiJnk fnr e curonarv amck. ln: Ne. Hcn- L
mv u Curdiu.nscblar Pnc/ire. etlilcd by H. L Rusmt Uniecrsity Park Preis. BW[i I.
mwe.l9)5.V.129.
46. Malurfsbi Mahcs4 Yogi.On ehe BhugavudGirm PcnguVn Publiutiom.
47. DempxY. D. Mytb o[ [bc new kour&lt; class. TM New York Tono Mugarine, lawary
26.19]8.
dR. Fnas. W. F. HnBnes. R. H.. erM Be&gt;eq l. Coronary anery xkrasb in Amcriun sddiers
kilkd during sM Reman War. JA.M.A.. 1953. 152. III90.
&lt;9. Senuyana. G. Tbr 401 nlReaenn. 19D5.
f
~
pgNbr=10
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
