<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aae15f00</tid>
<ti>-- No Title --</ti>
<dt>Letter</dt>
<dt>Correspondence</dt>
<dd>19640217</dd>
<au>Mooney-EF, ATCO</au>
<rc>Selected Members Of Sales Organization Who Are Promoting Carlton Cigarettes Starting February 24</rc>
<!-- Note:co:Marginalia-->
<!-- Note:ci:10004026-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":(set 3) 1-->
<pg>44</pg>
<!-- Note:ag:60192651-->
<!-- Note:dl:19981123-->
<bt>990087244/7287</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="a":ATX03 0255771/ATX03 0255814-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>"Upon expiration of the period referred to above, all orders
for tax-paid CARLTON Cigarettes for this area will be billed
at the regular price of $.1764 per package."
This is for your information.
%
E, F. Mooney
Director of Sales

pgNbr=1
Under "Advertising Material Placea" enter the Display Cards, Carton Cards,
Shelf Strips in the columns provided. The placement of Package Cutouts is to
be entered under "Display Cards." Posters, including Window Streamers, are
to be entered in the column "Posters."
AND REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES FOR CARLTON CIGARETTES.
SALES MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING FOR YOU!
SELL MORE IN SIXTY-FOUR!
February 10, 1964


pgNbr=2
ANALYSES OF THE SMOKE OF SAMPLES OF CARLTON CIGA-
RETTES ARE MADE PERIODICALLY BY AN INDEPEND-
ENT RESEARCH LABORATORY. ANALYSES DURING THE
MOST RECENT TEST PERIOD PRIOR TO THE MANUFAC-
TURE OF THE CIGARETTES IN THIS PACKAGE AVERAGED:
PER CIGARETTE
&lt;&lt;TAR"* 2.5 MG ............................
NICOTINE 0.4 MG ......••••••••••••••••PER CIGARETTE
*SMOKE COMPONENTS COMMONLY
BUT INACCURATELY CALLED "TAR".

pgNbr=3
~

pgNbr=4
AN UNUSUAL NEW CIGFiRETTE-
Carlton
FLAVOA-FILTEA
CIGARETTES
EVERYTHING ABOUT CQIIIO/1 IS SELECTED AND
CRAFI'ED TO PRODUCE THIS ONE RESULT:
LOW "Tar"and Nicotine,
With REAL Smoking Pleasure.
(,(11rf07n is so low in "tar" and nicotine,
we print test results on all packs and cartons!
CQr«(/n has
- a distinctive blend
-high porosity paper
- special oirvents
cmd a new "Flavor-Filter" with Activated Charcoal
~~~~'which~ail~n~rlcl&gt;9s~.~he tastol:q,~ ~* ~ . - actu
SEE FOR YOURSELF!
U

pgNbr=5
3-PLACING OF CARLTON ADVERTISING MATERIAL
To help you sell CARLTON Cigarettes, the following attractive, beautifully de-
signed advertising material will be available;
Display Cards Shelf Strips
Posters Window Streamers
Carton Cards Package Cutouts
"Now in Stock" Strips
6-Pack Wire and Styrofoam Display
Attachments for Cash Register
Package Dispensers
Strips for Racks and Package Dispensers
Vending Machine Material
Mats and Reproduction Sheets
To help CARLTON Cigarette sales -make every possible effort to gain an
outstanding placement of advertising material.
Your customers will hear about and ask about CARLTON because of the im-
pact of our sales and advertising campaign.
Here are some beautiful reminder pieces featuring CARLTON that will attract
attention and increase your cigarette business because it will remind people
that you have CARLTON. I will place it here for you. (Select the best spot.)
4-DISTRIBUTION FOUND ON CARLTON, MONTCLAIR AND DUAL FILTER
TAREYTON
You are to report distribution found on CARLTON, MONTCLAIR and DUAL
FILTER TAREYTON on your N.Y.O. 341, "Weekly Report."
5-REPORTING WORK PERFORMED
All work performed during this special Sales Campaign is to be reported o
N.Y.O. 341, "Weekly Report." Cash sales of CARLTON are to be reporte
in the HERBERT TAHEYTON column. Any cash sales of HERBERT TAREYTON
are to be reported under "Remarks." For example-"Call No. 3-2 H.T--
$....... '
Under "Sampling 20s Used" enter the brand name CARLTON in the space
provided. Enter the number of packages of 20s used and the total cost on each
call.

pgNbr=6
/50 (QL 4_vndf~/.J1PCL
91
.21. /00/7
February 17, 1964
SALES CAMPAIGN ON
Carlton
FLAVOA-FILTEA
CIGARETTES
TO MEMBERS OF THE SALES ORGANIZATION
IN THE AREAS OPENING ON FEBRUARY 17
Many of today's filter smokers seek a smoke that is low in "tar" and nicotine.
CARLTON Cigarettes, with an exclusive flavor-filter, have been marketed to fill
this need.
See lor yourself! Look at the package of our new cigarette CARLTON. It's dif-
ferent. For the first time the pack carries the "tar" and nicotine levels of a cigarette.
It's unusual in that CARLTON is extremely low in "tar" and nicotine and yet de-
livers high tobacco satisfaction.
EVERYTHING ABOUT CARLTON IS SELECTED AND CRAFTED TO PRODUCE
THIS ONE RESULT:
LOW "TAR" AND NICOTINE, WITH REAL SMOKING PLEASURE
Attached is a copy of Circular No. 3943 dated February 17, 1964, which has been
mailed to all customers located in the open areas announcing the introduction and
first shipments of CARLTON Cigarettes beginning February 17. Please read this
circular carefully as you will play an important role in the introduction, promo-
tion and sale of this unusual new cigarette in your area.

pgNbr=7
ciacuua No. 3943
§ry,tr,YiE~run, ~&lt;~~f ~ q'~o-f,rn~~~irr//.
/50CRUeG/f2P`~l2/irce ~t
III-y" vf , Illy, /00/7
Febnrary, 17, 1964
TO OUR CUSTOMERS
In the following Counties in the State of
MASSACHUSETTS
Barnstable
Bristol
Dukes
Essex
Middlesex
Nantucket
Norfolk
Also the following Counties in the State of
NEW HAMPSffiHE
Belknap Hillsboro
Cheshire Merrimack
Also the following County in the State of
VERMONT
Windham
And the entire State of
RHODE ISLAND
Plymouth
Suffolk
Worcester
Rockingham
Strafford

pgNbr=8
AND IN THE NEAR FUTURE-
... Book Matches and Decals will be available to also help you merchandise
the brand
An initial shipment of CARLTON advertising material will be made. A letter out-
lining shipping information will be forwarded to each District Manager. Addi-
tional requirements should be requisitioned in the usual manner.
Please sign and return the enclosed acknowledgment slip indicating your receipt
and understanding of these instructions.
AND REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES FOR CARLTON CIGARETTES.
SALES MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING FOR YOU.
SELL MORE IN SIXTY-FOUR!
E.F. Mooney
Attachments Director of Sales
SPECIAL NOTE TO SUPERVISORY PERSONNEL
On Monday, February 24, the District Managers concerned are to hold a meeting
with their Sales personnel involved to (1) discuss in detail the complete plan of
operation for this campaign, (2) distribute advertising material and (3) review
Sales Route Coverage.
District Managers will receive further instructions on this from their Sales Mana-
gers. The Sales Managers should make certain that their District Managers are
fully prepared for and completely understand their responsibility.

pgNbr=9
If the headquarter town is not in the open area commence work on this
coverage at the first town on route in the open area continuing in sequence
as listed working towns in the open area.
C. All work in the open area is to be recorded on the Sales Route in the 2-64
column. On completion of work in the open area the Salesmen are to re-
sume work on the 1-64 trip at the point they left off recording that work in
the 1-64 column.
As our primary objective is to obtain and maintain distribution as quickly
as possible, in those Assignments where double coverage of the head-
quarter town has been provided, the headquarter town will not be worked
twice during this coverage. On resuming work on regular route the double
coverage of the headquarter town will apply.
Where regular Salesmen have supermarket commitments on a scheduled
basis, District Managers should be guided by the following:
1. Commitments inside the open area should be fulfilled on their regular
schedule.
2. Commitments outside the open area should be fulfilled where practical
to do so. Where it is impractical, Salesmen in the open area are not to
handle them. The District Manager or Section Sales Manager should as-
sign other Salesmen to handle these stores.
Your Supervisor will review the above route coverage with you at the meet-
ing to be held on Monday, February 24.
RETAIL CALL
Instructions are attached for the Retail Call to be made during this Sales
Campaign.
NOTE: There will be no store sales, breakfast, luncheon or other special sam-
pling calls or use of the carton conversion-wcokday gratis plan by
regular Salesmen during this Sales Campaign on CARLTON Ciga-
rettes.
SAMPL7NG
Convincingly sample retail dealers as instructed in the "Outline of Retail
Call" using your own stock.

pgNbr=10
Under "Advertising Material Placed" enter the Display Cards, Carton Cards,
Shelf Strips in the columns provided. The placement of Package Cutouts is to
be entered under "Display Cards." Posters, including Window Streamers, are
to be entered in the column "Posters."
AND REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES FOR CARLTON CIGARETTES.
SALES MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING FOR YOU!
SELL MORE IN SIXTY-FOUR!
February 10, 1964
-5-

pgNbr=11
. • ~fh..A~,nnuvam Jo~rvo-G',;,ana,~
3. General Services Administration - The purchasing
division of this federal agency, which 1s charged
with the responsibility of purchasing supplies and
services for federal activities such as prisons,
reformatories, etc., operates under the same prin-
ciple as outlined in item 1 above; i.e., the main
office of General Services Administration in
Washington will not list CARLTON Cigarettes in
their Federal Supply Schedule until it has national
distribution. However, purchases up to $25 may be
made by federal institutions and activities for any
merchandise they require which is not listed in the
Federal Supply Schedule.
4. Coast Guard and Marlne Cor s Exchan es and Government
es a and Ce e eriaa - Theae insta la ione order
pro ucte o our manufacture direct from us without any
reference to a Supply Bulletin or Price Agreement.
5, Veterans Canteens - Circular No. 3943 was sent to each
eglonR sS 034`ice in the areas opened and to Veterans
Canteen Service Headquarters in Washington, D. C.,
requesting that they notify each Canteen in the
opened areas of the availability of CARLTON Cigarettes
and our special introductory offer. As in the past,
V.C.S. Headquarters will send a bulletin to each
Canteen in the areas involved which enables the indi-
vidual canteens to order the brand from us.
E. F. Mooney
Director of Sales

pgNbr=12
For the first time in smoking history, a really flavorful cigarette, extremely low in
"tar" and nicotine, is available to the smoking public - giving them the pleasure
they want. CARLTON has a new flavor-filter with ACTIVATED CHARCOAL which
actually enriches the taste. The fine tobaccos were specially selected-and so
was the high porosity paper for CARLTON which is also vented -the result is a
cigarette extremely low in "tar" and nicotine.
Complete instructions covering the Sales Campaign on behalf of CARLTON Ciga-
rettes starting February 24 will be furnished by your Supervisor. The following are
attached for your guidance and should be studied carefully:
1. "Plan of Operation" on opening date (February 24)
2. "Outline of Retail Call" on CARLTON Cigarettes
CARLTON can deliver both flavor and the irreducible minimum of "tar" and nico-
tine which makes it unique among cigarettes. You can therefore make CARLTON
Cigarettes unique in the minds of smokers because it is unique. CARhTON should
be used to convincingly sample and convert consumers as outlined in the at-
tached Retail Call,
THE SOLE PURPOSE OF THIS SALES CAMPAIGN IS TO OBTAIN IMMEDIATE
DISTRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES SO THAT THE MANY CONSUMERS
WHO ARE ALREADY ASKING FOR CARLTON CAN READILY OBTAIN THEM.
IN VIEW OF THIS MUCH OF THE WORK USUALLY PEHFORMED ON YOUR
REGULAR RETAII. CALL HAS BEEN CURTAILED TO ENABLE YOU TO GET DIS-
TRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES THROUGHOUT YOUR ASSIGNMENT AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
To successfully introduce this unusual now cigarette in your area there will be
... A liberal distribution offer to the trade-$6 per case
... Heavy impact advertising in newspapers and on radio
,.. Display Cards, Posters, Carton Cards, Shelf Strips, Window Streamers,
"Now in Stock" Strips, Package Cutouts, 6-Pack Wire and Styrotoam Dis-
play Attachments for Cash Register Package Dispensers, Strips for Racks
and Package Dispensers, Vending Machine Material and Mats and Repro-
duction Sheets
... Sampling with 20s during the initial stages of the Sales Campaign to retail
dealers only as outlined in the attached Retail Call

pgNbr=13
PLAN OF OPERATION
ON OPENING DATE
CARLTON
Flavor-Filter
Cigarettes
PLAN OF OPERATION BEGINNING MONDAY, FEBRUARY 24
BRANDS TO BE CARRIED
CARLTON Cigarettes are to be carried in cabin bags on all calls.
A small quantity of MONTCLAIR, DUAL FILTER TAREYTON, PALL MALL,
LUCKY STRIKE, HERBERT TAREYTON and HALF AND HALF Pocket Size
Smoking Tobacco is to be carried in cars so low or out-ot-stock conditions can
be corrected where necessary.
ADVERTISING MATERIAL
Those men working the open areas are to carry and place only CARLTON
advertising material.
COVERAGE
A. Each Salesman is to operate solely within his own Assignment. Our pri-
mary objective is to obtain and maintain distribution on CARLTON Ciga-
rettes as quickly as possible. In view of this your Retail Call is to be con-
centrated on CARLTON Cigarettes only, i.e., sampling the retail dealer,
gaining distribution for the brand and placing advertising material. Since
no work will be performed on our other major cigarette brands (other
than taking care of low or out-of-stock conditions) during this concentrated
Sales Campaign, we estimate your present call average should triple. It is
estimated, therefore, that regular Salesmen could possibly average ap-
proximately 3D calls per day in their Assignments starting February 24.
B. Each regular Salesman is to commence work in his headquarter town-
if the headquarter town is in the open area. If the headquarter town is
sectionalized, the Salesman is to start work in the first section and work all
sections until the headquarter town has been completely worked.
On completion of work in the headquarter town the regular Salesmen are
to work the remaining towns in the open area in the sequence listed until
all the towns in the open area have been worked.

pgNbr=14
SATURATION RADIO
.. STARTING THE WEEK OF Ijn,N 9 -the news about CARLTON
will be told on 7 major radio stations throughout the area with a saturation
schedule of dramatic, attention-getting 30 and 60 second announcements.
ADVERTISING WILL BE HEAVY AND STEADY from the start in local news
media ... the media that will tell the news about CARLTON and sell the
emokem in our area.
SELECTIVE SAMPLING
... STARTING MONDAY, FEBRUARY 24 -- the power and persuasive force of
personalized contact with smokers by our Sales Organization will be placed
behind a consumer sampling program for CARLTON Cigarettes.
Ai.LOlR PROMOTIONAL ACTIVITY
All-out promotional activities by the Sales Organization will convey the news
about CARLTON with power and impact at the point-of-sale.
SEE FOR YOURSELF
CARLTON IS NEWS ... AND CARLTON WILL MAKE NEWS ... SALES
NEWS FOR YOU ... ORDER NOW UNDER THE SPECIAL INTRODUCTORY
OFFER.
All orders are subject to aur acceptance and to prices and styles in e//ect at
our factory on date of shipment.
No representative or employee of this Compony has authority to change ony
circular, letter or price list issued by this Company.

pgNbr=15
~%Pj~~ Joee-el-e,
/SO (";alY7w_-K7,liiveL
/00/7
February 17, 1964
SALES CAMPAIGN ON
Carlton
FLAVOBJ ILTEH
CIGARETTES
TO MEMBERS OF THE SALES ORGANIZATION
IN THE AREAS OPENING ON FEBRUARY 17
Many of today's filter smokers seek a smoke that is low in "tar" and nicotine.
CARLTON Cigarettes, with an exclusive flavor-filter, have been marketed to fill
this need.
See for yourselfl Look at the package of our new cigarette CARLTON. It's dif-
ferent. For the first time the pack carries the "tar" and nicotine levels of a cigarette.
It's unusual in that CARLTON is extremely low in "tar" and nicotine and yet de-
livers high tobacco satisfaction.
EVERYTHING ABOUT CARLTON IS SELECTED AND CRAFTED TO PRODUCE
THIS ONE RESULT:
LOW "TAR" AND NICOTINE, WITH REAL SMOKING PLEASURE
Attached is a copy of Circular No. 3943 dated February 17, 1964, which has been
mailed to all customers located in the open areas announcing the introduction and
first shipments of CARLTON Cigarettes beginning February 17. Please read this
circular carefully as you will play an important role in the introduction, promo-
tion and sale of this unusual new cigarette in your area.

pgNbr=16
B. First I would like to have you light up a CARLTON so I can get your per-
sonal reaction as to the taste and smoking pleasure of this fine cigarette.
C. Light the cigarette for the dealer
I want you to have this package with my compliments but before I pre-
sent it to you let me point out this message to you.
Point to the message on the package, while convincingly telling the dealer:
CARLTON is a new and pleasurable smoking experience. It's an unusual
cigarette because it's extremely low in "tar" and nicotine with real smok-
ing pleasure. CARLTON is so low in "tar" and nicotine we state the facts
on every packl
D. Present the balance of the opened package to the dealer.
2-SELLING AND DISPLAYING CARLTON CIGARETTES
A. Objectives
On all calls, enthusiastically strive to -
1. Obtain and maintain dislribution ot CARL'1'ON Cigarettes.
2. Strive to obtain outstanding merchandise displays at point of sale and
place advertising material in prominent locations.
B. Live Merchandise Displays
]. The primary objective is to attain and maintain distribution and gain
outstanding displays of all types-mass displays, counter displays,
spreads, etc. REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES.
This can be accomplished by---
a. Displayinq CARLTON Cigarettes in the 4-Carton unit
The 4-Carton unit, made up with four cartons of CARLTON should
be presented and placed on the counter so that you can obtain an
elfective display. (Every other package may be inserted so that the
message on the pack can be readily seen and read.)
If you haverit been able to fully explain the unique merits of
CARLTON Cigarettes to the retail dealer because he does not smoke
cigarettes, approach the subject of displays along lines similar to the
following:

pgNbr=17
OUTLINE OF RETAIL CALL
CARLTON
FLAVOR-F7LTER
CIGARETTES
For the first time in smoking history, a really flavorful cigaretto, extremely low in
"tar" and nicotine, is available - CARLTON Cigarettes!
Everything about CARLTON is selected and craited to produce this onc result:
Low "tar" and nicotine, with real smoking pleasure
CARLTON is so low in "tar" and nicotine wo print test results on cll packs and
cartons!
CARLTON Cigarettes mean additional sales ior the Company. In making your
calls as outlined below, REMEMBER AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES. SALES
MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING FOR YOU.
THE SOLE PURPOSE OF THIS SALES CAMPAIGN IS TO OBTAIN IMMEDIATE
DISTRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES SO THAT THE MANY CONSUMERS
WHO ARE ALREADY ASKING FOR CARLTON CAN READILY OBTAIN THEM.
IN VIEW OF THIS MUCH OF THE WORK USUALLY PERFORMED ON YOUR
REGULAR RETAIL CALL HAS BEEN CURTAILED TO ENABLE YOU TO GET DIS-
TRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARF.TTES THROUGHOUT YOUR ASSIGNMENT AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
YOU ARE NOT EXPECTED TO DELIVER THE SAMPLING AND SALES TALKS
ON CARLTON WORD FOR WORD. AFTER YOU HAVE LEARNED THESE '1'ALKS
THOROUGHLY THEY SHOULD BE USED AS A GUIDE IN PRESENTING THE
MERITS OF CARLTON CIGARETTES TO RETAILERS.
1 - INTRODUCTION
Enter the store and grcel the dealer. Identify yourself when necessary and
tell the dealer that you represent The American Tobacco Company working
in the interest of CARLTON Cigarettes.
If the dealer is a cigarette smolre:, open a package of CARLTON 20s from your
own stock and offer him a cigarette from the package. Then convincingly ex-
plain the unique merits of CARLTON Cigarettes using the lollowing sampling
talk:
A. Offer a cigarette to the dealer
CARLTON has a distinctive blend of fine tobaccos and a new flavor-filter
with activated charcoal which actually enriches the taste. (If the dealer in.
dicates a willingness to smoke the cigarette, continue)
L ~

pgNbr=18
B. First I would like to have you light up a CARLTON so I can get your per-
sonal reaction as to the taste and smoking pleasure of this fine cigarette.
C. Light the cigarette for the dealer
I want you to have this package with my compliments but before I pre-
sent it to you let me point out this message to you.
Point to the message on the package, while convincingly telling the dealer:
CARLTON is a new and pleasurable smoking experience. It"s an unusual
cigarette because it's extremely low in "tar" and nicotine with real smok-
ing pleasure. CARLTON is so low in "tar" and nicotine we state the facts
on every pack!
D. Present the balance af the opened package to the dealer.
2 -SELLING AND DISPLAYING CARLTON CIGARETTES
A. Objectives
On all calls, enthusiastically strive to -
1. Obtain and maintain distribution of CARLTON Cigarettes.
2, Strive to obtain outstanciing merchandise displays at poinl of sale and
place advertising material in prominent locations,
B. Live Merchandise Displays
1. The pimary objective is to attain and maintain distribution and gain
outstanding displays of all types-mass displays, counter displays,
spreads, etc. REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES,
This can be accomplished by-
a. Displaying CARLTON Cigarettes in the 9-Cartan unit
The A-Carton unit, made up with lour cartons of CARLTON should
be presented and placed on the counter so that you can obtain an
effective display. (Every other package may be inserted so that the
message on the pack can be readily seen and read.)
If you haven't been able to fully explain the unique merits of
CARLTON Cigarettes to the retail dealer because he does not smoke
cigarettes, approach the subject of displays along lines similar to the
following:

pgNbr=19
LIST PRICE: $9.00 per M sub)ect to usual 2% cash discount.
PACKING: 20s/200s cup package-12 M shipping case.
SHIPMENTS: Firsl deliveries of CARLTON Cigarettes will be made begin-
ning today (February 17) to customers of the Company lo-
cated in the area outlined in this Circular.
DISTRIBUTION OFFER
You will be paid $6.00 per case (50¢ per M) an purchases of CARLTON Ciga-
rettes shipped Irom February 17 through February 28 for your cooperation in
attaining distribution. Payment will be made by separate check.
CAPITALIZE ON THIS DISTRIBUTION OFFERI ORDER CARLTON CIGA-
RETTES TODAYI
ADVEBTISING
With dramatic impact and heavy /requency, CARLTON advertising will
forcefully demonstrate how every Wng about lhis unusual cigarelte is selected
and crafted to produce this one result:
LOW "TAR" AND NICOTINE
WITH REAL SMOKING PLEASURE
CARLTON is so low in "lar" and nicvtine. test results are printed on all packs
and carlons, Yet, CARLTON delivers real smoking pleasure with its ACTI-
VATED CHARCOAL-"FLAVOR-FILTER" which actually enriches the taste.
CARLTON is news ... and CARLTON will make news ... with powerful
local advertising focused on your market.
"`bCODlP1.8SC NCWBPAPP$ C~~.9r1o51 t`~f4YS~'(~~,;~r . ..~ii~ .~. . . .
.. STARTING THE WEEK OF H.v,ecflz -the news about CARLTON
will be carried by p key daily newspapers throughout the area in full page
and large-space, lwo-rolor ads.`
* (Where Color Is Available)

pgNbr=20
Ciwcuuaa NO. 3943
' ~
~
I ~rza/uvcc r .o- cro
iC~creF
TO OUR CUSTOMERS
In the following Counties in the State of
MASSACHUSETfS
Barnstable Middlesex Plymouth
Bristol Nantucket Suffolk
Dukes Norfolk Worcester
Essex
~
February 17, 1964
i
Also the following Counties in the State of
NEW HAMPuHIRE
Belknap Hillsboro Rockingham
Cheshire Merrimack Strafford
Also the following County in the State of
VERMONT
/SC .~i,oe6 'c,~fc~~'G+ac6
/OG/7
Windharn
And the entire State of
RHODE ISLAND

pgNbr=21
C/9ll/ ~if412(h(P~(A~OL c~ //Q!'fAI~~CYIY~LCUIZLp
/JO~7(/.''Amlv{2~fdkv,l2[H 01,`
(~~ ut(crtn.L, .~1. (~f /L~li/7
February 17, 1964
TO SELECTED MEMBERS OF THE SALES ORGANIZATION WHO ARE
PROMOTING CARLTON CIGARETTES STARTING FEBRUARY 24
Circular No. 3943 announcing the Sntroduction of CARLTON,
our new Flavor-Filter cigarette brand, which was mailed
today to all customers in the open areas, contains certain
provisions which conflict with the method of operation of
some government activities that are not permitted to make
a profit.
In order that the Armed Forces may receive the benefit of
our $6.00 per case offer, we have arranged to convert the
offer to a temporary reduced price for government accounts
only.
For your information, special covering letters were mailed
to the following government accounts in the open areas
which buy tax-paid cigarettes from us:
1. Armed Forces Exchanges
2. Armed Forces Commissaries
3. Armed Forces Clubs (Officer and Enlisted)
4. Federal, State, County and City Institutions and
Activities
5. Finance Officers
For example, the covering letter mailed to Armed Forces
Exchanges reads in part as follows:
"For your convenience we are converting our special dis-
tribution offer of $6.00 per case to a temporary reduced
price per package as follows:
'ORDERS FOR TAX-PAID CARLTON CIGARETTES RECEIVED
FROM ARMED FORCES EXCHANGES (LOCATED IN THE AREA
COVERED BY THE ENCLOSED CIRCULAR) WHICH ARE DATED
WITHIN THE PERIOD FEBRUARY 17, 1964, THROUGH FEBRUARY
28, 1964, WILL BE BILLED AT $.1664 PER PACKAGE.
INVOICES COVERING SHIPMENTS MADE TO ARMED FORCES
EXCHANGES AT THIS NET PRICE WILL BEAR A NOTATION
READING:
"SPECIAL OFFER CURRENTLY IN EFFECT"

pgNbr=22
LiST PRICE: $9.00 per M subject to usual 2% cash discount.
PACKING: 20s/200s cup package - 12 M shipping case.
SHIPMENTS: First deliveries of CARLTON Cigarettes will be made begin-
ning today (February 17) to customers of the Company lo-
cated in the area outlined in this Circular.
DISTRIBUTION OFFER
You will be paid $6.00 per case (502 per M) on purchases of CARLTON Ciga-
rettes shipped from February 17 through February 28 for your cooperation in
attaining distribution. Payment will be made by separate check.
CAPITALIZE ON THIS DISTRIBUTION OFFERI ORDER CARLTON CIGA-
RETTES TODAYI
ADVERTISING
With dramatic impact and heavy frequency, CARLTON advertising will
forcefully demonstrate how everything about this unusual cigarette is selected
and crafted to produce this one result: _
LOW "TAR" AND NICOTINE
WITH REAL SMOKING PLEASURE
CARLTON is so low in "tar" and nicotine, test results are printed on all packs
and cartons. Yet, CARLTON delivers real smoking pleasure with its ACTI-
VATED CHARCOAL-"FLAVOR-FILTER" which actually enriches the taste.
CARLTON is news ... and CARLTON will make news... with powerful
local advertising focused on your market.
COMPLE'lE NEWSPAPER COVERAGE
.. STARTING THE WEEK OF MARCH 2-the news about CARLTON will
be carried by 8 key daily newspapers throughout the area in full page and
large-space, two-color ads.•
• (Where Color Is Available)

pgNbr=23
3-PLACING OF CARLTON ADVERTISING MATERIAL
To help you sell CARLTON Cigarettes, the following attractive, beautifully de-
signed advertising material will be available:
Display Cards Shelf Strips
Posters Window Streamers
Carton Cards Package Cutouts
"Now in Stock" Strips
6-Pack Wire and Styrofoam Display
Attachments for Cash Register
Package Dispensers
Strips for Racks and Package Dispensers
Vending Machine Material
Mats and Reproduction Sheets
To help CARLTON Cigarette sales - make every possible effort to gain an
outstanding placement of advertising material.
Your customers will hear about and ask about CARLTON because of the im-
pact of our sales and advertising campaign.
Here are some beautiful reminder pieces featuring CARLTON that will attract
attention and increase your cigarette business because it will remind people
that you have CARLTON. I will place it here for you. (Select the best spot.)
4-DISTRIBUTION FOUND ON CARLTON, MONTCLAIR AND DUAL FILTER
TAREYTON
You are to report distribution found on CARLTON, MONTCLAIR and DUAL
FILTER TAREYTON on your N.Y.O. 341, "Weekly Report."
5-REPORTiNG WORK PERFORMED
All work performed during this special Sales Campaign is to be reported on
N.Y.O. 341, "Weekly Report." Cash sales of CARLTON are to be reported
in the HERBERT TAREYTON column. Any cash sales of HERBERT TAREYTON
are to be reported under "Remarks." For example -"Call No. 3-2 H.T.-
$....... '
Under "Sampling 20s Used" enter the brand name CARLTON in the space
provided. Enter the number of packages of 20s used and the total cost on each
call.

pgNbr=24
"Upon expiration of the period referred to above, all orders
for tax-paid CARLTON Cigarettes for this area will be billed
at the regular price of $.1764 per package."
This is for your information.
E. F. Mooney ~
Director of Sales

pgNbr=25
NOTE: CARLTON Cigarettes in sample packages of 4s will be available in
the near future and will be furnished to you for use in place of 20s.
You will receive further instructions regarding this.
IMPORTANT NOTE TO MERCHANDISING REPRESENTATIVES
Due to the nature of their specialized work, Merchandising Representatives
should remain on their regular routes recording their work on the Sales
Routes in the normal manner.
When making calls in the open area, Merchandising Representatives should
place primary emphasis on obtaining and maintaining distribution and
prominently displaying CARLTON Cigarettes, secondary emphasis on
MONTCLAIR Modern Cigarettes and tertiary emphasis on DUAL FILTER
TAREYTON. In addition, all of our brands should be merchandised to the ex-
tent possible.
They should continue to sample consumers with DUAL FILTER TAREYTON
and MONTCLAIR 5s and PALL MALL and LUCKY STRIKE 20s and make
breakfast, luncheon and other special sampling calls using only MONTCLAIR
and DUAL FILTER TAREYTON 5s as outlined in the Sales Presentation.
They are to continue to conduct store sales and use the carton conversion-
weekday gratis plan as heretofore including CARLTON Cigarettes along with
our other brands when working the open area.
In those instances where consumers express an interest in CARLTON Ciga-
rettes because they have seen or heard our advertising or publicity on the
brand and indicate a desire to try the brand or indicate they are smoking or
buying their present brand because of what, in their opinion, is its low "tar"
and nicotine content, they should be sampled with CARLTON 20s.
When sampling with CARLTON Cigarettes, you should use the sampling
talk outlined in the attached Retail Call as a guide following the mechanics
outlined in the Sales Presentation and suggesting a switch to CARLTON
Cigarettes.
N.Y.O. 341, "WEEKLY REPORT"
Please be guided by instructions in the "Outline of Retail Call."
AND REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES FOR CARLTON CIGA-
RETTES. SALES MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING
FOR YOU.
SELL MORE IN '64
-3-

pgNbr=26
PLAN OF OPERATION
ON OPENING DATE
CARLTON
F7avor-Filter
Cigarettes
PLAN OF OPERATION BEGINNING MONDAY, FEBRUARY 24
BRANDS TO BE CARRIED
CARLTON Cigarettes are to be carried in cabin bags on all calls.
A small quantity of MONTCI,AiR, DUAL FILTER TAREYTON, PALL MALL,
LUCKY STRIKE, HERBERT TAHEYTON and HALF AND HALF Pocket Size
Smoking Tobacco is to be carried in cars so low or out-of-stock conditions can
be corrected where necessary.
ADVERTISING MATERIAL
Those men working the open areas are to carry and place only CARLTON
advertising material.
COVERAGE
A. Each Salesman is to operate solely within his own Assignment. Our pri-
mary objective is to obtain and maintain distribution on CARLTON Ciga-
rettes as quickly as possible. In view of this your Retail Call is to be con-
centrated on CARLTON Cigarettes only, i.e., sampling the retail dealer,
gaining distribution for the brand and placing advertising material. Since
no work will be performed on our other major cigarette brands (other
than taking care of low or out-of-stock conditions) during this concentrated
Sales Campaign, we estimate your present call average should triple. It is
estimated, therelore, that regular Salesmen could possibly average ap-
proximately 30 calls per day in their Assignments starting February 24.
B. Each regular Salesman is to commence work in his headquarter town-
if the headquarter town is in the open area. If the headquarter town is
sectionalized, the Salesman is to start work in the first section and work all
sections until the headquarter town has been completely worked.
On completion of work in the headquarter town the regular Salesmen are
to work the remaining towns in the open area in the sequence listed until
all the towns in the open area have been worked.

pgNbr=27
AN UNUSUAL NEW CIGARETTE-
Carlton
FLAV08-FILiEA
CI6ARETTES
EVERYTHING ABOUT CQlftO/1 IS SELECTED AND
CRAFTED TO PRODUCE THIS ONE RESULT:
LOW "Tar" and Nicotine,
With REAL Smoking Pleasure.
CQfftOn is so low in "tar" and nicotine,
we print test results on all packs and ccntons!
CQdtO/1 has
- a distinctive blend
-high porosity paper
- special airvents
and a new "Flavor-Filter" with Activated Charcoal
which actually enriches the taste!
SEE FOR YOURSELF!

pgNbr=28
AND IN THE NEAR FUTURE-
... Book Matches and Decals will be available to also help you merchandise
the brand
An initial shipment of CARLTON advertising material will be made. A letter out-
lining shipping information will be forwarded to each District Manager. Addi-
tional requirements should be requisitioned in the usual manner.
Please sign and return the enclosed acknowledgment slip indicating your receipt
and understanding of these instructions.
AND REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES FOR CARLTON CIGARETTES.
SALES MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING FOR YOU.
SELL MORE IN SIXTY-FOUR!
~-~-+-.-,-d----~^--!
E. F. Moane ~y
Attachments Director of Sales
SPECIAL NOTE TO SUPERVISORY PERSONNEL
On Monday, February 24, the District Managers concerned are to hold a meeting
with their Sales personnel involved to (1) discuss in detail the complete plan of
operation for this campaign, (2) distribute advertising material and (3) review
Sales Route Coverage.
District Managers will receive further instructions on this from their Sales Mana-
gers. The Sales Managers should make certain that their District Managers are
fully prepared tor and completely understand their responsibility.

pgNbr=29
(/7t1~ ~lY%J"llll«!!~I/1G C/(/f~(l('k~'(r"I~CYJJL/Jil/I2I6'
/S&lt;J CCn6t ~l_9nf/,(~J~?~+. O lt
/00/7
February 17, 1964
TO MEMBERS OF THE SALES ORGANIZATION WHO ARE
PROMOTING CARLTON CIGARETTES STARTING FEBRUARY 24
In an effort to clarify the matter of CARLTON Cigarettes
being placed on the Supply Bulletins of various government
agencies, we should like to point out the following:
1, Arm and Air Force Commissaries - Circular No. 3943
was mai ed to each Army and Air Force Commissary
Officer and Finance Officer currently on our direct
list in the opened areas as well as to the Headquar-
ters Office in Chicago. However, CARLTON Cigarettes
cannot be included in the Supply Bulletin until we
have achieved national distribution on the brand.
As far as Army and Air Force Commissaries are con-
cerned, one of the most direct methods of booking
an order for a new brand such as CARLTON (during
the period our distribution offer on the brand is
in effect) is to use our regular order form, N.Y.O.
342, as follows:
At the top of the page after the word "Jobber"
write the name and address of the Commissary.
Then write in the quantity of cigarettes that
the Commissary may purchase under the terms of
our special distribution allowance. Indicate
the reduced price for Commissaries (i.e., $1.664
per carton) and across the face of the order
write "As per terms of Circular No. 3943, dated
February 17, 1964." The Commissary purchase order
number should also appear on the order.
2. Arm and Air ~~Force Exchanges, Post Restaurants and
Cafeterias - Circular No. 39 3 was sent to each
xcE Fiange and Regional Office in the areas opened, as
well as to the Headquarters Office in New York, in-
forming them of the availability of CARLTON Cigarettes
and our special introductory offer. Although withheld
from inclusion in their Price Agreement Listings until
wider distribution of this brand is effected, Exchange
Officers should have no difficulty in forwarding orders
to us for CARLTON Cigarettes. This also applies to
Navy Exchanges, Restaurants and Cafeterias.

pgNbr=30
For the first time in smoking history, a really flavorful cigarette, extremely low in
"tar" and nicotine, is available to the smoking public--giving them the pleasure
they want. CARLTON has a new flavor-filter with ACTIVATED CHARCOAL which
actually enriches the taste. The fine tobaccos were specially selected-and so
was the high porosity paper tor CARLTON which is also vented-the result is a
cigarette extremely low in "tar" and nicotine.
Complete instructions covering the Sales Campaign on behalf of CARLTON Ciga-
rettes startinq February 24 will be furnished by your Supervisor. The following are
attached tor your guidance and should be studied carefully:
1. "Plan of Operation" on opening date (February 24)
2. "Outline of Retail Call" on CARLTON Cigarettes
CARLTON can deliver both flavor and the irreducible minimum of "tar" and nico-
tine which makes it unique among cigarettes. You can therefore make CARLTON
Cigarettes unique in the minds of smokers because it is unique. CARLTON should
be used to convincingly sample and convert consumers as outlined in the at-
tached Retail Call.
THE SOLE PURPOSE OF THIS SALES CAMPAIGN IS TO OBTAIN IMMEDIATE
DISTRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES SO THAT THE MANY CONSUMERS
WHO ARE ALREADY ASKING FOR CARLTON CAN READILY OBTAIN THEM.
IN VIEW OF THIS MUCH OF THE WORK USUALLY PERFORMEI) ON YOUR
REGULAR RETAIL CALL HAS BEEN CURTAILED TO ENABLE YOU TO GET DIS-
TRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES THROUGHOUT YOUR ASSIGNMENT AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
To successfully introduce this unusual new cigarette in your area there will be
... A liberal distribution offer to the trade -- $6 per case
.,. Heavy impact advertising in newspapers and on radio
... Display Cards, Posters, Carton Cards, Shelf Strips, Window Streamers,
"Now in Stock" Strips, Package Cutouts, 6-Pack Wire and Styrofoam Dis-
play Attachments for Cash Register Package Dispensers, Strips for Racks
and Package Dispensers, Vending Machine Material and Mats and Repro-
duction Sheets
. Sampling with 20s during the initial stages of the Sales Campaign to retail
dealers only as outlined in the attached Retail Call

pgNbr=31
If the headquarter town is not in the open area commence work on this
coverage at the first town on route in the open area continuing in sequence
as listed working towns in the open area.
C. All work in the open area is to be recorded on the Sales Route in the 2-64
column. On completion of work in the open area the Salesmen are to re-
sume work on the 1-64 trip at the point they left oft recording that work in
the 1-64 column.
As our primary objective is to obtain and maintain distribution as quickly
as possible, in those Assignments where double coverage of the head-
quarter town has boon provided, the headquarter town will not be worked
twice during this coverage. On resuming work on regular route the double
coverage of the headquarter town will apply.
Where regular Salesmen have supermarket commitments on a scheduled
basis, District Managers should be guided by the following:
1. Commitments inside the open area should be fulfilled on their regular
schedule.
2. Commitments outside the open area should be fulfilled where practical
to do so. Where it is impractical, Salesmen in the open area are not to
handle them. The District Manager or Section Soles Manager should as-
sign other Salesmen to handle these stores.
Your Supervisor will review the above route coverage with you at the meet-
ing to be held on Monday, February 24.
RETAIL CALL
Instructions are attached for the Retail Call to be made during this Sales
Campaign. '
NOTE: There will be no store sales, breakfast, luncheon or other special sam-
pling calls or use of the carton conversion-weekday gratis plan by
regular Salesmen during this Sales Campaign on CARLT'ON Ciga-
rettes.
SAMPLING
Convincingly sample retail dealers as instructed in the "Outline of Retail
Call" using your own stock.

pgNbr=32
Y
OUTLINE OF RETAIL CALL
CARLTON
FLAVOR-FILTER
CIGARETTES
For the first timo in smoking history, a really flavorful cigarette, extremely low in
"tar" and nicotine, is available-CARLTON Cigarettes!
Everything about CARLTON is selected and craflod to produce this oue result.
Low °lar" and nicotino, with real smokLng pleasurc
CARLTON is so low in "tar" and nicotine we print test results on oil packs and
cartons!
CARLTON Cigarettes mean additional sales for the Company. In making your
calls as outlined below, REMEMBER. AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES. SALES
MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING FOR YOJ_.
THE SOLE PURPOSE OF THIS SALES CAMPAIGN IS TO OBTAIN IMMI:DIATE
DISTRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES SO THAT THE MANY CONSUMERS
WHO ARE ALREADY ASKING FOR CARLTON CAN READILY OBTAIN THEM.
IN VIEW OF THIS MUCH OF THE WORK USUALLY PERFORMED ON YOUR
REGULAR RETAIL CALL HAS BEEN CUHTAILED'1'O ENABLE YOU'I'O GET DIS-
TRIBUTION ON CARLTON CIGARETTES THROUGHOUT YOUR ASSIGNML"NT AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
YOU ARE NOT EXPECTED TO DELIVER THE SAMPLING AND SALES TALKS
ON CARLTON WORD FOR WORD. AFTER YOU HAVE LEARNED THESE TALKS
THOROUGHLY THF:Y SHOULD RI: USED AS A GUIDE IN PRESENTING THE
MERITS OF CARLTON CIGARETTES TO RETAILERS.
1--INTRODUCTION
Enter the store and greet the dealer. Identify yourself when necessary and
toll the dealer that you represenl The American Tobacco Company working
in the interest of CARLTON Cigarettes.
Ii the dealer is a cigarette smokcr, open a package of CARLTON20s from your
own stock and offer him a cigarette from the package. Then convincingly ex-
plain the unique meritss of CARLTON Cigarettes using the following sampling
ta1k;
A. Offer a cigarette to the dealer
CARLTON has a distinctive blend of line tobaccos and a new flavor-filter
with activated charcoal which actually enriches the taste. (If the dealer in
dicates a willingness to smoke the cigare,fe, continue)

pgNbr=33
G r
n
NOTE: CARCigarettes in sample packages of 4s will ~be avail- //
abl and will be furnished to you for use in place o1.20s. You will re- ceive further instructions regarding this.
IMPORTANT NOTE TO MERCHANDISING REPRESENTATIVES
Due to the nature of their specialized work, Merchandising Representatives
should remain on their regular routes recording their work on the Sales
Routes in the normal manner.
When making calls in the open area, Merchandising Representatives should
place primary emphasis on obtaining and maintaining distribution and
prominently displaying CARLTON Cigarettes, secondary emphasis on
MONTCLAIR Modern Cigarettes and tertiary emphasis on DUAL FILTER
TAREYTON. In addition, all of our brands should be merchandised to the ex-
tent possible.
They should continue to sample consumers with DUAL FILTER TAREYTON
and MONTCLAIR 5s and PALL MALL and LUCKY STRIKE 20s and make
breakfast, luncheon and other special sampling calls using only MONTCLAIR
and DUAL FILTER TAREYTON 5s as outlined in the Sales Presentation.
They are to continue to conduct store sales and use the carton conversion-
weekday gratis plan as heretofore including CARLTON Cigarettes along with
our other brands when working the open area.
In those instances where consumers express an interest in CARLT'ON Ciga-
rettes because they have seen or heard our advertising or publicity on the
brand and indicate a desire to try the brand or indicate they are smoking or
buying their present brand because of what, in their opinion, is its low "tar"
and nicotine content, they should be sampled with CARLTON 20s.

When sampling with CARLTON Cigarettes, you should use~-perliewo-etJiae
sampling talk~ outlined in the attached Retail Call following
outlined in t e Sales Presentation and suggesting\a switch to CARLTON
Ciaarettes.
1V. I. V. .191, W LLM1L I nL['lln l
Please be guided by instructions in the "Outline of Retail CalL"
AND REMEMBER: AVAILABILITY EQUALS SALES FOR CARLTON CIGA-
RETTES. SALES MEAN PROFITS. AND PROFITS MEAN PROFIT SHARING
FOR YOU.
SELL MORE IN '64

pgNbr=34
1W _4/.A 'ZIe"11C;1'ru"Y
3. General Services Administration - The purchasing
division of this federal agency, which is charged
with the responsibility of purchasing supplies and
services for federal activities such as prisons,
reformatories, etc., operates under the same prin-
ciple as outlined Sn item 1 above; i.e., the main
office of General Services Administration in
Washington will not list CARLTON Cigarettes in
their Federal Supply Schedule until it has national
distribution. However, purchases up to $25 may be
made by federal institutions and activities for any
merchandise they require which is not listed in the
Federal Supply Schedule.
4. Coast Guard and Marine Cor s Exchan es and Oovernment
ee auran s and Ca e er as - These insta lations order
pro ucts of our manufacture direct from us without any
reference to a Supply Bulletin or Price Agreement.
5. Veterans Canteens - Circular No. 3943 was sent to each
gionael-OFfFc_ein the areas opened and to Veterans
Canteen Service Headquarters in Washington, D. C.,
requesting that they notify each Canteen in the
opened areas of the availability of CARLTON Cigarettes
and our special introductory offer. As in the past,
V.C.S. Headquarters will send a bulletin to each
Canteen in the areas involved which enables the Sndi-
vidual canteens to order the brand from us.
E. P. Moone Vx~/y
Director of Sales

pgNbr=35
I have here a supply of our new CARLTON Cigarettes. CARLTON
is extremely low in "tar" and nicotine with real smoking pleasure.
See for yourself! (Show message on pack) CARLTON is so low in
"tar" and nicotine we print test results on all packs and cartons!
The price per carton is $ .............
Your customers are going to be asking for CARLTON Cigaretles,
Mr. ......... .. .. By displaying them here (demonstrate by plac-
ing the display) You will increase your sales.
The following wilt be helpful to you when the occasion presents itself
to talk to dealers further about the unique features of CARLTON
Cigarettes:
CARLTON has a new flavor-filter with activated charcoal which
actually enriches the taste. The fine tobaccos were specially selected
- and so was the high porosity paper tor CARLTON which is also
vented - the result is a cigarette extremely low in "tar" and nico-
tine.
Supported by our heavy advertising in newspapers and on radio,
this display will create impulse sales for you -increase your ciga-
rette business.
b. Placing ], 2 or 3-caiion displays of CARLTON on counters with a
carton card
Strive to place 1 carton, 2 carton and 3 carton displays of CARLTON
Cigarettes on counters. (Every other package may be inserted so
that the message on the pack can be readily seen and read.)
SELL OR TRADE
ON EACH CALL, TAKE IN SEVERAL CARTONS OF CARLTON CIGARETTES
- WITH AT LEAST ONE MADE UP WITH A CARTON CARD FOR DISPLAY
AND STRIVE TO SELL OR TRADE AT LEAST ONE CARTON OF CARLTON
IN EVERY CALL MADE DURING THE SPECIAL CONCENTRATION.
It is imperative that ]00 % distribution be attained (as soon as possible) and
maintained to take advantage of tha consumer demand and our heavy ad-
vertising. You must tell and you must sell. You must gain !00%, distribution
on CARLTON Cigarettes to capitalize on the heavy demand and advertis-
ing in your area.
Make certain every store has an adequate supply of CARLTON Cigarettes
.. and that CARLTON Cigarettes are prominently displayed in the best pos-
sible locations.

pgNbr=36
SATURATION RADIO
.. STARTING THE WEEK OF MARCH 9-the news about CARLTON will be
told on 7 major radio stations throughout the area with a saturation schedule
of dramatic, attention-getting 30 and 60 second announcements.
ADVERTISING WILL BE HEAVY AND STEADY from the start in local news
- media ... the media that will tell the news about CARLTON and sell the
smokers in your area.
SELECTTVE SAMPLING
... STARTING MONDAY, FEBRUARY 24-the power and persuasive force of
personaliz contact with smokers by our Sales Organization will be placed
behind a cvnsumer sampling program for CARLTON Cigarettes.
ALL-ODT PROMOTIONAL ACTIVITY
All-out promotional activities by the Sales Organization will convey the news
about CARLTON with power and impact at the point-of-sale.
SEE FOR YOURSELF
CARLTON IS NEWS ... AND CARLTON WILL MAKE NEWS ... SALES
NEWS FOR YOU ... ORDER NOW UNDER THE SPECIAL INTRODUCTORY
OFFER. ~
All orders are subject to our acceptance and to prices and styles in effect at
our factory on date of shipment.
No representative or employee of this Company has authority to change any
circular, letter or price list issued by this Company.
Thank you.
Very truly yours,
t{fu.cs'Lnzvti~2/r ~~r~2t'ro-lc~n~oarr~

pgNbr=37
c/~ c!"~1rnv2ir^anc~r~i`&lt;e.ct,-{:.;~nr~zr&lt;~~,
/SO ~i1f /l2n~lJ~iur/
9e~,m~f&lt;n! , R1.
J J&lt;
February 17, 1964
TO SELECTED MEMBERS OF THE SALES ORGANIZATION WHO ARE
PROMOTING CARLTON CIGARETTES STARTING FEBRUARY 24
Circular No. 3943 announcing the introduction of CARLTON,
our new Flavor-Filter cigarette brand, which was mailed
today to all customers in the open areas, contains certain
provisions which conflict with the method of operation of
some government activities that are not permitted to make
a profit.
In order that the Armed Forces may receive the benefit of
our $6.00 per case offer, we have arranged to convert the
offer to a temporary reduced price for government accounts
only.
For your information, special covering letters were mailed
to the following government accounts in the open areas
which buy tax-paid cigarettes from us:
1. Armed Forces Exchanges
2. Armed Forces Commissaries
3. Armed Forces Clubs (Officer and Enlisted)
4. Federal, State, County and City Institutions and
Activities
5. Finance Officers
For example, the covering letter mailed to Armed Forces
Exchanges reads in part as follows:
"For your convenience we are converting our special dis-
tribution offer of $6.00 per case to a temporary reduced
price per package as follows:
'ORDERS FOR TAX-PAID CARLTON CIGARETTES RECEIVED
FROM ARMED FORCES EXCHANGES (LOCATED IN THE AREA
COVERED BY THE ENCLOSED CIRCULAR) WHICH ARE DATED
WITHIN THE PERIOD FEBRUARY 17, 1964, THROUGH FEBRUARY
28, 1964, WILL BE BILLED AT $.1664 PER PACKAGE.
INVOICES COVERING SHIPMENTS MADE TO ARMED FORCES
EXCHANGES AT THIS NET PRICE WILL BEAR A NOTATION
READING:
"SPECIAL OFFER CURRENTLY IN EFFECT"'

pgNbr=38
I have here a supply of our new CARLTON Cigarettes. CARLTON
is extremely low in "tar" and nicotine with real smok`ng pleasure.
See for yourself! (Show message on pack) CARLTON is so low in
"tar" and nicotine we print test results on all packs and cartons!
The price per carton is $ .............
Your customers are going to be asking for CARLTON Cigarettes,
Mr . ............. By displaying them here (demonstrate by plac-
ing the display) you will increase your sales.
The following will be helpful to you when the occasion presents itself
to talk to dealers further about the unique features of CARLTON
Cigarettes:
CARLTON has a new flavor-filter with activated charcoal which
actually enriches the taste. The tine tobaccos were specially selected
- and so was the high porosity paper for CARLTON which is also
vented-the result is a cigarette extremely low in °tar" and nico-
tine.
Supported by our heavy advertising in newspapers and on radio,
this display will create impulse sales lor you -- increase your ciga-
rette business.
b. Placing 1, 7, or 3-carton displays of CARLTON on counters with a
carton card
Strive to place I carton, 2 carton and 3 carton displays of CARLTON
Cigarettes on counters. (Every other package may be inserted so
that the message on the pack can be readily seen and read.)
SELL OR TRADE
ON EACH CALL, TAKE: IN SI:VERAL CARTONS OF CARLTON CIGARETTES
- WITH AT LEAS'I' ONP. MADE UP WITH A CARTON CARD FOR DISPLAY
AND STRIVE TO SELL OR TRADE AT LEAST ONE CARTON OF CARLTON
IN EVERY CALL MADE DURING THE SPECIAL CONCENTRATION.
It is imperative that 100 % distribution be attained (as soon as possible) and
maintained to take advantagc of the consumer demand and our heavy ad-
vertising. You must tell and you must sell. You must gain 100%, distribution
on CARLTON Cigarcttes to capitalize on the heavy demand and advertis-
ing in your area.
Make certain every store has an adequate supply of CARLTON Cigarettes
.. and that CARLTON Cigarettes are prominently displayed in the best pos-
sible locations.

pgNbr=39
Li0 ~i[dt ~F_~rulr&lt;~17nL
ioorr
February 17, 1964
TO MEMBERS OF THE SALES ORGANIZATION WHO ARE
PROMOTING CARLTON CIGARETTES STARTING FEBRUARY 24
In an effort to clarify the matter of CARLTON Cigarettes
being placed on the Supply Bulletins of various government
agencies, we should like to point out the following:
1, Arm and ASr Force Commissaries - Circular No. 3943
was mai e to eac Army and Air Force Commissary
Officer and Finance Officer currently on our direct
list in the opened areas as well as to the Headquar-
ters Office in Chicago. However, CARLTON Cigarettes
cannot be included in the Supply Bulletin until we
have achieved national distribution on the brand.
As far as Army and Air Force Commissaries are con-
cerned, one of the most direct methods of booking
an order for a new brand such as CARLTON (during
the period our distribution offer on the brand is
in effect) is to use our regular order form, N.Y,O,
342, as follows:
At the top of the page after the word "Jobber"
write the name and address of the Commissary.
Then write in the quantity of cigarettes that
the Commisaary may purchase under the terms of
our special distribution allowance. Indicate
the reduced price for Commissaries (S.e „$1.664
per carton) and across the face of the order
write As per terms of Circular No. 3943, dated
February 17, 1964." The Commissary purchase order
number should also appear on the order.
2, ArmY and Air Force Exchanges, Post Restaurants and
Cafeterias - Circular No, 39 3 was sent to each
Exenge and Regional Office in the areas opened, as
well as to the Headquarters Office in New York, in-
forming them of the availability of CARLTON Cigarettes
and our special introductory offer. Although withheld
from inclusion in their Price Agreement Listings until
wider distribution of this brand is effected, Exchange
Officers should have no difficulty in forwarding orders
to us for CARLTON Cigarettes. This also applies to
Navy Exchanges, Restaurants and Cafeterias.

pgNbr=40
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
